- The next thing we're going
to talk about is requirements,
and requirements are the
currency of an Agile project.
Requirements are going to tell
us what this product is going to
look like at the end.
We'll start with high-level
requirements, these are things
like project product descriptions.
It's the vision for the
product, it's product groupings,
we also might call these 'epics'
or 'huge stories' that give
us lots of features with
these high-level requirements.
And when we do that, we're
going to use a thing called the
MoSCoW prioritization, which
we'll talk about later.
This'll help us prioritize
those requirements in the things
must have, we should have, we
can't have, and we won't have.
Now, when we look at lower-level
requirements, this is down
at the team level.
These are our project
descriptions, they are our
requirements, they are
detailed features, they're user
stories that say "as a user,
I want to be able to do this
thing with the product".
And they're going to have these
lower-level requirements as
we go through, to really
give us the detail we need
to build across.
We're going to prioritize these
based on order, what is the
most important and what is
the least important, as we go
through and we work
through those problems.
Now as we move forward when
we look at these requirements,
we're going to start out all
the way with this big project
product description at the top.
This is a very high-level requirement.
We can then break that down.
So if I'm talking about a car,
we have a car as our project
product description.
It's going to have X amount
of seats, X amount of doors
and tires, you know, it's going
to be able to do this type
of thing.
Now, we don't know all of the
details that go in to making
that car yet, we just know we need a car.
We start breaking that down,
and so we'll have the engine
product group, we'll have
the electrical product group,
we will have the comfort
product group, right?
We'll have the safety
product group, which might be
the airbags and the brakes
and things like that.
And then we'll take on of those
product groups, like let's
say we're going to take the
electronics group, and in
that electronics group we're
going to break that down in
to different product descriptions as well.
We might have on for the radio,
we might have another one
for the headlights.
And then underneath the radio
we'll have the different
functions it should require.
In this radio, we need and
AM/FM radio, we need a tape
player, we need a CD player,
the ability to hook up
an iPhone, whatever those things are.
And you can see we take it
from this big, overwhelming
product, right, this car,
we've broken it down to
the electronics, and then
from the electronics down to
the radio, and from the
radio down to the different
functions.
And as we went from higher-level
to lower-level, we should
get more detailed in the
level of requirements we're
going to do.
Now, this is called decomposition,
and we'll talk more about
this as we go through.
The next Agile focus area we
have is rich communication,
because communication
problems can really derail
your project.
Whenever you can, you need
to proactively address
communication problems and
fix them, early and often.
Effective communication is
so fundamental to the way
we work in Agile, because
everything is team-based
and collaborative, and if
we can't communicate, we're
going to fall apart really
quickly, and we're not going to
be able to work in an Agile method.
Communication can take place
in many different formats.
It can be the traditional
E-mail or text message.
It can be written word,
such as writing it down on
a piece of paper or on a whiteboard.
It can be visualization by
drawing out pictures and using
kanban charts and things like that.
We can do it verbally
over the telephone or even
face-to-face.
There are lots and lots of
different ways to communicate
nowadays.
You have to figure out what's
going to be the best one that's
going to work well in your team.
Now, according to the Prince2
Agile exam, the best, fastest,
clearest, and most efficient
way to communicate is still
old-fashioned face-to-face communication.
Whenever possible, get
everyone in a room and talk to
them eye-to-eye.
By doing this, this is going
to help reduce the level
of formality, and it's
going to allow us to be able
to communicate quickest and
fastest because a lot of our
communication happens
through body language.
Now, when you deal with
technology, technology and your
level of formality needs
to be considered because if
you're across three or four
different states, you might have
to rely on things like Skype
to use video conferencing,
or you may have to just use E-mails.
These are things you're going
to have to consider as part
of your project.
Sometimes you need a
high level of formality.
If you're going to be putting
up a report, for instance,
that would be in written
form, not face-to-face
communication.
Written word does have it's
place, but there are a lot
of disadvantages when
dealing with written word.
Have you ever gotten a text
message from somebody and
you're not exactly sure if
they were joking or not?
Well if they had told you
that face-to-face, you
would've known, right?
Because you can read the body language.
And this is one of those
drawbacks from written word
to verbal.
Your project manager or your
team manager is going to be
responsible and aware of
how this team is going to be
communicating.
It's their responsibility
to come up with a good
communication plan and help
encourage the team to use it.
Communication does need to
be organized and it does
need to be planned.
One of the ways that we do
that is our daily stand-up
meetings as part of
our Scrum cycle, right?
Every morning we stand up
and for 15 minutes we go over
what we did yesterday and
what we're going to do today.
That's part of rich
communication, and again when that
can occur face-to-face that
is going to be the best way
of doing it.
One of the questions I
often get asked when people
start working an Agile
environment is: "How should I
communicate?", and I will
tell you that I am a big fan
of face-to-face communication
and using a lot of
visualization.
Because if I can draw
something up on the board, it's
going to be a lot clearer
than if we use a lot of words,
and so a three-page E-mail
is not nearly as effective
as a one-page infographic.
So that's the idea here
with visualization and then,
if I can do that in a face-to-face
manner, that's going to
eliminate a lot of
those questions as well.
So for the exam, remember
lots of visualization, lots
of face-to-face.
These are good things when
you're trying to communicate
effectively.