- In this lesson, we are going
to talk about some agile focus areas.
And these are things that are techniques,
or procedures, or other areas
that are focused specifically on agile.
And you have to understand
these for the exam.
The first one is the agilometer.
The agilometer is a way of
assessing your agile environment
in order to best tailor PRINCE2
in the most effective way.
This is going to highlight the risk areas
that we have if we decide to use agile,
and the benefit areas if
we are going to use agile.
This helps the project board
make an informed decision
when deciding exactly how
much agile we should use.
This is performed on a pre-project basis,
and it is repeated at each
of the stage boundaries.
And the project manager is going to help
to facilitate this assessment.
You can see that there are six key areas
that are going to be assessed.
And we are going to grade them
from one all the way up to five,
with one being the lowest
and five being the highest.
When we talk about one, this is going to
to be things where we don't feel that
the project environment
is well suited for agile
because of the way our
organization operates.
So if I look at the flexibility
on what is delivered,
how flexible is your organization
with what that final product will be?
If we have a lot of flexibility,
that's going to be a five,
and it's going to be high,
and very focused towards using agile.
If it's one, and it has
to be a certain way,
then we're not going to be as likely
to use agile in this scenario.
The second one is level of collaboration.
How much collaboration is
required on the project,
and how well does our organization
collaborate when it works?
The third is ease of communication.
Is it really easy for us to share things
and talk with each other.
For example, if we are all
working out of the same office,
it's really easy for us
to get up from our desk,
walk across the room,
and talk to somebody.
But if our project team is going to
be spread out across five
or six different locations,
that's going to be more of a
challenge for communication.
And so we might mark
it lower on that case.
The next one is the
ability to work iteratively
and develop incrementally.
By doing this, can we work
in this spiral development,
or do we need everything done at once
for us to be able to deliver a product.
For example, if I was
going to give you a car,
and the customer required a car to drive
from point a to point b,
can you really work on that incrementally?
Well some pieces you can,
but at the end of the day,
the customer doesn't
want a half-finished car.
They want a full car.
And so being able to have
that full product means
that we would be very low
when we are measuring how agile we can be.
Conversely, if I'm building
a software product,
I can probably be very
high on the agile meter
because I'm able to figure
out and put pieces of it
and add functionality later
and very quickly and easily.
Another good example of this is
if I'm building a satellite.
Once you launch that satellite
into orbit, it's up there.
You can't go and add
another piece to it later.
And so that is a very
low agile way of working.
The fifth area we are
going to to consider is
an anvantageous environmental conditions.
Is our environment that we're going
to be operating this project in culturally
and available to work in an agile method?
Some cultures are very agile focused,
and others are very procedural.
And based on that, you're
going to figure out
if you are low or high in that area.
And the final one, the
sixth and final one,
is going to be the acceptance of agile.
Do we accept agile as a way
of practice inside our organization?
If you're in a software
development company,
you are probably very high on this.
But if you're a commercial
builder you might be much lower.
And so we have to decide how
accepting is the organization
in terms of agile before
we can implement it.
And now when we get all of these,
we're going to mark them down on the chart
of where we think we are.
We're not going to average them.
Each one is considered individually.
But this is going to give us an idea
of how agile we think we can
be inside of our environment.
And if you're less agile, it doesn't mean
that you can't use agile at all.
It just means you're
going to have more control
and more governance, and
tighter tolerances placed
than if you were a highly
agile organization.
Now as I mentioned, when you grade these,
you're going to grade these pre-project.
So all the back in starting up a project.
That's going to say,
here's were we are today,
but every time we hit stage
boundary, we're going to reassess.
And so these can change over time.
You may see that over the course
of your project people start getting used
to working in an agile way.
And so these sliders might
move more towards the right,
and more towards the high side.
Now, once you've gone through
and you've assessed
each of these six areas,
you're going to be
considering them in isolation.
We don't want to average them.
We don't want to add them up.
This isn't a sum total game.
Instead we're looking at how agile we are
in each of these six areas.
This will give us a picture
of how agile this project can be,
or how little this project will be agile.
The question is not yes or
no, should I use agile or not.
The question is, how much
agile should I be using?
If we're a highly agile organization,
I'm going to give good tolerances
and let my teams go out and build
the thing they need to build.
If we are less of an agile organization,
I'm going to have tighter tolerances,
and add more governances,
and more oversight
as we go through the process.
This is going to represent
our starting point.
Now these assessments are done
every time we hit a stage boundary.
And so we are going to go back
and look at where we are
today as an organization.
And, when we hit that stage boundary,
where we are at that point.
As we see, these sliders may improve
or they may go backwards.
We're always trying to get more agile
depending on the project we're working on.
But in general, more agile
is going to be better
because it's going to
help us reduce our cost,
hit our time goals, and deliver a product
that our customer wants.
- The next thing we're going
to talk about is requirements,
and requirements are the
currency of an Agile project.
Requirements are going to tell
us what this product is going to
look like at the end.
We'll start with high-level
requirements, these are things
like project product descriptions.
It's the vision for the
product, it's product groupings,
we also might call these 'epics'
or 'huge stories' that give
us lots of features with
these high-level requirements.
And when we do that, we're
going to use a thing called the
MoSCoW prioritization, which
we'll talk about later.
This'll help us prioritize
those requirements in the things
must have, we should have, we
can't have, and we won't have.
Now, when we look at lower-level
requirements, this is down
at the team level.
These are our project
descriptions, they are our
requirements, they are
detailed features, they're user
stories that say "as a user,
I want to be able to do this
thing with the product".
And they're going to have these
lower-level requirements as
we go through, to really
give us the detail we need
to build across.
We're going to prioritize these
based on order, what is the
most important and what is
the least important, as we go
through and we work
through those problems.
Now as we move forward when
we look at these requirements,
we're going to start out all
the way with this big project
product description at the top.
This is a very high-level requirement.
We can then break that down.
So if I'm talking about a car,
we have a car as our project
product description.
It's going to have X amount
of seats, X amount of doors
and tires, you know, it's going
to be able to do this type
of thing.
Now, we don't know all of the
details that go in to making
that car yet, we just know we need a car.
We start breaking that down,
and so we'll have the engine
product group, we'll have
the electrical product group,
we will have the comfort
product group, right?
We'll have the safety
product group, which might be
the airbags and the brakes
and things like that.
And then we'll take on of those
product groups, like let's
say we're going to take the
electronics group, and in
that electronics group we're
going to break that down in
to different product descriptions as well.
We might have on for the radio,
we might have another one
for the headlights.
And then underneath the radio
we'll have the different
functions it should require.
In this radio, we need and
AM/FM radio, we need a tape
player, we need a CD player,
the ability to hook up
an iPhone, whatever those things are.
And you can see we take it
from this big, overwhelming
product, right, this car,
we've broken it down to
the electronics, and then
from the electronics down to
the radio, and from the
radio down to the different
functions.
And as we went from higher-level
to lower-level, we should
get more detailed in the
level of requirements we're
going to do.
Now, this is called decomposition,
and we'll talk more about
this as we go through.
The next Agile focus area we
have is rich communication,
because communication
problems can really derail
your project.
Whenever you can, you need
to proactively address
communication problems and
fix them, early and often.
Effective communication is
so fundamental to the way
we work in Agile, because
everything is team-based
and collaborative, and if
we can't communicate, we're
going to fall apart really
quickly, and we're not going to
be able to work in an Agile method.
Communication can take place
in many different formats.
It can be the traditional
E-mail or text message.
It can be written word,
such as writing it down on
a piece of paper or on a whiteboard.
It can be visualization by
drawing out pictures and using
kanban charts and things like that.
We can do it verbally
over the telephone or even
face-to-face.
There are lots and lots of
different ways to communicate
nowadays.
You have to figure out what's
going to be the best one that's
going to work well in your team.
Now, according to the Prince2
Agile exam, the best, fastest,
clearest, and most efficient
way to communicate is still
old-fashioned face-to-face communication.
Whenever possible, get
everyone in a room and talk to
them eye-to-eye.
By doing this, this is going
to help reduce the level
of formality, and it's
going to allow us to be able
to communicate quickest and
fastest because a lot of our
communication happens
through body language.
Now, when you deal with
technology, technology and your
level of formality needs
to be considered because if
you're across three or four
different states, you might have
to rely on things like Skype
to use video conferencing,
or you may have to just use E-mails.
These are things you're going
to have to consider as part
of your project.
Sometimes you need a
high level of formality.
If you're going to be putting
up a report, for instance,
that would be in written
form, not face-to-face
communication.
Written word does have it's
place, but there are a lot
of disadvantages when
dealing with written word.
Have you ever gotten a text
message from somebody and
you're not exactly sure if
they were joking or not?
Well if they had told you
that face-to-face, you
would've known, right?
Because you can read the body language.
And this is one of those
drawbacks from written word
to verbal.
Your project manager or your
team manager is going to be
responsible and aware of
how this team is going to be
communicating.
It's their responsibility
to come up with a good
communication plan and help
encourage the team to use it.
Communication does need to
be organized and it does
need to be planned.
One of the ways that we do
that is our daily stand-up
meetings as part of
our Scrum cycle, right?
Every morning we stand up
and for 15 minutes we go over
what we did yesterday and
what we're going to do today.
That's part of rich
communication, and again when that
can occur face-to-face that
is going to be the best way
of doing it.
One of the questions I
often get asked when people
start working an Agile
environment is: "How should I
communicate?", and I will
tell you that I am a big fan
of face-to-face communication
and using a lot of
visualization.
Because if I can draw
something up on the board, it's
going to be a lot clearer
than if we use a lot of words,
and so a three-page E-mail
is not nearly as effective
as a one-page infographic.
So that's the idea here
with visualization and then,
if I can do that in a face-to-face
manner, that's going to
eliminate a lot of
those questions as well.
So for the exam, remember
lots of visualization, lots
of face-to-face.
These are good things when
you're trying to communicate
effectively.
- The next Agile focus area is called
The Information Radiator
or the Team Board.
This is something that is
placed in your team's workspace
that allows you to visualize everything
that's being worked on.
So you can see here, we have the goal.
We're going to define
that the project is going
to be done by the end of the year.
Underneath that, you can see we have the
Kanban chart, showing
what is to be worked on
what's in progress, and what
is ready to be pushed out.
We can also see our team rules.
What are the things that our
team is going to buy into?
In this case: We should all be honest,
we should all be open
and everyone has a say.
So, really valuing that collaboration.
Then we go up on the other side.
We have our effort versus
time graph, which is
known as a burn down chart.
You could see the amount of
work that needs to be done
and the amount of time we have left.
And then, in the bottom corner,
we have issues and news.
And this is going to
be a way to tell people
new things about the
team, and what's happening
in the world around us and
things we have to consider
and the issues are things
we have problems with.
And those are issues
that we're bringing up
to the project manager
and the team manager
so they can help us deal with those issues
and make sure that we stay
on time and on budget.
Again, this is a great way
of visualizing information
and showing everybody what's going on.
Being open, being transparent and enabling
that rich communication
as we move forward.
Frequent releases are another
key concept inside of Agile.
With frequent releases, we're
really focused on releasing
something quickly that is
usable to the end customer.
This is going to be something
like a prototype or a beta
or it could be our finalized product.
Either way, it's going to
require a lot of planning
on our part, and we do this
using product-based planning
where we start with the end in mind.
What is this product we're trying to build
breaking it down into its component pieces
and putting it together.
There's a lot of advantages
to doing frequent releases.
The first is that you get early delivery
of benefits to your customer.
The customer gets something they can start
working with, and as they
start working with it,
they start going "Oh,
this isn't working the
"way I thought it was going to work".
And they give you
feedback, that allows you
to iterate for the next cycle.
This helps reduce the risk of
delivering the wrong product.
If I was going to build the entire product
from start to finish,
it may take me a year.
But if I can give them
something to look at,
maybe a wire frame diagram
of the app we're building
or may be able to give them a
couple of features to try out,
we could start to figure
out are we on the right path
to getting the final product?
Or, do we need to change
and adjust where we are?
This also gives us confidence
in how the project is progressing.
Because, if the customer keeps going
"Yes, this is good", "Yes, this is good"
"Yes, this is good" as we go along these
iterations, it really
does help the team know
they're on the right path.
This also is going to foster
better stakeholder engagement.
Because, the customer is
something they can touch
it's something they can
use and see if it's working
the way they wanted it to.
And, the final thing,
is it makes releasing
products easier. It
doesn't have to be this
big, huge deal where we release a product.
Because if we release
something, and it's not
quite right, we can go
back and iterate it again.
Whereas, if you use a waterfall approach,
it may have taken you a
year or two years to get
to this final product release.
And then, if you went
and hit the wrong thing,
that is going to be
devastating to your team.
So, frequent releases really are helpful
in the Agile way of working.
The next focus area we
have is Retrospectives.
And, retrospectives are a technique
that we use at the end of a sprint.
This is a technique
when we're working in an
agile way where we review
the ways the processes
that we use to get the product done.
This is something that we
have to plan and structure.
And it's going to cover
what went wrong and what
didn't go well.
Was there good communication involved?
Was there good collaboration?
What is working and what isn't?
We're going to improve little by little,
continuously, early, and often.
Because this is going
to help us get better
in the next sprint,
and in the next sprint,
and then the next sprint.
We also want to make sure
that the retrospectives
are efficient, and
effective, and to do this,
we might introduce variety.
Maybe, sometimes, we're going to do them
as a workshop. Maybe sometimes we're going
to do them as a lunch meeting.
Whatever it is, we want
to kind of break it up
a little bit so it is
not just so monotonous.
But, this is a great
way to gather feedback
in the forms of facts or feelings
of what you felt went well
Or, what actually went well.
Or, what you felt wasn't good.
Or, what really didn't go well.
And, by being table to
take all this information
we can learn from that experience
and improve ourself as we move forward.
Retrospectives are really key
to that continual improvement
as we move forward throughout
the processes, working in an agile way.
And, one of the ways we do that
is by workshops, I said, right?
Well, workshops are run as a way for us
to gather the information.
It uses live, face to
face interaction workshop
as a way to gather these lessons learned.
A workshop is run usually
by a neutral facilitator,
who can manage the workshop and make sure
the process is being done properly.
It is going to allow to get
these interactions and creativity.
We can use this for a retrospective.
But, we can also use this
for the prioritization
in creating all the
requirements for the product.
Workshops can be used at
any point during a project.
And, they're really useful
both at the beginning
of the project, with the
requirements gathering,
but also at the end of each sprint,
using them for retrospectives.
Now, this can help us get
quality outputs quickly,
if you conduct the proper preparation.
And, there are a couple
key areas you want to think
about, when preparing for this workshop.
You want to make sure that you've defined
what the objective of the workshop is.
Are we doing this workshop
to gather requirements?
Or, are we doing it as a retrospective?
We also need to figure out
who needs to be in attendance.
If we're going to be
gathering requirements,
that is going to be people
like your suppliers.
That is going to be
people like your customer,
your development team, your team manager,
and your project manager.
But, if we're going to do a retrospective,
we may have to bring in
other people, or less people.
And, so we have to think about that.
Logistics. You need to think about
where you're going to hold this workshop.
Is it going to be done
in a conference room?
Is it going to be done in a break room?
Is it going to be done
virtually, over technology?
You have to think about all of that.
And then, finally, pre-reading.
When you're preparing for this workshop,
not only are you preparing
to hold the workshop,
but the people who are coming
should be prepared, as well.
So, if we're going to go through
and we're going to develop
the idea for our next big product
as part of our requirements gathering,
and we're going to build a new iPhone app,
then we probably should
have some pre-reading
so people can understand
what's been popular
in the market space so far.
What are some of the ideas
we're already thinking about?
And, they can start
getting their minds ready
and in that mindset of
what we're going to do
when we have this workshop.
Now, when we do workshops, I've found
that there are three
great ways to hold these.
One is you want to make sure
you have lots of whiteboards there.
Because, you could write
up ideas really quickly,
you can erase them if they're bad,
and you can keep moving on.
Workshops should also
be group-working focus.
Everyone should be involved.
It shouldn't be one person
running the whole show
and answering all of the questions.
You want to get everybody involved in it,
because the best ideas come
from that collaboration
when we're working in an agile way.
And the other thing I
find works really well
is sticky notes, especially when you are
doing your requirements gathering.
Because, you can write it
down really quickly on a note
and stick it up on that whiteboard
and move them around very quickly.
And then, at the end, snap a picture of it
and you've got your work board
that you can start working from.
So this is just some of
the ideas that you have,
when you start working
through these workshops.
And, the more you practice them,
the better you're going to get.