- The next Agile focus area is called
The Information Radiator
or the Team Board.
This is something that is
placed in your team's workspace
that allows you to visualize everything
that's being worked on.
So you can see here, we have the goal.
We're going to define
that the project is going
to be done by the end of the year.
Underneath that, you can see we have the
Kanban chart, showing
what is to be worked on
what's in progress, and what
is ready to be pushed out.
We can also see our team rules.
What are the things that our
team is going to buy into?
In this case: We should all be honest,
we should all be open
and everyone has a say.
So, really valuing that collaboration.
Then we go up on the other side.
We have our effort versus
time graph, which is
known as a burn down chart.
You could see the amount of
work that needs to be done
and the amount of time we have left.
And then, in the bottom corner,
we have issues and news.
And this is going to
be a way to tell people
new things about the
team, and what's happening
in the world around us and
things we have to consider
and the issues are things
we have problems with.
And those are issues
that we're bringing up
to the project manager
and the team manager
so they can help us deal with those issues
and make sure that we stay
on time and on budget.
Again, this is a great way
of visualizing information
and showing everybody what's going on.
Being open, being transparent and enabling
that rich communication
as we move forward.
Frequent releases are another
key concept inside of Agile.
With frequent releases, we're
really focused on releasing
something quickly that is
usable to the end customer.
This is going to be something
like a prototype or a beta
or it could be our finalized product.
Either way, it's going to
require a lot of planning
on our part, and we do this
using product-based planning
where we start with the end in mind.
What is this product we're trying to build
breaking it down into its component pieces
and putting it together.
There's a lot of advantages
to doing frequent releases.
The first is that you get early delivery
of benefits to your customer.
The customer gets something they can start
working with, and as they
start working with it,
they start going "Oh,
this isn't working the
"way I thought it was going to work".
And they give you
feedback, that allows you
to iterate for the next cycle.
This helps reduce the risk of
delivering the wrong product.
If I was going to build the entire product
from start to finish,
it may take me a year.
But if I can give them
something to look at,
maybe a wire frame diagram
of the app we're building
or may be able to give them a
couple of features to try out,
we could start to figure
out are we on the right path
to getting the final product?
Or, do we need to change
and adjust where we are?
This also gives us confidence
in how the project is progressing.
Because, if the customer keeps going
"Yes, this is good", "Yes, this is good"
"Yes, this is good" as we go along these
iterations, it really
does help the team know
they're on the right path.
This also is going to foster
better stakeholder engagement.
Because, the customer is
something they can touch
it's something they can
use and see if it's working
the way they wanted it to.
And, the final thing,
is it makes releasing
products easier. It
doesn't have to be this
big, huge deal where we release a product.
Because if we release
something, and it's not
quite right, we can go
back and iterate it again.
Whereas, if you use a waterfall approach,
it may have taken you a
year or two years to get
to this final product release.
And then, if you went
and hit the wrong thing,
that is going to be
devastating to your team.
So, frequent releases really are helpful
in the Agile way of working.
The next focus area we
have is Retrospectives.
And, retrospectives are a technique
that we use at the end of a sprint.
This is a technique
when we're working in an
agile way where we review
the ways the processes
that we use to get the product done.
This is something that we
have to plan and structure.
And it's going to cover
what went wrong and what
didn't go well.
Was there good communication involved?
Was there good collaboration?
What is working and what isn't?
We're going to improve little by little,
continuously, early, and often.
Because this is going
to help us get better
in the next sprint,
and in the next sprint,
and then the next sprint.
We also want to make sure
that the retrospectives
are efficient, and
effective, and to do this,
we might introduce variety.
Maybe, sometimes, we're going to do them
as a workshop. Maybe sometimes we're going
to do them as a lunch meeting.
Whatever it is, we want
to kind of break it up
a little bit so it is
not just so monotonous.
But, this is a great
way to gather feedback
in the forms of facts or feelings
of what you felt went well
Or, what actually went well.
Or, what you felt wasn't good.
Or, what really didn't go well.
And, by being table to
take all this information
we can learn from that experience
and improve ourself as we move forward.
Retrospectives are really key
to that continual improvement
as we move forward throughout
the processes, working in an agile way.
And, one of the ways we do that
is by workshops, I said, right?
Well, workshops are run as a way for us
to gather the information.
It uses live, face to
face interaction workshop
as a way to gather these lessons learned.
A workshop is run usually
by a neutral facilitator,
who can manage the workshop and make sure
the process is being done properly.
It is going to allow to get
these interactions and creativity.
We can use this for a retrospective.
But, we can also use this
for the prioritization
in creating all the
requirements for the product.
Workshops can be used at
any point during a project.
And, they're really useful
both at the beginning
of the project, with the
requirements gathering,
but also at the end of each sprint,
using them for retrospectives.
Now, this can help us get
quality outputs quickly,
if you conduct the proper preparation.
And, there are a couple
key areas you want to think
about, when preparing for this workshop.
You want to make sure that you've defined
what the objective of the workshop is.
Are we doing this workshop
to gather requirements?
Or, are we doing it as a retrospective?
We also need to figure out
who needs to be in attendance.
If we're going to be
gathering requirements,
that is going to be people
like your suppliers.
That is going to be
people like your customer,
your development team, your team manager,
and your project manager.
But, if we're going to do a retrospective,
we may have to bring in
other people, or less people.
And, so we have to think about that.
Logistics. You need to think about
where you're going to hold this workshop.
Is it going to be done
in a conference room?
Is it going to be done in a break room?
Is it going to be done
virtually, over technology?
You have to think about all of that.
And then, finally, pre-reading.
When you're preparing for this workshop,
not only are you preparing
to hold the workshop,
but the people who are coming
should be prepared, as well.
So, if we're going to go through
and we're going to develop
the idea for our next big product
as part of our requirements gathering,
and we're going to build a new iPhone app,
then we probably should
have some pre-reading
so people can understand
what's been popular
in the market space so far.
What are some of the ideas
we're already thinking about?
And, they can start
getting their minds ready
and in that mindset of
what we're going to do
when we have this workshop.
Now, when we do workshops, I've found
that there are three
great ways to hold these.
One is you want to make sure
you have lots of whiteboards there.
Because, you could write
up ideas really quickly,
you can erase them if they're bad,
and you can keep moving on.
Workshops should also
be group-working focus.
Everyone should be involved.
It shouldn't be one person
running the whole show
and answering all of the questions.
You want to get everybody involved in it,
because the best ideas come
from that collaboration
when we're working in an agile way.
And the other thing I
find works really well
is sticky notes, especially when you are
doing your requirements gathering.
Because, you can write it
down really quickly on a note
and stick it up on that whiteboard
and move them around very quickly.
And then, at the end, snap a picture of it
and you've got your work board
that you can start working from.
So this is just some of
the ideas that you have,
when you start working
through these workshops.
And, the more you practice them,
the better you're going to get.