- Our last theme is Progress,
and as we consider the progress theme,
the big thing here is that there's no,
major changes that are
needed to the progress theme.
In fact, both PRINCE2 processes
and Agile techniques can both be used
and both have value in
measuring our progress.
When we start talking about
the Agile techniques though,
we're going to be focused
a little bit more,
on what is being delivered,
this includes stuff like
the velocity, how fast
it's being delivered,
the lead times, how long
does it take from the time
we initiate to the time
it gets to final delivery.
Or the value that it gives at the end.
We do this by using Burn Down
charts and Burn Up charts.
We also do this by demonstrating
the value that's been accrued.
There's tolerances that are
set early on in our process,
that support this by giving us the scope
and quality that we can work with.
And if we're not making enough progress,
we'll go back to the scope and quality
and redo some of those to
make the progress we need,
and get the deliverables out on time.
Progress is tracked at
all levels of the project,
down at the team level,
up at the stage level,
with the project manager and then up at
the project level with the project board.
And it's important that we maintain
progress towards our end goal.
Now as we look at progress,
the Agile perception of this
is that there's a large
emphasis on tracking progress.
PRINCE2 we always tracked
our progress as well,
but not nearly as much as Agile.
Agile is looking for daily updates,
we want to constantly know where are we at
in building things towards our end goal.
We do this using visualization techniques,
visualization techniques
are things like Burn charts,
and work in progress
charts, and we put these up
on the information radiator so everybody
can know exactly where we are.
By making sure there's
transparency in visualizing
and communicating the progress,
the team can all rally
around getting things done
and making sure we're
making the progress we need.
Whatever technique you
use, you want to make sure
your team is comfortable with that format.
If you want to use
spreadsheets and numbers,
that's fine if the team's good with it.
If you like charts and graphs instead,
then you should use those,
a lot of times though
it's a lot easier to use
a visualization technique,
like these charts and graphs I'm
going to show you in this lesson.
The first visualization
technique I want to
show you is called a Burn Chart.
And there's two types of
Burn Charts that we use,
one is called the Burn Down Charts,
and the other is called the Burn Up Chart.
Both of these are going to
show you the current situation,
the rate of progress, and
what has been completed.
But there is a difference,
with a Burn Down Chart,
we're going to assume that
there's a fixed amount of work,
with a Burn Up Chart we're going to assume
that the work amount is likely to
change even inside of one Spring.
And so as we look at this
Burn Down Chart on the screen,
you can see that we have two axises,
we have Time, and Effort Remaining.
And we have this nice straight line,
going from the amount of
effort at the beginning,
being 100%, all the way
down to zero percent,
once we hit our end of
our stage, or that time.
You'll see the jagged black line there,
that's showing the actual
work that has been done,
you'll see that originally,
we weren't meeting enough of the intent.
So we've put in extra work,
we've got back on schedule,
and actually created more effort done,
based on the time of where we wanted,
and now we're back towards the actual
line that we intended to be on.
Now as we move on to the next chart,
you'll see here is a Burn Up Chart.
A Burn Up Chart, instead
of starting at the top
and working down, is starting
at the bottom and working up.
The black line is the actual
work that has been produced,
and you can see, over time,
we're going to get up to 100%.
Now as you see, the total
work is that pink line.
And that is going to show
the work, as it starts out,
is fixed but somebody added
more work into this stage.
And so now we have a
higher level to be at.
But that started being too much,
so we've removed some and
the line came back down,
and we're constantly
adding and removing work,
until the effort and
the work end up meeting,
at the finish of the stage.
Another visualization technique we have,
is called a Cumulative
Flow Diagram, or CFD.
A Cumulative Flow Diagram
is used to track the work
and show the amount of work
that's remaining on each day.
So if we look at here on the chart,
you'll see this work in progress
board coming from our CONBON.
Now as you see we have the day listed,
we have what is ready,
what is being built,
what is being tested,
what is ready to deploy,
and what has actually been deployed.
And as we look across this, over the days
and across the columns
we can actually calculate
our lead time, how long does it take
for somebody to go from being
ready to being deployed.
You can look at this through
this chart and figure that out.
Now when we look at this
in a graphical form,
it's a little bit easier to see.
You can see here on day eight,
what was actually shown as ready,
in build, in test, ready
to deploy, and deployed.
And over time, we had a lot more deployed,
and a lot less ready
because we started pulling
things out inside this sprint
cycle to get that work done.
The last visualization technique
were going to talk about,
is called the Information Radiator.
And the Information
Radiator is a central board,
inside the teams workspace
that has all the information
on it that you could possibly
want to know about our project.
This is going to be visual
in nature most of the times,
and it's immediately accessible,
and gives you full transparency.
This is best created
and maintained manually,
by people actually writing things out,
and pinning it to a board,
we don't really like
doing this in a digital format,
because a lot of things get
lost in the digital space.
Plus, it's not centrally
seen by everybody,
when it's sitting on somebodies
website or somebodies SharePoint site.
Information here should be
pushed rather than pulled,
that means as the Project
Manager or the Team Manager,
or somebody on the team I
should be putting information
onto the Information Radiator,
so that everybody else on the
team can get that information.
When we hold our daily stand-up meeting,
we should be holding it around
the Information Radiator,
so we all can see a display and update
it immediately, as we're talking about it.
What does one of these
Information Radiators look like?
Well here's an example for you,
you can see on here we
have our team goals,
we have our Burn Charts,
we have what work is to do,
what's in progress, and
what's been deployed.
We have what issues we have,
we have what news we have,
and what our Team Rules are,
and this is just a sample of what kind
of information you can
sitting on your Team Radiator.