- What is project management?
After all PRINCE2 Agile
is focused on being
a project management framework.
Well, project management is the practice
of initiating, planning,
executing, controlling
and closing the work of a team to achieve
specific goals and meet
specific success criteria
at a specific time.
But we have to understand
what is a project.
Well a project is a temporary organization
that's created for the
purpose of delivering
one or more business products,
according to an agreed upon business case.
Now the key with a project
is that it is temporary.
It is for a short duration of time.
Now what exactly is a
short duration of time?
Well, a project may be a couple of months,
or it may be a couple
of years, but we're not
going to do a single
project and keep it going
for 20 or 30 years, that wouldn't be
a very temporary organization.
Now what kind of things
do we do with a project?
Well, we may be building a new building,
so if we're going to build
a skyscraper for example,
we have to plan exactly
when each part of that
I'm going to happen, that
includes building the foundation,
getting the work crews
on so that we can build
up the structure, and then we have to put
on the outside of the
building with the glass,
and the ceiling, and
then we're going to have
to go inside building and
start doing all the wiring
and the plumbing, there's a
lot of moving pieces here.
And so project management helps us manage
the output of this project
to make sure things are done
in the proper sequence,
in the proper order,
and to the proper cost.
On the other hand, if
we're going to do something
that's very normal and routine,
we call that business as usual.
Business as usual is defined
as work that is conducted
by an organization on a daily basis.
So if you work in IT for example,
and you need to setup a new user account,
you wouldn't need a project for that.
Instead, that's a simple
thing that you're going to do.
You'll get the person's
name, you'll create an email,
and you'll setup their account.
If we want to build a
whole new service for IT,
maybe we're going to
migrate all of our servers
from Windows into Linux,
that would be a project,
because it's bigger, it's more complex,
and it's more difficult.
And so that's what we're
going to do, is figure
out what is a project and
what is business as usual.
One of the key differences
between projects
and business as usual is what frameworks
you can use for them.
Agile can be used for both
projects and business as usual.
But PRINCE2 and PRINCE2 Agile
are designed specifically for projects.
If we're doing something
that's going to be considered
business as usual, you
can use Agile techniques,
but, you won't be using PRINCE2 Agile,
so any time we're going
to do a project we have
to decide are we're going to use PRINCE2
or are we going to use PRINCE2 Agile?
If it is something that
needs to be developed
in an Agile method,
then we're going to lean
towards PRINCE2 Agile.
If it's something that needs
really tight governance
and control structures,
that's when we're going to
lean more towards PRINCE2.
So in this course we
are going to be focused
on projects, not business as usual,
and so when we think
about a project remember,
it is something that is temporary.
We're going to create
a team to work on it.
This project may be difficult
in nature or complex,
and there's a certain degree
of uncertainty with it.
Now if we compare that to something that's
business as usual, that would be something
that's ongoing, there's a stable team
or a stable idea around how to do it.
There's this routineness
to it, we do it every day.
For example, I am always
going to be adding new users
to our system, that is
just something that happens
all the time, we don't need
a special project for that.
And there's this degree of certainty.
We know that if we do
steps one, two and three,
we're going to get output a.
But with a project, we have to figure out
what are the steps, what
order should they done
so that we can get the
output that we desire,
and that's the big difference between
business as usual and projects.
In this course we're going
to focus solely on projects.