- What is Agile?
Well, if you're taking this course,
I hope you at least have
an idea of what Agile is.
But if not, that's okay.
We're going to teach
you inside this lesson.
When we talk about Agile,
Agile was developed to address
new demands being placed on
the delivery of software.
Under the traditional model,
we would start a project
and it might take six months
or a year or two years
to deliver the end result.
But with Agile, the goal is
to get things out quicker,
cheaper, and faster, and
in most Agile developments,
something new is being released
every two to four weeks.
Agile can be viewed in
many different ways,
and in Prince2 Agile,
it's not just talking
about software development.
We apply this to all projects.
And so we'll talk about
when it's right to use Agile
verse when it's not right to use Agile
as we move through this course.
There are several well-known frameworks
that are out on the market
that are known as Agile ways of working.
Things like Kanban or Agile or Scrum.
And we'll talk about a lot
of these as we move forward.
Agile is characterized basically
as a family of behaviors,
concepts, and techniques.
There is no one way to do Agile.
But there are lots of
different pieces and techniques
that can be put together
to work in an Agile way.
And that's what Prince2 Agile tries to do
is they try to incorporate
the best of different ways
of working into a
framework that we can use
to deliver projects faster,
cheaper, and better than before.
Now, when we talk about the
old way of doing software,
what did it really look like?
Well, it used what's called
a waterfall development.
This was a very linear
process where we had an idea,
and then we had Phase One to Phase Two
to Phase Three to Phase
Four to Phase Five,
and we actually then delivered something.
And so you could see how this
moved down the ladder over time,
and this may Have taken
three months or six months
or 12 months from the time we had an idea
to the time something
got out in operations.
This is the traditional
project management method.
And this is what is shown
basically back in the processes
I showed you in the seven process lecture
under the original Prince2 Framework.
Now, when we start moving into Agile,
we started using things that are
iterative in their development.
We did this spiral.
And so we kind of keep
improving a little bit at a time
until we get to where we want to go.
And so you'll notice that now
instead of having one product
that took us that entire
time, let's say one year,
to get from concept to delivery.
In that same time we're now
able to get four products out.
Now, are they the same
level of depth of a product?
Probably not.
But, we're getting more out,
better, faster, and cheaper.
And notice that the first time
we got something in operations
was only about 30 to 40% of
the way along this timeline.
And so by doing this spiral,
we can really get things
done quicker, faster,
and get things into the hand of our user.
That's the whole idea of Agile.
If we want to get
something out there quickly
so we can get feedback on it, better it,
improve upon it, and
then put out Version Two,
Version Three, and Version Four.
And by doing that, we get a
lot better product in the end.
Now, this whole thing
about Agile was created
based on a document called
the Agile Manifesto.
This is the closest
single definition of Agile
you're going to be able to find.
And it was created as this alternative
to that slower waterfall
development process.
So if you pull up the Agile Manifesto,
you'll see that it starts out this way.
"We are uncovering better
ways of developing software
"by doing it and helping others do it.
"Through this work, we have come to value
"these four things:
"individuals and interactions
over processes and tools.
"Working software over
comprehensive documentation.
"Customer collaboration
over contract negotiation.
"And responding to change
over following a plan.
"That is, while there is value
on the things on the right,
"we value the things on the left more."
So, what this really breaks down
is the fact that Agile
is a team-based approach.
They focus on these individuals
and this interaction
that happens to bridge communications
instead of doing things based on processes
and tools and the old ways.
They focus on getting working
software out there quicker
and faster as opposed to having a product
that may be perfect and well-documented,
but it took three years
to get it to market.
They focus on this customer collaboration
where it's actually a
process where the customer
and the supplier are working together
to get this product to market,
as opposed to the traditional
contract negotiations
where everything is written
up formally, legally,
and with a scope of work.
They work on responding to change
over this following of a plan
because things change in the development.
If you're building a
website and somebody says,
you know what, I don't
want it to blue, I want it
to be purple, can you go
through and change that quickly?
Or do we have to go back to
a new contract negotiation?
In the old methods, we would have
to go back to a contract negotiation.
But in Agile we don't.
We're able to work
quicker, faster, and better
by using these processes
and these techniques.
And that is what Agile is focused on.
So if you're familiar
in the software world
and you've heard of
Agile development before,
you'll notice that there's generally
this basic perception of what Agile is.
And it comes down to three main things.
They think about it as
a time-based approach,
they think about it as a
collection of techniques,
and they think about it
in the terms of Scrum.
Now, when I talk about
a time-boxed approach,
this is where Agile likes to take things
and break it down instead
of into stages, into time.
And everything is a fixed unit of time.
And so, your time might
be every two weeks,
we're going to release something.
Or every four weeks we're
going to release something.
That is a time-based approach
or a time-boxed approach.
Now, the second thing is this
collection of Agile techniques.
And int he software world, a
lot of times we'll take things
out of different pieces of
Agile from different techniques
and try to combine them together
to get to a finished product.
And then finally we have Scrum.
Scrum has become almost
synonymous with Agile.
But, there are lots of
other frameworks out there
that are Agile that aren't Scrum.
And so as we try to
expand our view from just
this basic view of Agile
into a more wholistic view,
we look at how Prince2 use Agile.
And in Prince2, we look at Agile
beyond this basic perception.
We look at it more comprehensively.
We want to think about
it more as the vision,
the roadmap, and the releases
we want to get out there.
That's kind of the overarching plan.
We think about it in non-IT situations.
We can use Agile to do
all sorts of things,
from marketing campaigns to websites
to building a fixed product.
And we think about it in
terms of project work,
not as business as usual,
which is a lot of what Agile is used for.
And the final thing we think about,
is it being flow-based work,
where we can take more or get less
based on how fast we can
process through requirements.
With a basic perception of Agile,
we have a product backlog,
it's all the requirements
that we have from our customers.
We'll pick out what we're
going to use in our time box,
called a sprint, and say we'll take
five or six different requirements,
and we're going to work on
them this two-week period.
We'll get all those worked, and
we'll ship that product out.
And then we'll start another sprint.
We'll pull out more backlog.
We'll work on those, and
we'll ship those products out.
That's the way a basic Agile will work
in the software world.
Now, with Prince2 Agile,
we're going to take those
Agile sprints and combine them
with our Prince2 processes.
And so you can see here
that we have our typical
Agile process that only
talks about sprints.
But here we're going to
build in this governance
and control mechanism that we can use it
with other projects that
aren't just software.
And so you'll see in the
starting upper project phase
and the initiating a project
phase, we are going to have
the vision and the
product backlog created.
From that, we're going to
select what's going to go
into our controlling
stage, which is our sprint.
And here we're going to
get our sprint backlog.
We're going to put those into our time box
of two to four weeks, we're
going to work on those,
we're going to get the
product backlog done,
we're going to get the release
backlog done, and then we're
going to be able to get
approval to ship that product.
Now, this may not look very different yet,
but as we go through the course
and we talk about each
of these things in depth,
it really is going to tie
together and make a lot sense.
The idea here is that we can
apply these Agile concepts
to anything we want to build.
It doesn't have to just be software.