- In the last lesson we talked about
the six performance variables.
Time, cost, risk, benefit,
scope and quality.
Now, you may be wondering we we're able to
flex some and fix some.
And it really comes
down to the five targets
which represent the reasoning why
we have these six areas
and why we're going to
find or fix certain ones.
These five targets all come down to
being on time and hitting deadlines,
protecting the level of quality,
embracing change, keeping your team stable
and accepting that the customer
doesn't need everything.
We're going to talk about
each of those in this lesson.
The first one is being on time
and hitting your deadlines.
We talked about the
fact that time was fixed
in an Agile project.
The reason is, we need to
get a product out there
to get that early realization of benefits.
This is going to help us
with further planning,
giving us confidence that
we can deliver things
and sometimes we just have no choice
but to deliver on time.
By doing all of this and
hitting our deadlines
it really does reduce our likelihood
of having cost over runs,
and it's going to help us
to improve our reputation.
Because if we hit our deadlines
the customer starts realizing
that when you say you're
going to get something
out on time, they can
take that to the bank.
They know you're going to deliver.
Now, you many not deliver with everything
they wanted, but you're
going to give them something.
And that's the key here.
We want to build this trust between
the customer and the
supplier relationship,
and being on time and
hitting those deadlines
is critical to that.
The next one we have when
we talk about the five
targets is embracing change.
Because change is inevitable.
You're going to hit
roadblocks inside your project
and you're going to
have to move around them
and change things up to get to something
that's deliverable.
The more accurate your final product is,
is going to be based on how much change
and how quickly you can
adapt to that change
based on what your seeing.
In Agile we are very, very focused
on embracing change.
Because we know that we have the ability
to flex with intolerances, to get to what
needs to be delivered.
A lot of times you'll have a customer
who asks for something,
and they don't really
define the requirement well.
And so when you start building it
you realize, you know they asked for X
but they really need Y.
By embracing change you have the ability
to flex what is being delivered
and deliver Y instead
of X and the customer
will usually be happier for it.
The third target we're going to talk about
is protecting the level of quality.
This is important because it ensures
that you have the appropriate level
of quality being achieved in order
for you to get the desired
outcomes and benefits
that you were expecting.
A lot of times poor quality can happen
if you start reducing your testing cycle,
if you don't bother to
do any documentation,
if you create a sub optimal design.
Sometimes it happens because you don't
give good training to your end user
and they don't understand how to use
the product you delivered.
And sometimes you just decide
you're not going to
comply with any standards
in the marketplace and
you design something
on your own.
And when you don't comply with standards
that's going to decrease your
level of quality as well.
Now, to protect the level of quality
that's where this fix and flex comes in.
Again, we're going to fix those required
and essential items but we're going
to flex the requirements
for those that are desired.
And the reason is that by flexing
on the desired things we can free up
more time and resources to focus
on those required or essential things,
improving the quality there which is
going to have more impact
to our final project.
Our fourth target that
we're going to look at
is keeping our teams stable.
Agile uses this concept
of self organizing teams
and informal communication.
And because of that you
have to have this team
trust that gets built.
There's this norming and forming stage
that happens and eventually the team
starts working together well.
Well if you start getting
behind on a project
and you go, you know
what, let's just throw in
another person into that team,
that'll give us additional people,
we can get more work done, it usually
will actually have a detrimental effect.
Because when we bring in a new team member
we have to spend time
getting them up to speed
of where we are.
We also have to start
increasing the number
of communication lines.
So now instead of having
fie people to communicate
on our team, we have six or seven.
And that takes more time
and as we start growing
that becomes harder to deal with.
Teams should be kept small as they work
on a project.
There's opportunity
costs that also incurred
because if I start looking at Jason's team
over here is behind schedule and we're
going to take somebody from Ally's team
and bring them over, well now Ally's team
is one person down.
And there's opportunity
cost that's incurred
by taking that person
away from Ally's team
because they're not able to do what
they need to do now.
And the other thing is,
when I bring in new people
the team dynamics change.
And when you change those team dynamics
everything has to be re-established
because there may be
trust with the five people
on the current team, but when you bring in
person number six,
nobody knows that person.
Nobody trusts them, they're still feeling
them out and figuring out if they
can trust that person
and if they understand
and respect their opinion.
So, what we look at with Agile,
is keeping your team stable.
On the exam, if you get asked a question
about this, the appropriate time
to add or remove people from the team
is at the end of a sprint.
Get through your entire month long sprint
and then you can change out the teams
and start again.
That's okay.
But if you're behind schedule
the idea that you can throw more
people at the problem is
not going to save you,
it's going to actually
cause you more problems
and get you further behind.
Now the final target we have is
accepting the fact that the customer
doesn't need everything.
This is a really true statement
because customers will tell you
all of the things that they need
and if you're asking them about a car
they want you to build and you start
getting all the requirements you may
get some silly things in there,
like I want a car that can fly,
I want a car that can drive itself,
I want a car that can
go zero to 3,000 miles
on one tank of fuel.
Those are all great things and hopefully
we can get there one day but today
the technology doesn't
exist for all of those.
And so you have to start prioritizing
the features of the product that are
the safest and most sensible area
that you want to be able to get done
and then the things that
you can compromise on,
you want to compromise on.
You want to realize that not everything
defined at the start of the project
has to be delivered as a final output.
And this is very different
then our traditional
waterfall development.
In Agile we understand that we may have
100 requirements and we're only going to
deliver 10 of those.
Many of the functions and features
are never even used in the final product.
And so it's okay to remove those.
Let's think about Microsoft PowerPoint
or Microsoft Word.
How many functions do you actually use
in one of those programs.
Most people probably use about 10 or 15.
You might use some things like
changing the font color or the font size
or centering it versus left justifying it.
But those programs have thousands
of different features.
And if I took away half of the features
in that program, you probably wouldn't
even know as a customer.
And so removing features can help you
to meet the deadlines you need
and protect the level of quality
for those essential items.
So again going back to my Microsoft Word
example, things like changing font sizes
and changing font colors and be able to
left justify or center.
Those are essential things
that people use everyday,
we want to make sure those are protected.
But if there's something
like the mail merge function
that maybe one out of 1,000
customers are going to use,
we can sacrifice on the
level of quality there
if needed.
And we also want to make sure
that we're delivering what the customer
really wants and what
they really need quickly.
And by removing all
these additional features
that may take us months or years to get to
we can give them a product today
that does 90% of everything they need
which is going to make them happier
to have something in
their hand they can use
as opposed to something on the shelf
that you're still developing.
Now when we look at all of this
these are those five targets and
these are the reasoning of why we fix
and why we flex on different requirements
inside Agile development.