- [Jason] Our first theme
is the business case,
and the first thing we
have to do inside the
business case is define what value is.
Value is the benefits that
are delivered in proportion
to the resources that we put into it.
So if I'm going to put in
a $1,000,000 of company
assets, I'm hoping that
I'm going to get at
least a $1,000,000 back out.
That would be a positive
evaluation and a positive return
on our investment inside this project.
Now, the problem is when we look at
value, it's not always so clean.
It's not $1 in equals $2 out.
Often, it's going to be subjective.
Maybe I'm going to spend
$10,000 on an ad campaign,
so you know who I am and you start
knowing me and trusting me more.
That had some subjective outcomes that
we're going to have to figure out.
So when you do this, it's often
easier just to assign relative values.
Maybe something like small,
medium, or big, right?
That would be the relative
value, as opposed to saying
that if I put $10,000
into this ad campaign,
I'm going to get back $16,243 in value.
Maybe I would just say I'm
going to get back medium value.
And so, these values can be
assessed in many, many ways.
If you look at value, it may be
tied directly to your revenue.
It may be that I put in $10,000
and get back $20,000 in profit.
It may be that I've reduced cost.
I spent $10,000 on
building this new IT system
that's going to reduce my
manpower requirements, and that's
going to save us money every
single month moving forward.
Or, value may even be something
like customer satisfaction.
It may cost me money to
provide a better customer
experience, but that
customer satisfaction may be
worth it in the end and be
of more value to us than
the actual revenue or reducing cost.
And so it really does depend
on what your end goals
are for your particular project.
The idea here is we want to
focus on the benefits, and
these benefits are going to be
helped through collaboration.
We want to get a benefit that's comes from
an outcome that comes from an output.
Now, what does that mean?
Well, if I start doing some process,
and building some thing, that's an output.
That output enables our
customer to get the outcome
they want, and that outcome
can then turn into a benefit.
If I'm going to create a
new process in a new piece
of software that's going
to more quickly filter
through your emails, that's an output.
When you take that and
you put it into practice,
you're trying to achieve
an outcome, saving yourself
time going through your inbox.
Now, if it does do that,
you're going to realize
that, as a benefit, you've saved 3 hours
per day of going through emails.
That's how we take our output,
move it into an outcome,
and then, ultimately,
get that benefit, which
is what we derive our value from.
Now, as we look forward
and we start looking
at how we're going to
tailor the business case,
there's not any major
changes in the business case
that are required, because
the business case is something
that's fairly universal in
traditional Waterfall Development
as well as an Agile Development.
The only real thing
here is that we're going
to need more information on tolerances
around what the intended benefit is.
And what I mean by that is,
if I'm building a piece of
software to save you 3 hours a
day by filtering your emails,
then I'm going to have to
build intolerances as they're
building the project of
what features are needed
and how well those features need to work.
Another thing that we're
going to tailor inside the
business case is the
realization that we're trying to
get early benefits by
applying early costs.
And what I mean by that is
we want to develop something
like a minimum viable product.
I want to get you some
incremental delivery.
If I can get you version 1 of
my email filtering software,
and you could start using
it, and you realize that it's
only giving you an
hour-and-a-half savings per day,
then you can recommend some
tweaks and give me some
feedback that I can implement
into version 2, and by
doing this incremental
delivery, giving you a little
bit and a little bit and a
little bit, we could start
getting feedback quicker and adjust it to
give us a better valuation and benefit.
Lastly, Agile is focused on
getting value from a user story.
This is where it says "I
am this person and I want
this thing so that I can do X benefit."
This is going to allow for
better feature prioritization
when we need to do that,
because a lot of times, our
business case may state that
we're going to get end benefit
of X but we don't have enough money
to build everything that X needs.
And so we're going to have
to start prioritizing.
What is the most important
thing to the customer?
What do they value?
And based on that, we'll make
prioritization decisions.
So, how does Agile view the business case?
Well, inside of Agile there
are 3 main considerations
for the business case, and
the first one may shock you.
It's that in some Agile environments,
you may not need a business case at all.
Instead, they would replace
that with user stories or the
intended value and benefits
that we're trying to achieve.
It would be a very very summarized version
of a business case essentially,
because it's going to leave
out all of the formality
and all of the details.
The second thing we have
to remember is that there's
often a focus on value
assigned to features
instead of an end result or an output.
So again, this is what features are
important to our customer;
where do they derive value from?
And so, if there's features
that are important to them,
that's something that we're going to have
to build into that business case.
And finally, we have to
remember that the business case,
or this user stories, or
whatever we're developing instead
of a business case, it has to be created
at the beginning of our project.
This would be back in
what we would refer to as
the Starting Up A Project
Phase in Traditional Prince 2.
In an Agile environment though
we may call this Sprint Zero.
Sprint Zero is where
we're doing all the prep
work before moving into the first
Sprint where we actually start work.
So in summary, let me provide
you some guidance on the
business case, as it implies
inside of an Agile environment.
First, the business case may be affected
by the amount of things being delivered.
So, if we have a very
large product backlog,
that's going to have a lot of
different features that have
to be prioritized and
figured into it, and the
business case is going
to be affected by that.
If we have a very small
list of features, and things
we want to deliver, then we may
not even use a business case,
but instead just use the user stories.
Second, early delivery of benefits is
going to affect our business case.
If I develop a minimum viable
product and I start getting
that to customers, and they
start using it, and they
realize it's great, that's
good for our business case,
but they start using it and
realize that it's horrible,
that may mean that we're
going to abandon this project.
And because of this, you
really needed to find in your
business case what is going to
be your minimum viable product?
What is the minimum thing
you have to deliver that's
going to give the benefit to
the customer they're expecting?
Your project viability is not the
same as your minimum
viable product either.
Minimum viable product is the
least amount of product you
need to deliver, but the
project viability is based
on whether it's going to be
received well based on what
value is going to be gotten
out of this project, and the
minimum viable product is only version 1.
We're going to reiterate
and do incremental
development of that as
we keep moving forward.
So project viability must go
past the minimum viable product
for us to be able to get
to version 2 and version 3.
We also needed to find
inside of this business case
what is our best-case,
worst-case, and expected-case in
relation to the amount of
features we're going to deliver?
Best-case is I give a customer
100% of what they asked for.
Worst-case is probably half of that.
Expected-case, probably
somewhere in the 70-80% range,
because again, our customer
doesn't have to get delivered
everything they want, but we do
need to know what's the worst-case?
What are the minimum things that
they need to have a viable product?
And the final guidance
is that high uncertainty
leads to more minimal business cases.
If I'm going to do something
that's brand new that we've
never done before, we need
to just start getting into it
and start testing our assumptions quickly.
If it's something that's more
certain, and it's something
that's a bigger project, for
example we're building a house
that's more certain, we know
what the end state needs to
look like, then we would have
a well-defined business case,
but often if we're doing things
like software development,
or we're doing things like
putting on a production,
there are things that are
highly uncertain in that.
And because of that, we just need to get
things out there and see what sticks.
It's all about getting those things out
and testing those assumptions quickly
so that we can move on
into the next phases.