- So up to this point, we've
talked a lot about PRINCE2.
And we talked about the principles,
the themes, and the processes.
And then, I started talking about
the three main different
types of Agile frameworks.
But we haven't talked much
about how to blend the two yet.
And that's what we're going to
start doing in this lecture.
And going throughout
the rest of the course.
So when we talk about
Agile, the way that PRINCE2
looks at Agile is as
a family of behaviors,
concepts, frameworks, and techniques.
So what does that really mean for us?
Well as we start looking at
PRINCE2, which started out
as a very firm project
management technique.
And now, it's starting to try to implement
Agile inside of it.
We have to understand how we can do that.
When we look at PRINCE2 Agile,
they look at Agile as
not the, simply the way,
but it is a way of doing projects.
And what I mean by that, is it
all comes down to tailoring.
PRINCE2 in it's purest
form allows for tailoring,
because that's the seventh
one of the principles.
And tailoring PRINCE2
really does focus on the
project context and what
it's going to affect.
This includes things like how formal
we're going to be in the project.
Where the emphasis is
placed in the project.
And how we're going to
carry out the project.
And this naturally leads itself,
to implementing well with Agile.
And so, when start looking
at Agile and these different
behaviors, concepts, and techniques.
We have to start looking
at the way that we do Agile working.
And how this is going to be different,
to the way we would do Agile,
in one of the pure Agile frameworks.
Something like Scrum, or
Kanban, or Lean startup.
And so, as we start looking at that,
we first have to look
at our Agile behaviors.
These behaviors can also be known
as our principles, our
values, or our mindset.
Some examples of these
behaviors are things like
being collaborative,
being self organizing,
being customer focused,
empowering your team members,
and trusting your team
members and not blaming them.
By really taking these concepts at heart,
PRINCE2 Agile really
does focus on making sure
we can do the best job in our projects,
by using collaborative,
self-organizing teams,
delivering products
that the customer wants,
and empowering our team
members to make decisions,
and trusting them to do the right thing.
That's what we're looking
at when we start talking
about these behaviors.
Now, as we start looking forward
and we look at that in PRINCE2,
there is five key areas
that we really focus on.
And this is transparency, collaboration,
rich communication,
self-organization, and exploration.
These are the Agile
behaviors inside of PRINCE2.
So we talk about transparency,
this is focused on being open,
visible, honest, trusting people,
having integrity, and having respect
amongst the team and amongst
your fellow co-workers.
By having this transparency, we all know
where we are in the project,
we all know what needs to
get done in the project,
and we can all work
together to get it done.
Which brings us to collaboration.
Collaboration is this
internal collaboration
amongst our team where
they work well together.
But we also have collaboration externally,
between the team and the customers.
To make sure we have a
shared understanding of
what needs to be delivered
and who's responsible for what.
Where does that ownership really occur?
Now, to make all of this happen and
to have transparency and collaboration,
you have to have rich communication.
And when we talk about
communication in Agile,
we really want to do as much communication
face to face as possible.
Because, while email is good
and phone calls are okay,
when you have a face to face
communication with somebody,
you really do knock down all of the walls.
And you eliminate anything
that might be hidden.
And so everything becomes
fully transparent.
It allows communication to
occur quickly and to the point.
And it really does help
progress to move forward.
Next, we have self-organization.
When we have these teams, we
want to be able to trust them.
And trust the people in
the teams, so that they
can take action and get things done.
Allowing self-organization
of the teams to happen,
this inherently is going to
build more trust within the team.
Because, if I'm picking people on my team
that I like to work with,
I'm inherently going to trust them more.
So that's really going to
help with all of the other
things that we already talked about.
And really getting more progress
done, inside of a project.
And the fifth one that we look at
with Agile behaviors is exploration.
Again we talked about this back in Kanban
and we talked about this in Lean startup.
We want to do frequent
iterations with rapid feedback.
So that we can get an
opportunity to learn,
so we want to experiment
and create spikes.
Put something out there
and see what happens.
That is going to be something
that we really do focus on
as one of these principle, or behaviors,
or values inside of Agile
in a PRINCE2 environment.
Now, as we move forward
we start to talk about
the concepts inside of PRINCE2.
Now we look at concepts
from an Agile prospective,
these would be known as our fundamentals.
What are some of the fundamentals
that we start considering?
Well we want to think about
how we prioritize what
is going to be delivered.
We start realizing that
the customer doesn't
need to have everything.
They need to have the important things.
And so, prioritization is going to be key
as we start working and
planning our sprints.
We have to work iteratively
and we have to increment frequently.
And so again that Lean startup concept of
build and learn is going to
be important for us, right?
Build, measure, learn.
And then we're going to have,
not delivering everything
that's asked for.
This is a key concept inside of Agile.
When we look at PRINCE2,
from a structure perspective,
in the older PRINCE2,
the Non-Agile environment.
It really is focused on requirements.
At the beginning of
project, we list everything
that this thing needs to have.
And at the end of the project,
it has to have all of those things,
otherwise we have exceptions
and changes that have to go in.
But with Agile, we understand that
we don't know everything upfront.
Instead, we put a list of all
the things we think we want.
And then we're going to prioritize
as we go through the project.
The other thing in Agile that
we look at, is time focused.
And we talk about this in Timeboxing.
We're going to have strict sets of time,
that is set aside to build
these phases of the project.
We're also going to inspect
and adapt things as they go.
And again, if we inspect it
and we don't find what we like,
we iterate it and we
start working on it again.
We have this idea of
continuous improvement,
known as Kaizen in Japanese.
And this is really important
inside of Agile as well,
because we're always trying
to get the next thing.
And get it better, and quicker,
and faster, and cheaper, right?
And that continuous
improvement of our processes
allows us to do that.
And then, taking in from
Kanban, we limiting our
work in progress.
This is another thing, it is
a key concept inside of Agile
that we have to consider.
Now, we've talked about behaviors,
we've talked about concepts.
The third part with techniques.
These are known as the practices,
or the tools we're going to use.
And things in this area are things like
burn charts that will
measure our progress,
we'll talk about those
more in the progress theme.
User stories, which take the
place of our requirements.
Retrospectives, where we
try to learn what happened
during the sprint and
how we can do it better.
Timeboxing, where we
give ourselves two weeks
or four weeks inside of the sprint.
And then measuring flow,
which again is how quickly
we can take something from an
idea to a finished product.
And that again comes from
our Kanban perspectives
as we measure how things
are moving across.
So these are just some of the techniques,
and we'll talk a lot about
them in depth as we go
through the rest of this course.
Now, when we blend PRINCE2
and Agile together,
we do this because it gives
us the best of both worlds.
We can do things in a purely Agile method,
but when we do that, we're
very delivery focused.
We're all about getting products out.
And that doesn't give us
a lot of the direction,
and management, and
governance that we might want.
Especially in more
larger complex projects.
Now when we look at
PRINCE2, it tends to be
very management driven
and very heavy focused
on that governance and control.
But, by blending the two together,
we get the best of both worlds.
We getting the governance,
management, and control
from PRINCE2 coming down.
As you can see on the left side here.
And we have Agile
delivery focus coming up.
And so we get that area of
strength from both of them
and blend them together.
To give us something that
really does work well
in the real world,
as we start going through our projects.
Instead of using something
that's purely Agile
or purely PRINCE2,
we get this PRINCE2 Agile that really does
give us the best of both.
So, when I take the best of both,
what do I end up with?
Instead of ending up with
the three things from
PRICNCE or the five things from Agile
I end up with eight combined things.
I get the principles, the themes,
and the processes, from PRINCE.
Giving me that structure,
that guidance, that management
prospective from the top down.
But I also get the five
key areas from Agile,
the frameworks, the
behaviors, the concepts,
the techniques, and the focus areas.
And by combining all of
this together we really
do get a wonderful
package for working in an
Agile method as we move forward.