- We've come a long way in the last couple
of hours together.
We started out talking about PRINCE2
and the seven principles,
the seven themes,
and the seven processes,
then we went in through all
of the different Agile
techniques, behaviors,
concepts and tools.
Then we brought them all together
and talked about how we
can apply those Agile ways
of working inside of
the PRINCE2 principles,
themes, and processes.
At this point, you should
know everything you need
to be successful on exam day.
I want you to go through and
take the practice exam now,
go over your answers,
and see how you score.
Good luck on the exam,
and I hope to see you
in a future course.