- In this video, we're going to talk about
Lean Startup, and the whole idea with
Lean Startup as an agile methodology is
for us to fail fast and learn fast.
The concept of the Lean Startup method
is for us to develop business practices
and products very, very quickly.
The whole concept is to shorten your
development life cycle by doing
experimentation, iterative
product releases,
learning something very
quickly and whether
you fail or you succeed,
that's going to tell
you something that you can implement into
the next release, and we want to validate
our learning and that's the whole concept.
When you start talking about Lean Startup,
there's a couple of key
terms you have to know.
The first one of those is MVP,
or Minimum Viable Product.
Minimum Viable Product is this version
of your product that allows you to collect
the maximum amount of validated learning
with the least amount of effort.
So, if I wanted to build
a program in software,
I don't need to program every single
function and feature out there to
make it and release that product.
Instead, I need to put the core pieces
into that software, release it into the
environment, and see what I can learn
based on the customer feedback.
The idea here is for us to test those
business hypotheses that we have
and make these leap-of-faith assumptions.
This allows us as a company to determine
very quickly if an idea is really viable
and worth continued investment,
and the whole idea with an MVP or
this minimum viable product is for us to
really get something out
into the world quickly.
Now, it doesn't have to
be your final product
and it doesn't have to
go into operational use.
You can do it as an
experiment or a prototype.
That's okay too. The
idea is to get something
into the hands of your end-users
so they can tell you, do they like it,
do they not like it and
by doing that, we can
find out very quickly
before we invest a ton of
money and a ton of
resources at this product,
is it something that
people are going to buy.
This is very, very common
in the online space,
a lot of online products go on Kickstarter
now, right and when they do that,
they're doing a minimum viable product.
What they do is they make a video or
a commercial for the product that may
not even exist and see
if they can get funding
for it and if they do,
that validates their idea
and they go forth and build the product.
That is the minimum
viable product they need
to be able to get money
and get that commitment.
It's just a video. Now, in the real world,
we often will have to put out something
tangible so that people
can get that minimum
viable product, use it, figure out if they
like it, and then give
us feedback from there,
but either way, the idea is the same.
We want to get something
out there, quickly,
so we can learn from
it and that's going to
bring us to our next
thing, which is called
continuous development.
In lean startup, this is very heavily used
in the software development space.
The whole idea with continuous development
is for us to be able to
get something out there
and then quickly iterate it and get
the second version, the third version
and the fourth version out there.
Instead of giving us this fully, finished,
and polished thing,
we're going to have all
the code written very quickly
and immediately deployed
out into production.
Now, this is horrible from
a security standpoint,
but it is great from an operations
standpoint because we can get
things out there very, very, quickly.
This is going to help
reduce development cycles
and when you're talking about using agile
Lean startup is one of
the most agile methods
in this case because they can lead
to daily production releases and
sometimes multiple times per day.
Now, since we're going to be putting this
with more governance and framework
by using Prince2, we're
actually going to do this
as part of our timebox and we're going to
release things at the end of a time box.
So, two weeks or four weeks, which gives
us more time for testing
before deployment,
but in lean startup, the idea
is get things out continuously.
We're not going to stop
and wait for a deadline.
Instead, we're going to do
it as soon as it's ready,
push it out, and see if it works.
So again, this could be
really bad for security
and it can cause a lot
of issues if you don't
have proper testing in
place. So keep that in mind.
The next one we have is split testing,
also known as AB Testing.
This is where you create two version of
your product and you offer them out,
so let's go back to our
kickstarter example.
Maybe we make two
different versions of the
product, or two different
videos for the product
and see which one performs better.
The whole goal here is for us to observe
the differences in behavior
between two customer
groups and so, if I take
this course for example
maybe I'm going to have
one background that has
a white background with purple text on it
and I have another
background that's purple
with white text and I
put out two identical
versions of the product,
but one with purple
and one with white and I see which group
of students like it
better, which one gives
us better reviews, which
one sells more copies,
all of that kind of thing.
That's the idea with split testing.
Very similar product
with different versions
to figure out which features the students
like best or the customers, in your case.
When you do AB testing,
the important thing
to remember is it should always be done
at the same time to minimize variables.
A lot of companies do
this wrong and they'll do
this week we're going to sell product one
and next week, we're
going to sell product two.
That's different times, different cultural
situations, and different
amounts of students.
Instead, we should do
both of them this week
and see which one sells better,
and this can be done
very well in an automated
environment, especially
when you're dealing
with website testing because you can serve
up version one to the first customer,
version two to the second and keep going
back and forth and then see the results.
Now, the next one we're
going to talk about is
the process inside of lean startup,
and they call this build-measure-learn
process as you can see here on the screen.
The process starts with an idea.
We have an idea for a
product and immediately
we're going to jump into building it.
As we build this, we're going to
create our product and release it.
Notice that we're only
halfway through the cycle,
but we've already released a product.
Then, once that product is
out there, we're going to
measure what we get
back from our customers.
That's feedback, right.
We collect all of that,
which gives us data.
That data is in analyze
so we can learn something
and that is going to
give us an idea for what version to the
product will look like and then we'll
build version two, we'll
release version two,
measure version two, we'll collect data on
version two, and we'll
learn from version two,
and then, we create
version three, and we keep
going through this loop over
and over and over again.
The whole idea is to
get ideas to market as
quickly as possible, so
we can learn something,
and we're either going to
fail fast and learn fast,
or we're going to
succeed. Either way, we're
going to learn something very quickly
and get to the next, better version.