- So, how do we use Scrum in our projects?
Well, when we start using Scrum,
we're trying to do it to
create some sort of product
that can be sent out when we're done.
Right?
And that comes down to
three different areas.
We have a product
backlog, a sprint backlog,
and then a final shippable product.
All of these are known as artifacts.
Now the product backlog is
something that's going to list all
of the features, all of the
requirements, the enhancements,
and the fixes that we
propose for future releases.
This is done by using
epics and user stories,
and we'll talk about both of those more
as we go through the course.
Continually, over time,
we're going to keep
refining these backlog ideas
and we're going to add details
to them, estimates to them,
and order and prioritization to them
until they are quote ready.
When something is ready,
it's put into what's
called the ready status.
This means it's a product
that can be actually moved
into the development
team for them to work on
until it's done and ready to be shipped.
And so, once we get this
requirement firmed up,
that's when we can call it a ready status.
Now, once we get it ready,
it can move on into what's
called the sprint backlog.
And this is where we take a set of items
from the product backlog and say
they're going to be worked on
during this time box and this sprint.
The items here are the ones
that are going to create the
highest business value for us,
and they're pulled by the team to work on.
So the development team, actually,
is going to go into the backlog and go,
"What five or six things can we work on
"in this next two weeks that will give
"us the best value for the business?"
And the way they do
this is by going through
and figuring out which ones
are ready for them to work on
and which ones have the highest priority.
Now, in addition to pulling
these product backlog ones
in to work on, they also are required
to take at least one high
priority process improvement item
and include that into the sprint as well.
Because part of our sprints
is trying to make sure
that we're always improving
and getting better.
So we're going to create things to finish
into the finish product to
get a done shippable product,
but we also want to fix
our processes themself
to get us better, faster,
and more efficient.
And that brings us to the last piece.
So, once we've taken it
from the product backlog
to the sprint backlog, we now finish it
and we put it all together into
what's called an increment.
An increment is the culmination of all
of the product backlog items
that were completed during this sprint.
These items are all ready
and in an usable condition
to be shipped, released,
and considered done and off the table.
Once we do that, that is something
that we release to market
or release as a prototype
to get more feedback on
as we move forward through the process.
And so, that's the three
artifacts that we have.
That product backlog, the spring
backlog, and the increment.
Now, as we move forward,
we're going to start talking
about the five events
inside of Scrum.
This is our sprint, our sprint
planning, our daily scrum,
our sprint review, and
our sprint retrospective.
Now, what are these?
Well, the sprint is
what we're going to use,
which is a time-based
event of one month or less.
Generally, you'll see this
as two weeks or four weeks.
In a sprint, we're going to
take stuff from the backlog,
work on it through the development team,
and create a done usable,
releasable increment.
This will allow us
to maintain a consistent
duration throughout the project
because we're always going
to use the same time box,
either two weeks or four weeks
or whatever your company is going to use.
That's the idea here with a sprint.
Now, as we move forward, we're
going to spring planning.
How do we figure out what
we're going to work on,
on this sprint?
Well, we're going to do that
through sprint planning.
And this is a plan that
is created collaboratively
with the entire scrum team.
That includes a scrum master,
that's going to include the product owner
as well as the development team.
They're all going to sit down
in something like a workshop,
they'll do it,
and it's going to take less
than eight hours per month
for them to sit down at
this time-boxed event
and decide what are we going to
work on during this increment,
during this sprint.
What kind of work are we going to do,
and how will the work need to
be performed to be achieved?
And this is why we have
the product owner there
because the product owner is going to say,
"This is really important,
this gives us high value,"
and then you have the
development team there who says,
"That's great, but in this two weeks
"I can only get done x amount of work,
"so I can't do all five
high priority things.
"I'll take numbers one and two,
"and I'll work on the other
ones in the next sprint."
And you can start planning
out your sprints that way.
The next thing we're
going to talk about here
is our daily scrum.
And this is a time-boxed
event that takes 15 minutes
or less and it only occurs
with the development team.
The development team comes in the morning,
they do this daily stand-up,
and this meeting is going
to be done to talk about
what did we do in the last 24 hours,
and what are we going to work on today?
This will help us to
identify any issues, risks,
or challenges, and help us
finish our increment on time,
on budget.
That's the idea here.
So, this daily scrum is
really this leveling meeting
that allows everybody
on the development team
to come together and
figure out what did we do
and what are we going to do today.
Next, we have our sprint review.
And this occurs at the end of your sprint.
This is a chance for the team to stop
and inspect the increment
that they just worked on
and adapt the product
backlog as appropriate.
So, if you go through the increment
and you test all the functions out
and you're working on five
pieces of software code
and one of them wasn't working right,
well, you still have a time-boxed event
and so that one piece of code
might have to get put back
into the product backlog to
be worked in the next sprint.
This is an informal meeting
and it's not designed as a status meeting.
It's for people to go through
and inspect the products.
This meeting should be no longer
than four hours per month of sprint.
So, if you're doing a one month sprint,
it can be up to four hours.
If you're doing the two weeks sprint,
it should be no more than two hours.
The next one we have is
what we call our sprint retrospective.
And this is an opportunity
for the scrum team,
both the product owner as
well as the development team
and the scrum master to come in
and inspect itself on the processes
and create plans for
improvements for the next sprint.
So, we might go back
and look at this and go,
"You know what, when we
were working on this piece
"of the sprint, it was
taking us three times longer
"than we thought it was going to be
"because we were missing this
type of person on the team.
"So, let's go ahead and get that person
"in the next sprint so
that it can go faster."
This occurs after each sprint review
and before you start going into
your sprint planning for your next stage.
At most, this should be a
three hour meeting per month.
Because, again, our goal
here is not to have people
in hour-long meetings over and over again,
we want to get it done once
so we can get back to work
and create more product.
So, as we went through
these five Scrum events,
the key here that I
want you to remember is
that these events are prescribed
to create regularity
throughout the process.
Each and every event
has a maximum duration.
You saw that I said
this one is three hours,
or that one is four hours.
The reason is we don't want
to kill people with meetings,
we want people to be productive.
This sprint is at the
heart of this concept.
We have that fixed two
week or four week sprint
and everything else is based
on the beginning of the sprint,
such as sprint planning,
or the end of the sprint,
such as the sprint review
and the sprint retrospective.
This helps force transparency
throughout the process
and gives us opportunities
to inspect what we built
and adapt our processes so
that we can become better
with time as we keep moving
forward throughout this process.
So, how do we put all of this together?
Well, in Scrum, it's
actually fairly simple.
You'll see here on the screen,
we have our product owner.
They're going to go through
and create all of the epics
and user stories, what we
might know as requirements
in a standard process,
and put them into the product backlog.
In this product backlog,
we will have it all
sitting there, ready to go.
These are all of the pieces
they need for the versions
of the products that they
want to be developed.
These are all the different features
that a customer might need.
The development team and the
scrum master will then work
at the sprint planning
meeting with the product owner
to pull out what is going to
come from that product backlog
and be put into this sprint,
which will last up to 30 days.
This becomes known as our sprint backlog.
From here, the development
team starts working.
And they have up to 30 days,
whether it's a two week sprint
or a four week sprint, to go through
and create all the product
that's going to be created here.
This will be known as the increment.
Each day during this
cycle, you're going to see
that the development team goes out
and has their daily scrum meeting.
Remember, this is no more
than 15 minutes a day.
During this meeting, they're going to say,
"Yesterday, I built this,
today I'm going to build that.
"And here with the issues I had,
"here's the risks as I see them."
The scrum master is there making sure
that process goes smoothly.
And we keep working through
that for the entire sprint.
At the end of the sprint,
we're going to go into our sprint review,
where we're going to look
at all of the products
that were created that are
now known as the increment.
We look through all of those products.
We verify their quality.
We make sure that
they're good for release.
And they are now marked as done,
and they get pushed
out into the increment,
out to the product owner,
to their final customer.
Right after we finish that sprint review,
we're going to do a sprint retrospective.
And that sprint retrospective
is very much focused
on the processes that were involved.
Where the sprint review was focused
on the quality of the increment,
the sprint retrospective is
focused on how the sprint went,
how was the quality of the stand-ups,
how was the quality of the daily meetings,
how was the quality of how
well the team worked together.
What things were they missing,
what things did they need more of.
That is what we're focused on
with that sprint retrospective.
And remember, this
meeting should be no more
than a couple of hours once per sprint.
So that's how we put it all together,
and that's how we move forward with Scrum.