- So as we combine PRINCE2 with Agile
to come up with PRINCE2 Agile frameworks,
we have to start thinking about
what does this really come down to.
And if you pull up the Agile guide
inside your PRINCE2 Agile book,
it's going to give you
eight guidance points,
and we're going to cover those here.
The first one is that
PRINCE2 is already enabled
for use with Agile.
And we know this is true
because we can see things
like tailoring to suit
the project environment
back with our principles.
We also see things like organization
and define rules and responsibility,
which does take place
within an Agile team.
We see things like
learning from experience
which is really important
in the Agile iterative way of working.
The second guidance point
we have is that PRINCE2
is suitable for any style of project
and it's not a traditional
project management approach.
Now what they mean by this is that
in some traditional project
management approaches,
they are very strict in the
way things have to be done.
They focus on how things are
done in project management
but PRINCE2, on the other hand,
focuses on what needs to be
done with project management.
So what PRINCE2 says,
you have to have a way
to gather requirements, they
don't tell you what form
that has to take.
And so this works really
well in an Agile environment
because we can replace those
requirements with things like
epics and user stories
which then are naturally
an Agile way of working.
The third guidance point we have is that
PRINCE2 Agile is ready
for use with any project,
not just IT projects,
and this is important
because if you look at some
of the other frameworks,
such as Kanban, it's very
focused on manufacturing.
But if you look on Scrum or
you look at Lean Startup,
those are very focused on IT projects
as well as numerous other
Agile frameworks out there.
Because IT is one of the heavy adopters
of the Agile framework.
But we don't have to use this just for IT,
we can use this with any project.
Our fourth guidance point
is that IT only frameworks
and techniques are not our
focus inside of PRINCE2 Agile.
Instead, we're looking
at how we can use this
across all projects, like we just said,
in guidance point number three.
Let's move on to the fifth guidance point.
There is much more to
Agile than just Scrum.
In fact they like to say
that Agile is not Scrum.
Whilst Scrum is an Agile framework,
Agile itself does not equate to Scrum,
even though, in most people's minds,
they think of Scrum first
when you start talking about Agile.
As we mentioned before,
there's 10 or 12 different frameworks
that were mentioned in the textbook.
And we covered three of them in depth.
There is more to Agile than just Scrum.
When we go into guidance point number six,
we're going to talk about two
of our most commonly used frameworks,
which are Scrum and Kanban.
Both of those are very common and used
in a approach for Agile,
but they are not suitable
by themself for managing a
product across its life cycle.
And that's why we take the
techniques from Scrum and Kanban
and we put them into our
PRINCE2 Agile projects
because those techniques are great
but they don't give you the ability
to fully control it across its life cycle.
Now, number seven, is that
Agile is a family of behaviors,
concepts, frameworks and techniques.
And we talked about this
a lot in the last lesson.
We have these behaviors
which are our core guiding
principles and values,
we have the concepts, which
are the ways of working,
we have the frameworks which
are setup to help us working
in an Agile environment, and
techniques like burn charts
and sprints and timeboxing
and things like that.
Our final guidance point is that
when you're using Agile on a project,
you have to question how
much Agile should be used.
Really it comes down to not whether or not
I should use Agile, it's
how much of this project
will be done in an Agile manner.
So, if I'm using an example
of building a house,
this is something that it's
much more of a traditional
project management scope.
But we can use Agile
even in doing something
like building a house.
We my leave it up to our
electricians tp figure out
how they're going to wire the house
specifically as the wires
go through the walls.
But we want to tell them
where we want the outlets to be placed.
And so we can start saying how
much control is given to them
and how much is retained by the customer,
and this is part of this
Agile way of working.
So, again, number eight, we want
to figure out how much Agile
should be used in a project.
Now, the real benefit
here, when we start talking
about PRINCE2 Agile is that using Agile
doesn't mean that we're removing
our control or our guidance.
The control and governance that we have,
is going to allow Agile to be
used in complex environments.
So, no matter how complex
the thing is, for example,
here on the screen you will
see an F-22 fighter jet.
This is a hugely complex
machine but it doesn't give up
its control and governance,
the pilot still has the ability
to control and make
corrections as it goes,
but the plane has the
ability to self-correct it
as it moves through the air.
And so, this is one of those things
where we have this give and take.
When we start dealing with Agile projects,
we really have to think about
what control is going to be
held up high and what
tolerances we're going to give
so that the team, who's
delivering the final product,
has the wiggle room and the manouvre space
to really be able to
work through the issues
they come across inside the project.
Because if you don't give
them enough tolerance
and enough ability for them
with the left and right bounds,
to solve the problems themselves,
then you're not working in an Agile way.
But, giving them those tolerances,
means you have maintained
your control and
governance over the project
and so we're not giving
it up when we work Agile,
we're just making sure
we have defined it well
and so we can empower our teams
to do the right things for us,
as we move through these projects.