- In PRINCE2, the seven
themes are these areas
of project management
that have to be addressed
continuously throughout the project.
As we look at these seven themes,
you're going to see that they are based
upon the seven principles we just covered.
And next we're going to take these themes
and apply them by using seven processes,
because PRINCE2 is all about sevens.
It's the seven principles,
the seven themes,
and the seven processes.
Now, what are those seven themes?
The seven themes are
business case, organization,
quality, plans, risk,
change, and progress.
Now, the first one we're
going to talk about
is the business case.
What is the business case?
Well, the business case is created
and maintained to create
this business justification
for the project,
and so it really is using that principle
of continued business justification.
This is going to ensure
that our project's outcomes are achieved
and the benefits we want
are actually realized.
As we go through and we decide
are we going to take
on this project or not,
the first thing we're going to do
is develop this business case
and decide is it worthwhile?
How much is it going to cost?
How much time is it going to take?
And what are the benefits
we're going to get out of it?
If there's a good balance there
like we talked about in
continued business justification,
then we can initiate the project.
The next thing we have is organization.
An organization is used to define
the project's organizational
structure and the roles.
This is going to use that principle
of defined roles and responsibility.
This is going to help us to
define our communication approach
and how we're going to engage
with different stakeholders,
up from the project board
down into the project manager
across over to our
users and our suppliers.
All of this is stuff that
we're going to have to develop
inside of our organization theme.
Next we have quality,
and quality is used to define the project
quality management approach.
This is what's going to
specify the prioritized
acceptance criteria for our
final project's product,
and by doing this we're going to say,
does this product meet the warranty
and use case that we're developing it for?
If it does,
then we've maintained good quality
and it's accepted by our end customer.
We're going to talk about
quality both inside the project
and into its final product state
as we go through this course.
Next we have plans,
and plans is really going
and taking that manage by stages approach
and going into it much,
much more in depth.
Plans are going to be used
to recommend different levels
of planning that's going to be done
to facilitate communication and control
from different perspectives
across the project organization.
These plans are going to
enable our business case
to be realized with a product at the end.
So this is going to take it from idea
all the way through
execution into delivery.
When we break this up into
managing it by stages,
we have an overall plan
called the project plan.
We then have a stage plan
for that particular stage,
and underneath that stage plan,
we may have several team plans
that are being used for
specific pieces of the project,
and all of these are going
to nestle in together
so that we can have a good,
cohesive way of managing this
from start all the way through to finish.
The next theme we have is the risk theme,
and risk theme is going
to be focused on defining
the risk management approach
and ensuring that the
project risks are identified,
assessed, and controlled.
And we do this through the
risk management process.
The risk management process goes through
and does identification,
assessment, planning, implementation,
and communicating those risks
up through the organization.
We'll talk more about that
as we go through the course.
The next thing we have is change.
Change is inevitable in a project,
whether it's a change in requirements,
a change in deliverables,
a change in personnel,
a change in the way you do business.
Change is always going to happen.
And the change theme
is focused on defining
the change control approach
and ensuring that issues
are captured, assessed,
and controlled during
all of these changes.
Because if we can have a
good control over the change,
this is going to allow us to
have a good quality product
at the output.
Now, in Agile,
we're going to modify change a little bit,
but you'll see that as we
go through this course.
Next we have progress,
and progress is about defining the way
that a project's progress is measured
and compared to its performance targets.
This can be done in
lots of different ways.
Some organizations do progress
based on how much money has
been spent towards the goal.
Others do it by how much
products have been created
or how much work output has been created.
We'll talk about different
ways inside this course
as we go through the Agile concepts.
But the whole idea is that
progress is going to enable us
to forecast the continuing
project viability
by figuring out how much
has been done so far
and how much is left to do.