- There are a lot of different
Agile Frameworks out there
on the market today.
Many of these frameworks
are going to combine
different techniques and tactics
and give us the ability
to do things in a faster,
more efficient way.
Some of these are more common than others,
and a lot of these are only focused on IT
because that's where a
lot the world of Agile
developed from.
They're all going to
focus on kind of three
main concepts though.
It's either the planning phase,
the collaborate and build phase,
or the deliver phase,
and we're going to talk about
that as we go through here
and talk about the Agile Frameworks.
Now, on the screen,
you're going to see 12
different Agile Frameworks.
We have Scrum, Kanban, Lean Startup,
Lean, XP, SAFe, DAD,
DSDM or AgilePM,
DevOps, FDD, Crystal, and ASD.
Now, the question I get from students is
do I have to know all of these frameworks,
and the answer is no.
If you see the name,
you should recognize that
these are Agile Frameworks,
but you don't need to know
the specifics of each one
with the exception of three of them.
Scrum, Kanban, and Lean Startup,
and we're going to talk
about each of those
in a separate lecture in
the next three lectures,
because they really do make
up a very important part
inside of the PRINCE2 Agile Framework.