The next process we have
is controlling a stage.
And this is focused very
heavily on our project manager.
We start looking at our stages.
Our stages are going to
be made up of timeboxes.
Whether those are releases or sprints
underneath those releases.
And this will create the features
that will enable the
benefits in the end product.
As we look at this controlling a stage
we have to remember in
an agile way of working
we want to be very team
based and collaborative.
So, we're going to require
the team to help us
when we're planning
things, estimating things,
and creating our work
packages in a flexible manner.
As we start looking at
this as a project manager,
we want to figure out
how are we going to do our
reporting and our communication?
How are we going to
identify issues and risks?
And one of the best things
inside the agile environment
is to keep it much more informal.
In traditional Prince2,
we would do this through
checkpoint reports
and highlight reports
and using risk registers
and things like that.
But, when we start tailoring it for Agile,
we're going to do things like stand-ups
using information radiators,
using burn charts or sprint demos.
We want to identify any
blocks or impediments to us
being able to cretae the finished product.
And this is one of the ways
we do our risk management,
is by doing this
identification within the team,
as opposed to doing it through
an electronic risk register.
Now, as we go through
our Agile process here,
we want to focus on how we're
going to get something delivered.
Back when we were doing regular Prince2,
we were looking at things like
time and cost as our main variables,
but here in Agile,
we're looking at things
like scope and quality.
And by changing scope
or quality we can decide
what's going to get delivered
on time and on budget.
Now, as I look through
this, what are some of the
things you might find
when you start looking at the controlling
a stage process inside of Agile?
The most common thing you're
going to see, is timeboxes.
And these timeboxes are used
so that we have a control
mechanism in place that's based on time.
You've got two weeks to
deliver X Y Z products.
This is going to be forming one release.
Now, we might iterate on that later
or increment on that later,
but were always going to
be using these high level timeboxes
that build up the stages.
Those big stages can then
be broken down into releases
and those releases can be
broken down into sprints.
The other thing you're going
to see is that sometimes
there's more than one team working.
You may have a single
team working on a project
or you may have three or four
teams working on a project.
If you have multiple teams
working on a project,
you have to start focusing
on what's known as the scrum of scrums.
Where we start with this project manager
working with each of those team managers
to make sure their scrum
processes are working properly.
So, you have this one overall scrum master
looking out over these
four smaller organizations.
Now, some of the things you might also see
as you're trying to figure out
what to do inside controlling a stage
is you always want to
plan around your features.
Your time is just fixed
constant inside of this
and so you have to start figuring out
how many features can you
build inside your fixed sprint?
To do this, you should be
creating flexible work packages.
This will allow your
management by exception
to work much easier, it
allows the teams to be
much more self organized,
it enables communication
to happen amongst the team and
amongst the project manager.
Its the equivalent of having
a release and multiple sprints
all being put into one stage.
But, if you're going to
create your work packages,
you want to make sure those work packages,
which generally take the
form of a product backlog,
are going to be easily
accessed by the teams,
so they can figure out
what they can get done
in a single sprint.
If you're ever going to
be the project manager
in an agile environment, you really do
have to remember that
scope and quality criteria
are going to be your foundation.
Because this is where you're going to
be able to de scope things
to get a higher level of
quality or reduce your quality
to get a higher level of scope.
And this is something you're
going to have to help the team
decide on.
Is, what are we going to get done
inside this sprint, based on our progress,
our velocity and other issues like that.
And your job is to always monitor risks.
So you want to look at the risk involved
with this Agile process and help them
come to the right solution
of what the scope should be
and what the quality should
be to make sure we're doing
everything we need to
on time and on budget.
Again, this is a very
collaborative environment.
We want to make sure
we're all working together
and the team is being able to
pull the features out to work on.
We're going to show this
in a very visual way
inside our information radiators.
Doing our standup meetings
and going through our demos.
We always want to do it based
on facts and not feelings.
We want to think about how much was done
and look at that velocity,
so we can figure out
what can be done in the next sprint.
And we always want to inspect
what's coming out of these and adapt.
If is start inspecting a
product and I realize its not
up to the quality level,
I need to feed that
back done to the team
and say, hey, you need to
increase the quality on this.
And they may come back and
say, if I increase the quality
on that I'm going to have to
de scope this other feature
we plan on doing
cause they only have a
fixed amount of resources,
a fixed amount of time, and
a fixed amount of money.
And that's okay, because
we want to make sure
we're getting a good quality
product out the other end
so that our customers can use it.
Now, when we talk about work packages,
you have to remember that work packages
are a vital interface
inside controlling a stage.
This is the main way
that the project manager
talks to the team manager
and lets them know what's expected.
This is where we start binging
Prince2 and Agile together.
Because, in Prince2 we
use a lot of work packages
to dictate what the part
teams are going to work on.
But the big difference here in Agile,
is that this work package
is going to be collaboratively defined.
The team might help with it,
the team manager will
certainly help with it,
and the project manager will help with it.
This will create a safe
boundary of control.
Heres what is expected,
heres your left and right
limits stay within them.
This give you space to empower
your teams to self organize
enable their rich communication
and work on the products
they need to during the sprint.
When you start making a work package,
it can be just for one sprint,
one release, or multiple
sprints and releases.
Generally though, I try
to keep the work packages
down to just one sprint.
I find that works a lot better
and it works a lot more efficiently
as we can work through those processes,
because sometimes at the end of the sprint
we'll have new people come on
the team and old people leave.
And that's okay, you can change
over at the end of a sprint.
You just don't want to change
over in the middle of a sprint.
And so as you're doing
that its helpful to have
a formal work package that's
done for each and every sprint.
Now, how is the project manager
in controlling the stage
going to report up to the project board?
In traditional Prince2, we
use formal highlight report.
Now when we go to Agile, we might not need
to have something nearly as formal.
Instead, it might be an
email, or it might be
bringing the project board
down to the team radiator
and start going through the
information on the radiator.
Either way is okay, it
just depends on what
you want to do for your project,
the size, the complexity,
and the scope of it.
Your highlight report
should have information
on releases and sprints and
the progress being made,
as well as the benefits that
are going to be realized.
And this can be in the form
of a report, a burn chart,
an information radiator, or
something else of that nature.
Again, in Agile, we can
be a lot less formal
with some of these things as long as
the same information is being conveyed.
And also, we want to look at this,
is this going to be a push method,
where the project manager's
going to send the
information up to the board,
or is it going to be a pull
method, where the project board
is going to grab the information
from some repository,
like the information radiator.
Again this can all be tailored
inside of Prince2 Agile
depending on the needs
of what your project has.
The last management product
I want to talk about
is the checkpoint report.
Here in the controlling a stage process,
normally the checkpoint
report is a formal report
that is created by a team
manager and passed up to the
project manager.
The project manager then
takes information from that
includes it in his highlight
report and sends it up
to the project board.
Just like we talked about
with the highlight report,
we can tailor this into
being something less formal.
It can take the form of a burn chart,
an information radiator,
or even a daily stand-up.
Now, the one thing I
want to caution you is,
if you use it as a daily stand-up
to replace the checkpoint report,
make sure you're not
turning your daily stand-up
into a reporting to mechanism.
So what I mean by this is you
can invite the project manager
to sit in to your stand-up report.
And the reason you want to do
that is so they can get the
information they need.
As the team is talking
and discussing the issues
and the risks and what their working on
the project manager is getting
the information they need.
But, we don't want to
turn this into a meeting
where the team manager
is giving information
directly to the project manager
and ignoring the collaboration
aspect of a daily stand-up.
If it turns into a reporting to mechanism,
this is going to go
from being collaborative
to being very managerial
and we don't want that.
Instead, we can use the daily stand-up
as a replacement for our checkpoint report
if the project manager will be there
in an observation capacity
and not in a leadership
or management capacity.