- What is Scrum?
Well, Scrum is an Agile
Framework that's used
for developing and
sustaining complex products.
Scrum is a collection of
different roles, events,
artifacts, and rules for us
to be able to make products
faster and more efficiently.
It was first created back in 1995
by Schwaber and Sutherland,
and it was a method that's
used to assess the efficiency
of your current practices in
order for you to improve them
so you can get things done
better, cheaper, faster,
and with less risk,
and that is what we're
going to heavily base
our PRINCE2 Agile on
is the Scrum Framework.
Now, Scrum Theory was
founded in empirical process
control theory.
They wanted to see what was being done
and make their decisions
based on evidence.
There are three core
areas of Scrum Theory;
transparency, inspection, and adaptation.
Transparency is focused
on showing that there are
significant aspects of the
process that must be visible
to all of those who are
responsible for the outcome,
so the old ways of some
manager in an ivory tower
having all of the information,
and those of us down at lower levels,
not knowing the bigger picture,
that is gone inside of Scrum.
Scrum thinks that everyone
from the bottom to the top
should have transparency
into the significant aspects
of the process,
because it allows us to
make better decisions
and work better as a team.
The second core area is inspection,
and this is focused on
users frequently inspecting
the artifacts and the progress
towards your sprint goal,
because again, focusing on transparency,
if we all know where we are,
and we check the progress as we're going,
we'll all be able to get there better,
faster, and cheaper.
And the third is adaptation.
Adaptation is where we focus
on taking our processes
and our materials and
adjusting them as needed.
Nothing is sacred here,
everything can be modified.
Just like we talked about
back in PRINCE2 principles,
where we say we want to
tailor to the environment
of tailor to the project,
adaptation really does believe that,
and that is one of the heavy concepts
here inside of Scrum Theory.
Now, when we look at our Scrum team,
we have to realize that
this team of people
that are going to work on the project,
they should be self-organizing,
cross-functional, flexible,
creative, and productive.
By self-organizing,
the team doesn't have to have
this hard amount of pressure
from management to get things done.
They're going to come
together and form together
to get the product done
that needs to be done.
They're cross-functional,
meaning that everything you
need to build the final product
should exist already within the team.
So if I'm making a website,
that means I need somebody
who can write copy
for the website,
I need somebody who can build
graphics for the website,
and I need somebody who
can code for the website.
If I have those three people in my team,
and we all self-organize together,
we're now cross-functional
because we each have
different areas of expertise.
That allows us to be more
flexible, more creative,
and more productive as we move forward,
and that's the whole benefit of Scrum
is putting the right
people on the right teams
so that you can get the
right product at the end.
As we start looking at the Scrum team,
there are different roles
that we're going to have
that have to be assumed.
We have the role of product owner,
development team, and Scrum master.
Now, the Scrum team is actually bigger
than just the development team,
so in the example of the website,
I said I need a graphic
designer and a coder
and a copy editor,
well that's the development team.
They are going to consist
of the professionals
who do the work and deliver
a reasonable increment
of done for each sprint.
They're going to give us some
product that can be released.
But, outside of the development team,
we have some other roles as well.
We have a product owner.
They're the ones who are
responsible for maximizing
the value of the product
resulting from the work
that the development team is building.
They're going to be the ones
who manage the product backlog
and create a lot of the requirements,
and so, if you want to
take this product owner,
you could think about
them as the customer,
they're the ones who are asking
for something to be built,
and then we have this third
thing called a Scrum master,
and the Scrum master is a
person who's responsible
for the process of Scrum and making sure
that everyone kind of buys into the idea
that we're going to work as a team,
that we're going to
work cross-functionally,
and that we're going to work
in this highly adaptable
and fast changing environment.