- Welcome to this course on
the Prince2 Agile Foundation.
In this course, we're
going to cover everything
you need to know to study
for, to take, and to pass
your Prince2 Agile foundation's exam.
In this course we're going
to provide you an excellent
review of all of the material
covered in the Prince2
Agile guidebook.
Now this isn't an in depth guide.
We're not going to go through
and cover every single
piece of information
that's in that 400 pages.
But instead, we're going to go
over the most frequently asked
concepts and help you
focus your study efforts
so you can pass on the first attempt.
Now my name is Jason
Dion and I am a professor
and instructor of cyber security
and information technology.
I've been working in those
realms as a professional
for over 20 years, and during that time,
I've worked on hundreds
of different projects,
ranging from just a couple of dollars,
and the way up into the
millions of dollars.
In my experience, we've
used both Waterfall
and Agile technologies and
techniques as we've gone
through these projects.
And as we go through this
course, I'm going to share
a lot of that experience
with you, so you can see
how we can apply this in
a real world environment.
Now before we go any
further, I want to give you
a couple of key pieces of information.
First, there are closed
captions are available
for this course.
Just hit the CC button at the
bottom of the video player
and you'll be able to see
all the words going along
with what I'm speaking.
Now also, when it comes to
speaking, sometimes people say
I talk too fast.
Others say I talk too slow.
Either way, you get to
control the playback speed.
If I happen to be talking too
fast, you can slow me down
by reducing me to .75.
If I'm talking too slow,
you can speed me up
by putting me at 1.5x.
Now either way, you can
listen to me at normal speed,
faster or slower, to the
way that it works best
for you to learn.
Now all the information
I'm going to give you
during this course, I do
have a handout available
as a downloadable resource.
So please download that
and you can use that
for all fun studying as well.
And we also have a Facebook
group that is set up
to help you as you're studying.
If you have any questions, or
you get stuck on something,
just go to
Facebook.com/groups/DionTraining,
and join the group and
we'll be happy to help you
and answer any questions you may have.
Now the last thing I want you to know,
is that when you take this
course, you are in good hands.
We're going to help you get
certified in the best way possible.
Dion Training Solutions,
which is my company,
is an authorized training organization
for the Prince2 Agile Foundation
and Agile Practitioner
certifications.
So when you take a course
from us, you are taking it
from somebody who is authorized, trained,
and certified by Axelos,
the owners of the exam.
Also, because you've taken it from us,
you are eligible for a
discount on your exam voucher.
By going to our website
at DionTraining.com.
So with all that said, let's
move into our first lecture
and start learning about the exam.