- In PRINCE2 we have six
performance variables
that we utilize when we're
defining our projects.
These are time, cost, risk,
scope, quality, and benefits.
And each of these is going to have
a tolerance assigned to them.
When we talk about
tolerance, this is something
that is an allowable variation around
those target areas.
So for example, with cost, if I said,
"I want to do this project for $100,000
"with a 10% tolerance," that means
that anything between $90,000-$110,000,
would be considered acceptable.
But if I was going to be
below that or above that,
that would become a
variation and we would have
to raise an exception
up because our tolerance
would be exceeded either
too low or too high.
Now as we start looking at this,
inside of a traditional project
with Waterfall development.
The two biggest variables that we're
going to adjust, are time and cost.
If I'm building a house for example,
and I started going over budget,
I may allow more time
where that means I can
get a cheaper price on delivery.
And that might bring down the cost.
And so I want to bring down the cost,
but that may increase my time.
I'm not going to change out the benefits,
which is a three bedroom, two bath house.
I'm not going to change the quality,
which is the level that we've accepted.
And this is the way we do
things in a Waterfall method.
We really do adjust the time
and the cost heavily.
And we really try to fix
those other four areas.
Now when we go to Agile,
it's actually flipped around.
Instead, time and cost
become fixed for us,
and our biggest variables
are scope and quality.
And the reason why is
we can start descoping
things and delivering
less, so that we can make
it on time and on
budget, because in Agile,
those are the two most
important variables.
And so as we look forward,
we're going to talk
about each of these six areas and what you
have to think about as
we move through them.
The first one is time.
In an Agile area, time is fixed.
Agile uses time-boxing with set durations.
So we have zero tolerance
for any extra time
on any level of the project.
You can't get more as a
team, you can't get more
in a stage, and you can't
get more as a project.
Time is fixed.
When I say that we're doing a sprint
of four weeks, at the end of four weeks,
you have to deliver something.
We're not going to have
any variation here.
The next one we're going
to look at is cost.
And cost in Agile is also fixed.
There is zero tolerance for extra cost
on all levels of our plan.
Agile uses this fixed
cost and any tolerance
becomes an exception
that has to be raised up
to our project board.
And so unlike Waterfall,
where time and cost
can be swapped out and variable,
they can't inside Agile.
As we move down the hexagon, we look
at quality at the bottom.
This is one that can be fixed and flexed.
Quality, when we fix it and flex it,
means that we're going to
have acceptance criteria
that we have to meet.
These are for our essential items.
This acceptance in quality criteria
is going to be prioritized.
The essential things are going to
have zero tolerance.
Anything that goes
outside of that tolerance,
is going to be an exception report.
But there's a lot of
things that we consider
desirable and not essential.
And these are things where tolerance
can be utilized.
And so we call this a
fix and flex mentality.
We fix the essential items, but we flex
on the desirable items.
What would this look like?
Well, maybe we have the example
of building a car.
And we're going to make a four-seat sedan,
it's an electric car that can go 0-60
in 2.0 seconds.
Well the essential item
here, is that it has
four seats to hold four passengers.
We're going to have
zero tolerance on that.
You can't add a fifth seat, you can't take
away a seat and give me three seats.
This is an essential quality item.
Now, when I look at the desirable items,
that might be the 2.0 seconds.
Maybe it'll be OK if we were somewhere
between 1.9 and 2.1 seconds.
And so we'll have some tolerance there
that can be utilized.
This is the idea of fix and flex.
Each of those requirements
are going to be tied
to whether it's prioritized
as an essential item,
or a desirable item,
and we'll fix and flex accordingly.
We're going to do the same thing when we
start looking at scope.
We're going to prioritize
scope because not all
items are equally important and have
to be delivered.
There's some items that
we're going to delete out
and we're going to scope down on.
But again, if it's an essential item,
there's zero tolerance and if it's
a desirable but not essential item,
that's where we can have some flexibility
within the tolerances associated
with our given project.
Now in the middle of our hexagon,
we have two other areas.
We have the risk area
and the benefits area.
In the risk area, this is what we
call a fix or flex.
That means depending on our project,
and depending on the
needs of the project board
and the project manager, we'll determine
whether or not there's
going to be a zero tolerance
or some tolerance when
we set up our tolerances
for the project.
It could go either way.
It all depends on the risk appetite
of the organization, and
how the project board
wants to do it.
The same thing happens when we talk
about our benefits.
These can be fixed or flexed.
There may be zero
tolerance up to a minimum
level of viability for a project,
as defined in our business case.
But then anything above minimum,
can then have a flexibility.
What might this look like?
Well let's say that we were going to build
a software application
that's going to allow you
to have a calendar app on your phone.
The minimum requirement that we have,
is that we'll display the days of the week
and the year and the time and allow you
to put in appointments.
But some of the extra bells and whistles
that we wanted to add, was the ability
to email these off to somebody else,
to be able to color code them,
and do some other functions.
If we get up to the
minimum level of being able
to have an app that displays the time
and the date and allows me to block out
that time on my calendar,
that was the minimum viability.
Zero tolerance to that point.
But if I couldn't get
the color coding added in
within our time-box,
that might be something
that I flex on, and
allow me to move that on
to another time scope later on,
or another iteration.
Now, when we start doing all of this,
it all comes down to balance.
Some things we're going
to give up more tolerance
or less tolerance to get the product
that we want.
There's always going
to be a balance between
what the customer gets and
what the customer wants.
And you have to realize,
the customer's going to ask
for everything but they
don't need everything,
at least not right away.
And so we are going to
use these tolerances
and these performance
variables to really figure
out what we're going
to deliver in the first
iteration of the project
inside our time-box,
and then we'll put in other things
into the second, third, and fourth.
And to do this, we have
to have a good, holistic
view of what the end desirable product is.
And if we can do that, we
can use these variables
to our advantage to be be able to give us
an appropriate balance and get our product
out on time, on budget,
with an appropriate
amount of resources used.