- The next theme we're
going to discuss is quality.
Now, quality is focused on protecting
the 'fit for purpose' of the products.
Will they be able to do
what they're intended to do
once they're delivered?
We do this by prioritizing
acceptance criteria
and quality criteria, because
as we've talked about before,
the customer doesn't get
everything they want,
but they will get everything they need,
and by doing that prioritization,
that's going to help
us protect the quality.
We also do this by defining
quality tolerances.
What is within bounds and
what is outside of the bounds?
And if we can keep everything in
within a certain quality band,
then we're going to get
the quality we desire.
Also, we want to define the difference
between functional and
non-functional requirements.
What is something that is required
as part of this minimum viable product,
or something that is required
to get the benefit we need
versus something that's a nice-to-have?
That's the difference between
function and non-functional.
As we look at the Agile concepts,
we have to help clarify quality criteria.
There are two main Agile
concepts that refer to this,
the concepts of ready and done.
Ready means that our product
is ready to be worked on.
We've appropriately
defined the requirement,
we understand what the
quality requirements are
and what the tolerances are,
and now we can start building
towards that ready state.
Now, once we build and we
meet those requirements,
we place it into the done category,
and when it's done, it means it's ready
for delivery to the customer,
because we've met the quality
requirements we've been given.
Another area that we have to consider
when tailoring our quality theme
is quality checks themself.
How often are we going to do them?
Are we going to do them every
hour, every day, every week?
Every month, or just at
delivery of the product?
Well, in a traditional
PRINCE2 environment,
we tend to do it closer
to the end of a stage,
but in Agile, we want to
do it more frequently.
The problem, though, is if
we do it too frequently,
we can actually impact
our product's schedule
and our runtimes, and so this
can become an issue as well,
and so we have to balance that
as we're developing our quality criteria
and figuring out how often we're
going to do quality checks.
Now, one of the biggest differences
between PRINCE2 and PRINCE2 Agile
is the idea of quality
in relation to scope.
When we looked at those variables
back in our six performance factors,
under PRINCE2, quality
and scope were fixed.
You couldn't change the scope,
and you couldn't change the quality,
but in Agile, those are both flexible.
We can change scope and
we can change quality.
Now, we have to remember
that under PRINCE2 Agile,
a reduction in scope is not
seen as a reduction in quality.
Instead, scope is defined
by the products themself
where quality is defined
by the quality criteria.
Customer quality expectations
and acceptance criteria
have to be set properly
early in the project,
and that's the level that we have to meet.
Now, we sometimes will
deliver above that level,
but we're not allowed to
deliver below that level.
Instead, we will descope
so we can maintain
the level of quality of what is delivered.
What does this really
mean in the real world?
Well, let's say I'm going to
deliver a software application
to you, and you've requested
100 different things
go into this application,
and we've defined
that 60 of those are
required, have-to-have things.
Would it be better for me
to give you those 60 things perfect,
or give you 80 things
that don't work very well?
Obviously, you'd rather have
the 60 things working perfectly
and those other 40 things
that I couldn't get to,
we'll get to those in the next spin,
or the next cycle, or the next sprint.
That's the way we want to do this.
We will descope the
amount we're going to do
to make sure the must-haves
are done properly
and within our quality criteria.
Now as we look at Agile, we want to think
about the fact that
there's not going to be
a lot of emphasis placed
on quality planning
or quality management at
the start of a project.
And this is very different than PRINCE2
because in PRINCE2,
we're all about ensuring
that our quality is going to be fixed
and set up properly from the beginning.
Instead in Agile, quality
is more of a moving target,
and it's something that can be negotiated
with your customers.
There are lots of different techniques
that are going to be
there to help you define
what 'done' is and what
the acceptance criteria is
based on working with your customer.
We're always going to have
this evolving definition
of 'done' because we don't set
'done' back in the first step
or in sprint zero.
Instead, 'done' continually
gets evolved in change
in negotiations with your customer.
Again, this kind of goes
back to the whole idea
of if I have a project that
'done' would be 100 pieces
of function in a software and
I'm only going to deliver 60,
if your customers agree to that,
then that is what 'done' will be.
Another Agile concept
that's really important
for us in quality is
the idea of 'Test first'
or 'Test as you go'.
In traditional PRINCE2 and
Waterfall methodologies,
we wait until the end and
the product has been built,
and then we test it before we
release it to our customer.
But in Agile, the
developers should constantly
be testing it as they go.
They should be prototyping,
building things,
seeing if they work, and if they do,
move onto the next step.
Instead of building everything
that takes 500 steps to do
and then find out at that 500th step
something back in step three was broken,
and now you've got to
rework all of that stuff.
That's the idea here in Agile.
We want to test frequently and often
so we can catch errors early
and improve our quality.
So as we try to summarize
all of this guidance
around quality inside of
Agile, I want you to remember
that product descriptions are flexible.
These user stories are
a great example of this.
It says, as a user, I want to do this
so that I can get this.
And by doing that, it gives
us a lot of wiggle room
in what we're actually going to deliver.
For example, if you said, "As a student,
"I want an alarm clock that
wakes me up every day."
That gives me a lot of flexibility
in how I deliver that alarm clock to you.
Is it a traditional
mechanical alarm clock?
Is it going to be a digital alarm clock?
Is it an app on your phone?
There's lots of ways for me
to meet that same requirement
and keep the quality, giving
you the function you want.
Project product descriptions are always
going to be used to define an outcome,
not to define the way that
we're going to get there.
That's a big difference between
PRINCE2 and PRINCE2 Agile,
because in PRINCE2, we're going to define
what that thing looks like.
If I give you a product
description for an alarm clock
under normal PRINCE2, we would be looking
at something that says, "I
want a mechanical alarm clock
"that's precise to X amount of seconds
"and is going to work X amount
of times before it breaks."
Instead in PRINCE2 Agile, I am thinking
about what the function
is, what is the outcome,
what is the benefit the
customer wants to get.
Quality management and quality planning
is always going to include
a couple of things though.
Whether we're dealing
with PRINCE2 or Agile,
we want to make sure we know the tools
and approaches that are going to be used.
We want to know what the
role of the customer is.
And what are those essential ingredients
that we have to have to
give product delivery
that's acceptable to them?
We also want to know how
we're going to assess
and cost out the resources
that are going into
this quality management and
quality planning standards.
And finally, we have to know what
our quality control considerations are.
By knowing all of those
things, we can develop
a good quality management plan.
Now again, in PRINCE2, we would do this
back in our initiating a product stage
and put it into our product
initiation documentation.
Under PRINCE2 Agile,
we're still going to do it
at that point, but it will
not be nearly as detailed
because we're a lot more flexible
in what quality is going to look like.
So, we've talked a lot about quality,
but the real question is,
how do you test for quality?
Well, Agile gives you a lot
of different ways to test.
And remember, Agile
comes from the software
development world primarily,
so you have to be careful
when transferring these concepts
from software development
into other domains
to make sure they still are accurate
and work well for you.
There's lots of different ways of testing.
We have things like
test-driven development,
behavior-driven development,
the definition of 'done' and 'ready',
refactoring, and technical debt.
When I talk about test-driven development,
what I'm talking about is a concept
of writing up tests and quality checks
before I build the product.
So if I'm going to build an app
that's going to be an alarm clock,
I would write up what
the end function would be
and give that to my tester.
Then we'd build the product,
and then we can test it
against that quality checks.
Now if I'm looking at something that is
behavior-based development,
this is going to be
more collaborative than a
test-driven development.
Quality checks are written using languages
that the customer understands as opposed
to something that programmers understand.
What does the customer
really want to achieve?
Going back to my alarm clock example,
the customer wants to be woken
up every day at a set time.
If the alarm clock does
that, it meets the standard.
Now, under test-driven development,
it may have to do that
within X amount of seconds
or within X amount of precision
or some other technical terms.
Behavior-driven is more
focused on the outcome
and the function, which really works well
inside an Agile environment.
Now the other thing we have to look at
is what is 'done'.
When is this product finished?
Well, 'done' is the set of criteria
that we have set to determine if a work
or a collection of work is
really finished and completed.
This is when something is
either 'done' or 'not done'.
Either it meets the quality criteria
and is ready for release or it doesn't.
That's the idea of 'done'.
When we look at 'ready',
it's is that user story
have enough information for us to be able
to start work on this project.
It's the set of criteria that we use
to determine if we're ready to start doing
the programming or ready to start building
or designing based on it.
So this when we take it
from our product backlog
if it's in the 'ready' bucket,
we can now pull it and
start working on it.
Now, refactoring is an Agile concept
that comes from the
software development world,
and you have to be careful
in how you apply this one.
When we look at this from
a software perspective,
when we look at refactoring,
it's when you think
about inputs going in some black box
and some outputs coming out.
All the code is inside that black box.
Now, with refactoring, we can change
what's in the black box
so that it doesn't change
what goes in and what comes out.
So if we can change the software
in a way that it doesn't
alter the external behavior
of the code yet it's going to
improve the internal structure,
that's what refactoring is.
Again, this is commonly used
in software development.
You can apply it to any product,
but it is kind of harder
to think about this
in a traditional sense.
Like if I'm building an office building,
and I start thinking about
refactoring the plumbing
and moving the pipes around, I guess
that would work too, right?
I care about water
coming into the building
and water going flushing down the toilet,
and I don't really care about the pipes
that get it from one place to the other.
You could refactor the way you design them
as long as it still has the same function.
I guess that would kind of work.
But again, it's kind of a lot easier
to think about this in terms of software.
And lastly, we have technical debt.
Technical debt refers to
the eventual consequences
of your poor system design.
A lot of times in Agile,
we put something together
very quickly just to make it work
because no one really cares
what the code looks like
when we're dealing with software.
They just care if I put X in
and I expect Y out, did I get Y.
This is going to refer when
we talk about technical debt
to work that should have
been completed earlier
before we moved onto the next step,
but for some reason, it hasn't been.
Maybe we put in some placeholder code.
Maybe we did it in a non-elegant way
that takes 10 more steps
than it needed to be.
If we don't address this
technical debt early on,
what ends up happening is
it kind of builds up on us,
and later on down the road,
we're going to have problems.
A great example of this is when people
are building some kind of web server
or software development
and they don't think
about how it's going to scale up.
For example, when I
first started teaching,
I was used to teaching in a classroom
where I taught 20 students at a time.
The way you teach 20 students at a time
is different than the way you teach
2,000 students at a time.
And so, we have to make sure
that we're doing things that scale.
And that's one of the ideas
here with technical debt.
If you try to take
something that you built
for a small case and then
use it in a large case,
things are going to break.
A great example of this would be
if we did personalized
test and assessments
of every student in this class.
There may be 1,000 or
2,000 or 20,000 students
taking this class right
now, and if I had to grade
a single one-page essay from each of you,
I could never do it as one person.
So instead, we use things
like multiple-choice tests
that can be self-graded by a computer.
That scales well.
And that's the whole
idea of technical debt
is making sure that you're thinking ahead
and fixing those problems
before they pile up on you
and become a big problem in the end.