- The next process we have to consider
is directing a project.
And how are we going to tailor
that to work with Agile?
- Well, the first thing
you have to remember
with directing a project is
that we are really going to
be focused on management by exception.
Because we want to empower our teams.
By giving them the empowerment,
we're going to let them start
helping us decide how much
is going to be delivered during
any one sprint or release,
how the information is going to flow,
and we're going to give value
to the things being delivered.
By managing by exception, we're
going to give them tolerances
that they can stay between,
and let them know how they
can flex quality and scope
to make sure they're meeting
our time and cost objectives.
Now, when we start looking
at how we're going to do progress
reporting up to the board,
instead of doing it in
traditional highlight report,
we're going to use more of a pull method.
And they're going to
be able to have access
to our information radiators.
This will allow us to have
less reporting requirements,
while still being able to work faster,
and they're still going to get
the communication they need.
Another thing is anytime
you're doing demos
or you're doing releases,
the project board should
be invited to attend those key demos.
That gives them insight into
the details of the project
while still letting them stay
out of the day-to-day work.
One of the biggest key
things we have to focus on
is collaboration within agile.
And that's no more true than
inside directing a project.
With this collaborative environment,
we have to make sure there is trust.
The project board has to
trust the delivery team.
And they have to eliminate
a culture of blame,
because if there's
something that goes wrong
and the project board goes and says,
oh, it's the delivery team's fault.
That's going to not empower that team
to make decisions in the future.
And that's going to make
them second-guess themself
and always be going back to
the project board for answers.
Which then eliminates the agile
that we're trying to achieve.
So, one of the big
questions you may have is,
who is going to provide the
direction inside the directing
of project process?
Well, it depends on your environment.
If you're in a very mature environment,
you're going to use a project board,
very similar to the way PRINCE2 does.
If you're in a very basic environment,
you just started using
this PRINCE2 agile stuff,
you may just have the product owner,
the one who's going to end up
owning this thing at the end,
give that direction.
And that's a much more
agile way of working.
Now if you're somewhere in
between that, between a basic
and a mature, you're going
to be using the sponsor
to give you that direction.
But again, our goal is to get
you into a mature environment
to get you to using a project board
that gives you overall
governance and control, similar
to PRINCE2, while still
allowing agile ways of working
to happen down at the delivery layer.
One of the biggest
things that the directing
of project process can
do to empower the team,
is give them good requirements.
If you give the team good requirements,
they can then do the work
that they need to do.
This allows self-direction to happen.
These requirements must be
well-defined and well-prioritized
to enable agile ways of working,
because if they're not
well-prioritized, then the team
is not going to know which things
they need to work on first.
And they're going to keep
coming back to the project board
and asking for guidance.
Many terms are going to
describe what a project does
and what it does well.
These are things like
requirements, project descriptions,
or user stories as they're known in agile.
Let's look a little bit more in-depth
into this world of requirements.
When we look at requirements
we want to make sure
we're defining them at the right level.
So if the project board
comes up with a requirement,
that would be a high-level requirement.
Then, it needs to be
broken down and decomposed
into those intermediate objectives.
And that's where the project
manager's going to come in.
They're going to help the
project board take this big idea
and break it down into smaller pieces.
Now, those smaller pieces
still aren't small enough
to be worked on yet.
They're not ready.
So we're going to work
with the team managers
and the delivery team to
break those down even further
into detail-level requirements
that can then be worked against.
Now, this allows the project
team at the end of the day
to look at all of these
different smaller chunks
of requirements and trade out
and swap detailed requirements.
If you change something in one
of these detailed requirements,
it's not going to have a huge
effect on the overall product.
But, it does allow you to
work in a more agile method.
What do I mean by this?
The high-level requirement might
be, we need to build a car.
The intermediate-level
requirement might be,
we need to build a four-seat car.
The detailed requirement might
be, the seats must be able
to recline to 45 degrees,
they must be heated,
they must have this or
that or the other thing.
Now if I change out some
of those requirements,
does it effectively
change the big high-value
or high-level product, the car?
No.
It's still going to be a car,
it just may be a different color seat,
or may be a different fabric in the seat.
And those details can be
swapped in and out as needed
by the agile team delivering the work.
Now when we develop our requirements,
we use user stories inside of agile.
This works to give us the function
and the output we're expecting.
Usually they're in the form of,
as a blank, I want to blank,
so that I can blank, right?
So example of this
might be, as a consumer,
I want to be able to buy groceries online,
so that I don't have to leave the house.
That might be a description
of a grocery delivery service.
Now that's a really big description
and it doesn't give us
detailed requirements.
Instead, this might be an epic.
An epic is these big, broad user stories
that need to be decomposed
down to smaller pieces.
And so for that overall
concept that I gave,
a consumer who wants to be
able to buy groceries online,
so that they don't have
to leave the house,
there's a lot of things
we can break down in that.
We can break down to, how is
that going to be checked out?
How are we going to process payment?
How am I going to place the order?
Is it online or over the phone?
Am I going to use an app?
All those things have to be defined
and we'll break those down
into individual user stories.
Additional information might include
the acceptance criteria, the
amount of effort involved,
and the value for that particular thing.
So if I'm talking about, as a user,
I want to be able to
delete items from my cart,
so that I don't buy additional
products I don't want.
That is a clearer area
in a smaller, user story
to the larger, grocery delivery system.
This is going to be a starting point
and it is not a fully-defined requirement.
We're going to continue to
refine these until they're ready,
and once they're in the ready bucket,
then we can start working
and building towards those.
So, to drive this point home,
let's look at two more user stories.
The first one is one that
has very limited usefulness
because it's too generic.
As a store manager, I
want to manage a store,
so that the store is managed effectively.
This doesn't really help me much.
It doesn't tell me what
they really want to do.
And it takes a lot of skill
to write a good user story.
Let's go to rework this
at a more granular level.
Here is number 37.
It's a good user story, we're
going to use this as an example.
As a stock controller, I want
to know if my stock level
is very low, so that I don't
run out and I don't fail
to fulfill a customer's order.
You'll notice here that
it is very specific.
What do they want to achieve?
And what is the thing they need to know?
Now I can develop a program
that meets that need,
that manages the stock.
You'll also notice at the bottom,
we have the business value
and the effort involved.
The business value of eight,
says that it's 8 out of 10
on the business value scale.
This is something that's
going to help us decide
what priority it is when
we need to work on it.
Things that are higher
value should get worked on
before things that are lower value.
We also have effort here.
It's a 2 our of 10 on effort.
This tells me that it
is a lower effort item.
So it won't take me very long
to build this part of the code.
If this was a 9 or a 10,
that means it's going
to take a lot more time
and a lot more resources.
And so, by going through
these user stories
and defining them well, you
can see that this one is ready.
We can put it in the ready bucket
and the team can start working
towards it in the next sprint
to get it built, and then we get something
that the customer can use.
Now when I look at epics,
epics instead are going
to be a bigger user story
and these are your boulders,
these are your big requirements.
This is the overarching thing.
But they're not ready to be worked against
because they're not technical enough,
they're not functional enough.
And so we need to break down
these epics into smaller pieces
so that we can have a good user story
that we can build against.
And that's just the idea
of a requirement, right?
You take this big-level requirement,
you break it down into
a smaller requirement,
and then you break that
into a much more detailed
smaller requirement.
And when we get to that
lowest-level requirement,
that very detailed requirement,
that's what we can build against.
That's somebody building
something in a product line.
And that's what we're
trying to get to here
inside directing a project.
And so, for the exam
I want you to remember
that epics are these big,
high-level requirements.
And user stories are smaller,
more detailed requirements
underneath these epics.
Now, the last thing we have to talk
about inside directing a project,
is the idea of prioritization.
How are we going to
prioritize what requirements
and what user stories
should be worked on first?
There's two basic methods
that we use inside agile.
One is known as MoSCoW
and the other is ordering.
MoSCoW stands for Must have,
Should have, Could have,
and Won't have for now.
Let's look at a big requirement.
I have a requirement to have
a pen that my company can use.
So I can make information from my head
and write it down on the paper.
That is a big, overarching epic.
Now if I want to break that
down, what are the requirements
that I might have for that pen?
Well, do I need to have a pen cap?
Do I need to have ink?
Do I need to have a
barrel so you can hold it?
Do I have to have a logo on the pen?
These are all things we can think about.
Now as we go through the
prioritization as the project board
we're going to look at this
and go, okay, I need a pen.
That means it has to have
ink, that's a Must have.
I need to be able to refill that ink.
It Should have a barrel,
some way to hold that ink
inside of it.
Now it Won't have a logo
because we're not going to be
giving these out to customers.
Instead, we're going to
just use them in house.
And it Could have a top,
something to cover up the pen.
But if it doesn't, that's okay, too.
And so these are the ideas
here, is what Must it have,
what Should it have, what Could it have,
and what Won't it have.
All those Must haves are
your minimum viable product.
Your Should haves are better
than that, they're nice to have
but they're not necessary.
And then you have a layer even above that,
called your Could haves.
It Could have a top.
But, if we don't have a
top, I can still use the pen
and still write down stuff.
And then things that you just say,
you know what, we don't
need that right now,
we're not going to have a logo on it
'cause we don't need the
extra expense of printing it
if it's just going to be
used inside the office.
And that's the idea of how
you break these big epics
down into smaller stories,
and then decide which ones
you Must have, you Should
have, you Could have,
or you Won't have.
The second method of
prioritization is called ordering.
And in ordering, we're going to
just give a number to things.
So if I look at all of the requirements
and I have 10 different
requirements, I will number them
from 1 to 10.
And what will happen is
our workflow should be done
in the order from first to last.
Now, sometimes we're going to
pull things in different orders
though, based on the capacity of the team,
and working in our agile way.
So if you're working with
ordering, it is better to do this
when you have little
dependency between items.
If I go back to my car example,
I don't want to put the seats
in the car before I've built the chassis.
I don't want to paint
the exterior of the car,
until I've bolted everything on.
And so using it in an ordering
system sometimes doesn't work
as well as the Must have,
Should have, Can't have
and Won't have, because if you
can pull all the Must haves
and build those first,
that is going to be better
for your particular sprint
to make sure all those things
are done in the right
order, in the right time.
When you deal with ordering,
it just says this is my
priority from 1 to 10.
But again, the agile team can
decide that they're going to do
item 3 before item 1, if they want to.
And so that is just a priority system
when you talk about ordering, not in layer
of when you're going to do each thing
as you go through the project.