- Previously, we talked about
the seven principles of PRINCE2.
In this lesson, we're going
to talk about those again,
but talking specifically about
how we're going to implement
them inside an Agile framework.
The first is our continued
business justification.
And you may remember that we define this
as the project always
having a desirable, viable
and achievable outcome.
So we always want to make sure
that it's still relevant for us.
We did this by measuring our benefits
against the cost and the risk.
And if the benefits
outweighed the cost and risk,
we would move forward with the project.
Well, when we look at this in Agile terms,
there's two big concepts
we want to focus on.
The first is value.
We want to make sure that whatever
we're going to be building
is going to provide enough value
or benefits for us to continue forward.
So this one looks very similar to the way
we would do it inside a
normal PRINCE2 framework
as opposed to a PRINCE2 Agile framework.
But the second piece of this
is creating a Minimum
Viable Product or an MVP.
Now when we talk about a
Minimum Viable Product,
we're trying to create something
that we can get into the
hands of either our end users
or other users or a sample to see
if it's going to be worth
while creating the full thing.
So an example of this might be
if you're going to build
a new electric car,
you might not create the final prototype
with all of the bells and whistles,
but instead, you might build just a car
that has four seats and an electric motor
to make sure you can get
that part right first.
And if you can, that's now accepted
as a Minimum Viable
Product, we would then go in
and put all the additional
things, like the air conditioning
and the radio and all of the
other bells and whistles.
We do this a lot inside
the software world,
where if I'm going to
build a large program,
like say a word processor
that's got hundreds of
different functions,
well, the first Minimum
Viable Product to that
is something that can take text in
and display it on the screen, and allow me
to go back and edit that text.
And then we might add in other features
like adding bold or italics,
being able to change the color
or the justification, or
then doing mail merge,
and all of those other things.
But the Minimum Viable
Product is the least amount
that we can do to get something
in the hands of our users.
If you're going to build an app,
sometimes we'll do this
by doing wireframes
that aren't even functional.
But we can show you what
it's going to look like,
and you can approve that and
say you like or don't like it.
That would be a Minimum
Viable Product nutcase.
The key concept with the
Minimum Viable Product
is the minimum that we have
to do to get initial feedback
so we can determine if
we should keep moving
forward with this project.
This may be operational,
it may be something
that we released to the
public and sell as version one
with the intent that version
two would be even better.
It just depends on how you want
to set up inside your project.
The next one we have is
learn from experience.
And when we talk about
learn from experience,
we remember that everybody makes mistakes,
but can we learn from those
so we don't repeat those?
Now how do we implement learn
from experience inside Agile?
Well we do it in three different ways.
The first is using retrospectives.
At the end of our sprints, we
do our sprint retrospective,
and we start looking back at the sprint
and say what worked well
and what didn't work well.
We then want to implement
that into our next sprint.
That's a way to learn from experience.
Another way we do it in Agile
is by shortening those feedback loops,
by things like using Minimum
Viable Products, right?
And we start getting things out
into our users hands quicker
to get feedback sooner
that we can implement.
That helps us learn from experience.
The third thing is
inspecting and adapting.
As we're building things,
we're constantly inspecting
them for quality and control,
and making sure they're what we want.
And if they're not, we're going
to change it and adapt it,
learn from the experience and move
into the next version of the product.
Agile is really good about
learn from experience.
It's one of those core tenants and beliefs
that we can all learn and
implement it quicker and faster
to do something better in the future.
The next one that we have is defining
your roles and responsibilities.
This is where we want
to focus and make sure
that everyone in the project
knows what job they're doing
and what responsibilities
they have associated
with that role or that job.
Inside of PRINCE2 Agile, we do this
by blending our PRINCE2
roles and responsibilities
with those Agile roles.
So we start figuring
out who inside the role
maybe the project manager
is also going to be the scrum master.
This may be that we're going to deal
with the team members or the team leader,
and they're going to be part
of the development team.
We're going to make sure
that we line up those roles
from the regular PRINCE2 rolls
into the Agile roles as well
to make sure that there's a good blending,
and we can move forward.
The next principle we have
is Management by Stages.
And with Management by Stages,
we took that big long project
timeline and project plan,
and broke it down into smaller
stages for us to work on.
This allowed us to figure out better
how long it would take
and what the cost is.
Now that is what we would do
in a standard prints methodology.
But in Agile, we fix cost and we fix time.
So, do we still need to manage by stages?
Well yes, and we do
this by using timeboxes.
By using a timebox, we have
a fixed amount of time,
and a fixed amount of cost,
and this is going to
be put into our sprint,
and we're using sprints
as part of our releases.
These effectively start
becoming our stages.
And at the end of a couple of sprints,
they may have three
sprints inside one stage,
or you could have one sprint in one stage.
It depends on how your
governance is being set up.
But this is how we implement
this Management by Stages,
is by using shorter stages
and shorter timeboxes
still allow us to have that control.
Our next principle is Manage by Exception.
With Manage by Exception, we are focused
on making sure that only
significant changes or deviations
from the budget or the approved plan
were brought up to the
attention of management.
Now in PRINCE2 Agile and
PRINCE2, this is really the same.
It's the use of good tolerances.
If you have strong tolerances
that are defined well,
this is going to allow you
to empower your team members
to make decisions, and make
changes that will get us
back to the good end state
that we want for our product.
So tolerances are even
more important in Agile
than they were in PRINCE2,
because it allows the team
members to make the decisions,
and be able to work in
this Agile methodology.
The next principle is Focus on Products.
Focus on Products is working to ensure
that we successfully deliver products
that will lead to the project's benefits
being realized by our end users.
Now in prints, this is focused
on making sure management
products are created,
and the final deliverable
that thing we're building is created.
But in Agile, we're going to
modify that just a little bit.
In Agile, we realize that the customer
doesn't get everything that they want.
But we do want to ensure they
get everything that they need.
To do this, we do this
with a prioritization
of the products and the quality criteria.
This allows the team
and the project manager
to make decisions of how they're
going to shift the product
and what pieces they're
going to work on first.
Again, this works really well
when you're dealing
something that's intangible
like a software, more than something
that's tangible like a house.
But both are going to exist.
Also when we deal with
the management products
inside of PRINCE2 Agile.
We can really modify and tailor the format
and formality of these.
And this is part of this
modifying the focus on products.
Instead of being focused on
getting a checkpoint report up
from a team manager to
the project manager,
we may instead just
have the project manager
go and look at the information radiator,
and pull the information
they need themselves.
This is a modification of
the formality of the product
as well as the format of the product.
And there are lots of
those that can happen
throughout your project
as we move forward.
Some other tailoring and implementation
of these focus on products
that get looked at
besides the checkpoint report
might be the way that
highlight reports are sent up
from project manager up
to the project board.
Or it may be the way that
work packages are set up
from the project manager, down to the team
or the development team that's working it.
Instead of having a formal work package,
it might just be part
of the release backlog
that gets put together.
And so all of these are
things that can be modified
based on the formality or format
to meet our Agile working methods.
The seventh and final principle
is Tailor to Suit the Project.
This one was custom made for Agile,
because it really does allow
us to adapt specifically,
everything inside of PRINCE2
to our current project.
If we're going to work highly Agile,
we're going to do a lot of tailoring.
If we're going to work very little Agile,
we're going to do less tailoring.
The biggest way that we implement Agile
inside of Tailor to Suit
the Project environment
is doing an Agile assessment
using the Agilometer.
By going through those six
areas of the Agilometer,
and figuring out where our organization
sits in relation to them,
whether we are highly Agile
or low on the Agile scale.
It will help us better tailor
to suit our project environment
to address those risks as we move forward.