- In any PRINCE2 project, there are
three main stakeholders that we have
competing interests with
that have to be balanced.
The first is the business.
The second is the user.
And the third is the supplier.
In a traditional PRINCE2 organization,
this is represented on the project board
by the executive, who's
focused on the business needs,
the senior user, focused
on the user's needs,
and the senior supplier,
who's focused on the supplier's needs.
As all three of these are being balanced
inside the project to get
us a product at the end
that meets the delivery requirements
so the users can get benefit from it.
Now, as we start looking at this
inside the organization theme,
we have to determine how best
to set up our organization.
A traditional PRINCE2
organization is set up like this.
We have a project board
with the executive,
senior user, and senior supplier.
Underneath them, we
have a project manager.
And underneath the project manager,
we have the team manager.
And then underneath them
is the team members.
Who are actually working on
the delivery of the product.
Now as we look to take this PRINCE2 method
and start forming it
into an Agile construct,
we have to look at what
needs to be tailored
inside the organization theme.
The good news is, there
is no major changes
that really have to be made to the way
that PRINCE2 is organized
in order for it to work
in an Agile construct.
But we do have to add
a couple of key roles.
This is things like looking at the way
the team manager's role is set up,
and figuring out, are they
going to be integrated
into the delivery team,
or are they going to stay
outside of the delivery team
and be more of a managerial function?
We also need to look at
some common Agile roles,
like the product donor
and the scrum master.
When we look at the product donor,
who's going to fulfill that role?
Is it going to be the senior user?
And that's usually the most
common way of doing it.
If not, you're going to have to figure out
who's going to be that
person who's going to act
as the product owner
from an Agile perspective
based on the amount of time
and responsibility they have.
Next, we have to look at the scrum master.
This is something we need to bring in
if we're going to be using Agile construct
to make sure that somebody
is there making sure
the processes are working properly.
This person is going to
have a direct liaison
with the project manager
or, in some cases,
it may be the project manager.
It just depends on how you
want to set up your project
for your organization.
Now, as we look into the project
and we look at the way the organization
is being set up, we have
to think about the way
the team is going to be designed.
Now, how are we going to design this team?
Well, if we're using an Agile construct,
we should be using self-organizing teams.
That delivery team should
be made up of the people
who have the right skills and capability
and mesh together well to
provide the right product.
As we start focusing on
self-organizing teams
and allowing them to manage by exception,
we also have to think about
the traditional PRINCE2 roles,
things like project
managers and team managers,
and how do they fit in.
Well, if we're going to move from PRINCE2
to PRINCE2 Agile, those two roles
actually have less prominence.
There's less focus on the
managers and more focus
on the delivery itself.
Also, in a traditional
PRINCE2 environment,
we may have some roles out there
like requirements engineers
or business analysts, who help to develop
the really in-depth
requirements for our project.
When we start dealing with Agile, though,
we don't really need those people,
because we hae our user stories,
and we have our users
getting a lot more integrated
into our delivery and being
represented on the team.
And so a lot of that will
actually be diminished
and have less prominence as well.
Doesn't mean they go away completely,
but it does mean we're going
to spend a lot less time
on those particular functions.
Now as we start looking at this Agile view
of the way things are working,
we have to think about
what the relationships are
with different people.
So if we look, for instance, at the PM,
the project manager, and
the TM, the team manager,
how are they going to
relate to each other?
In a traditional PRINCE2 method,
usually the team manager
works for the project manager.
But, inside an Agile
methodology, there's more
of this servant leadership
attitude from the project manager
to the team manager.
While the team manger
still technically works
for the project manager,
the project manager
is really there to help
serve and do the things
that are needed for the team
manger to be successful.
Now, when we start looking
at the team manager themself,
we have a question of should they be
a part of the delivery
team, or should they just be
managing the delivery team.
And that's going to be different depending
on how you want to do
it inside your project.
We'll talk a little bit more
about that in just a second.
We also have to look at
that senior user role.
Are they going to act as the
product owner and the manager,
or are we going to get somebody
else to fulfill that function?
And then, whatever these changes are
that we decide on, because
we're using PRINCE2,
we do need to define those inside
our project initiation documentation,
because that's where the
organization is laid out.
Any changes or tailoring that's being made
should be put into your PID,
your project initiation documentation.
Now, when we look at things
from an Agile perspective,
what adjustments are we
making to the Agile process
to make it work well inside PRINCE2?
Well, one of them is that
we only use a single product owner.
Now, again, this can be your senior user,
or it could be delegated elsewhere,
but there should only be one product owner
inside of PRINCE2 Agile.
In a traditional Agile
environment, though,
you can have multiple product owners.
And that's okay, it just depends
on how you want to set it up.
Again, though, it is recommended
to have single product owner
inside of PRINCE 2 Agile,
because it allows more of that control
and governance to occur.
PRINCE2 Agile also
recommends that you have
further roles added to
help that product owner,
people that are known as
subject matter experts,
or user representatives,
and by embedding those type
of people inside the delivery team,
it allows that product owner function
to remain up at the senior user level.
Also, any of these changes you do,
and any of these modifications
you do inside Agile,
you should define them inside
your working agreements,
because a lot of times, the
teams that are delivering
your product don't work inside
your traditional organization or business.
They might be outsourced or contracted,
and so you want to make
sure all of this is defined
in the proper working agreements
so everybody knows what is expected.
Now, as far as the delivery team goes,
the delivery team has
a lot of people in it,
and we want to make
sure we keep that number
to a reasonable size, usually no more than
five to seven people.
We want to make sure
we have representation
from several different places, though.
For example, we need
somebody to lead the team,
usually your team manger.
We need somebody from the customer side,
or their representative.
That could be a subject matter expert
or a user representative.
We need a team to actually
create the products,
and the people who are going to
do the coding and the design.
We also need somebody to ensure
that the quality of the
product meets what we need,
that quality control function.
We need somebody who can coach the team
on how to use Agile, somebody
like our scrum master.
And we also need multi-skilled,
generalizing specialists.
That means that we don't want somebody
who can only do one thing.
We need people who can do multiple things.
If I'm going to build
an app, for instance,
I need to have some people
who can do graphic work,
and I need people who can do coding work.
But if I have somebody who
can only do a very specialized
type of coding, that's not
going to be good enough
for us to be able to be agile enough
to meet the different requirements
that may be placed on our team.
And so we want to have
people who are kind of
the jack of all trades but master of none.
That kind of philosophy where they can do
a little bit of everything,
and then pull in specialists as needed.
So I know I just threw a
whole bunch of terms at you.
Let's look at how this
looks in a graphical format
as we move from a PRINCE2 format
over into a PRINCE2 Agile format.
You'll notice on the left, we have our
traditional PRINCE2 methodology.
This has our project
board with our executive,
senior user, and senior supplier,
and it's hierarchically down
through the project manager,
through the team manager,
and then down to the team members.
Now if we move on to the
right in this Agile linkage,
we're going to look at
how we do this here.
We still have a project board at the top,
which is our senior user,
our senior supplier,
and our executive.
We still have our project
manager and our team manager,
and they may be one and the same person,
as you see with that line there.
But they're also going
to be working directly
with the delivery team,
and that delivery team
is going to be your supplier
subject matter expert,
your customer subject matter expert,
your quality assurance people,
your SMEs, your scrum
masters, all of those people
are part of this delivery team
that helps the organization move properly.
Because they're in the
team, that team becomes
very flat as an organization,
and they all work together collaboratively
to get what we need done,
as opposed to the more
hierarchal nature on the left
when we start dealing
with PRINCE2 hierarchies
in our normal organizations.
So as we continue moving
through our organization theme,
let me give you some guidance
of how we know when we
need to modify things
for this Agile method.
First, we need to add those PRINCE2 roles
to the Agile delivery
roles, and that seems to be
fairly straight-forward, where we can say
the team manger is also
the project manager,
or the project manager
is also the scrum master.
We might have the senior user being
the product owner, right?
Those things line up fairly easily.
How easy this is is going to depend
on the nature of your
work and your project.
Smaller projects are easier to align
than bigger projects, but
we do need to make sure
that we align these roles,
so that we're covering both
the PRINCE2 side of things
and the Agile way of working.
If we're looking at routine work,
these are going to be very
small-scale routine projects,
the number of teams you
need is probably one,
and this is not applicable
to a PRINCE2 environment,
because it's handled as business as usual.
If we look at something that's
a difficult type of work,
but is a small-scale, we still
might only need one team,
and this will be pretty straight-forward.
The project manager and
the team manger roles
can be combined into one,
and they might even be part
of that delivery team.
On the other hand, if we have a large
or difficult problem
that we're dealing with
inside the project, we may
need many different teams
to help us work on it.
And if we do that, this is
going to require more care,
more governance, and more control.
This is when we're going to
make sure the Agile roles
are properly aligned
to those PRINCE2 roles,
even across multiple
teams, and the alignment
may not be as obvious as it would be
in a smaller, less difficult project.
Now, the last thing we're going to cover
inside the organization theme
is how we're going to deal
with the project manager relationship
with the delivery team.
Is the project manager
going to work directly
with the delivery team?
Are they going to work
with a team manager?
And if so, is that team manager
a part of the delivery team,
or are they going to be management
above the delivery team?
There's really three
ways of looking at it,
and there is no right answer,
because it all depends on
your particular project.
Now, the first way we can do it,
is we can leave the delivery team roles
as they are in Agile, and
they're just going to work
directly with the project manager,
and it's going to be a very ad
hoc, very informal relationship.
The second way, is we can
leave the delivery teams alone,
but we can identify one person on the team
who's going to be the point of
contact for the project manager.
They're going to be the one
who's passing information
to and from the project manager,
and acting somewhat as a team manager.
The third is to actually
create a team manager role
in the delivery team,
and this person will then
manage and oversee the
entire delivery team.
Now, the challenge with
this versus option two,
is that this person now
may be seen as the boss,
and be a little less collaborative
inside that delivery team.
Now when we look at this organizationally,
there is really two ways that we can place
that team manager.
As I said, one is they can kind of work
above the team as a manager,
and the other is that
they can work in the team
as part of team delivery.
If they're working above the team,
this looks more like a
traditional PRINCE2 team.
And it is not as Agile in nature.
Instead, it's better to
get that team manager
to be somebody within the team,
who works on the development as well,
because this is going to
allow you to be more Agile
in the way you work.
So as we look at that, let's assume
that we're going to place our
team manager within the team.
Now, if they're working within the team,
we now have to look at the relationship
between the team manager
and the project manager.
The first way is if you're
using a single team structure.
When you're using a single team structure,
you're going to have a team
manager who's part of your team
reporting directly to a project manager,
and that person is going to
report to the project board.
Now, that project manager and team manager
may also be the same
person if you're dealing
with a small-scale project.
Now, if our project is
more complex and difficult,
and we have more teams,
say this example here,
where I have three
different delivery teams,
then I would have a team manager in charge
of each of the three teams.
Each of those delivery
managers or team managers
would report up to the project manager.
From that point on, it becomes much more
like standard PRINCE2, with
lots of governance and control
at the project manager and
the project board levels,
but remaining very Agile
down at the delivery level,
with the team managers
and the delivery teams
running the show.