- In this short video,
I'm going to show you
how you can get your exam
voucher for about $50 off.
Now normally when you take
the PRINCE2 Agile Foundation exam,
you're going to take it
online through peoplecert.org.
Now, as you go back and look
at the price of this exam,
it's going to vary by country,
but in the United States
it's $349, as shown here.
Now, depending where you are in the world,
it'll be a little bit
more, or a little bit less.
If you want to buy your exam
voucher through PeopleCert,
you can do that by booking your exam here,
and you'll go through and
schedule the date and time.
Now, you can go ahead and
schedule your exam right here,
or you can save a little bit of money
by taking one extra step.
You can go to diontraining.com,
and on the front
of our homepage, you'll
see the exam button.
If you click on that exam button,
what you're going to see is all
of our exam vouchers for sale.
Any of the exams that we
teach, such as ITIL 4,
ITIL, PRINCE2, or PRINCE2
Agile Foundations,
you can go and get your
vouchers through us.
As you can see on the screen,
the current price for
this voucher is $299,
a $50 savings off buying
it through PeopleCert.
Now when you buy it from us,
we're going to collect your
credit card information,
and instantly fulfill that voucher,
if it's in stock, back to your email,
where you'll receive a one-time use code.
Once you have that one-time
use code in your email,
you're going to go and
click and create an account
by going to the little
icon, and going down
to create an account, if
you're new to PeopleCert.
If you've taken an ITIL exam,
or a PRINCE2 exam before,
you'll actually have an account,
and you'll just sign in to your account.
Once you go here, you're going to go ahead
and enter your information, so
I'm going to put in Jason Dion,
my email address will be
youremail@youremail.com,
again you'll enter your
own information here,
and then you'll select
your country of residence,
mine is United States, and
then you'll give it a password,
and you're going to agree to those terms
and conditions for the privacy,
and if you'd like to receive marketing
from PeopleCert, you
can check that as well.
Once you do that, click
on join PeopleCert.
Now that you're logged into
your PeopleCert account,
and you have your exam voucher,
you can go and enter that
exam voucher up here,
and then click on confirm.
Once you do that, it'll bring
up a date and time calendar
for you to select the day and time
that works best for your schedule.
Once you select that, it'll
show up here under My exams,
and you'll come back here about 30 minutes
before your scheduled time
to be able to sign in,
download the software
needed, and begin your exam.