- The next set of seven
we're going to talk about
is the seven processes.
The seven processes are the application
of those seven principles
and the seven themes,
as we go through the project
management lifecycle.
The seven processes are used to describe
which role, from the
project management team,
is responsible for making decisions
and when those decisions should be made.
Now, as we go through these
seven processes, you're going to
see that they all tie in together.
In a linear fashion.
As we go through the project.
The first process we're
going to talk about
is starting up a project.
Starting up a project is
used to ensure that all
of the prerequisites for
initiating a project are in place
by answering a simple question.
Do we have a viable
and worthwhile project?
In starting up a project,
we're going to have hundreds
of ideas of what project should be done.
And eventually these are
going to be funneled down
into just one or two ideas
of what we should do.
One of these will end up
becoming the project mandate.
And we'll be told, we should
look at starting up a project
on idea X.
We want to build this thing.
And so we will start the
starting up a project phase.
Where initial research
and analysis will be done
to determine is this a viable thing to do?
For example, my company
is a training company.
If we had an idea of building
a rocket ship, that's
probably not a very viable
or worthwhile project for us.
It maybe for other
organizations, but not for us.
And so we have to take the
thousands of ideas that we come
up with, to decide what
is the thing that we're
going to work on next?
Then, once you have that good
idea and it's been approved,
we're going to move into
initiating a project.
And in initiating a project,
we are going to go through
and make sure that we
establish solid foundations
for this project.
Because we want to enable the
organization to understand
what is working and what isn't.
And what needs to be done to
deliver the project's products
before we commit to the
significant spending of resources.
And so, going back to my
company's example; we get
suggestions from students all the time
on different courses we should make.
Now, we might take those 50
or 100 different suggestions
and boil it down to one
or two different ideas
that's going to be our next project.
Then we start going through
our initiating a project phase
and we go and start looking at
what is the cost and benefit
of doing that.
Is there a big enough
market demand for that thing
that we're going to teach?
Do we have the knowledge and skills
to train that effectively?
And as we go through that,
we're going to put everything
in place and build up our
business case and build up
our project initiation documents,
so that we can then move
forward and build out that next product.
The next process we're going
to talk about is kind of
a unique one.
Because it doesn't sit in
just one stage, but it works
across all of the stages in the project.
It's known as directing a project.
And this is used to
enable the project board
to be accountable for the
project's success by making
key decisions and
exercising overall control
while delegating the day-to-day management
down to the project manager.
So when we start talking
about starting up a project
and initiating a project and
as we get through the rest
of the stages, a lot of those are focused
on what the project manager is doing.
But directing a project isn't.
This is where the board takes
input from the project manager
and makes decisions.
This may be the decision
to start up the project.
It may be the decision
to initiate the project.
Or to move from one
stage to the next stage.
Or how to handle an exception or an issue.
All of this is done at
directing a project.
So when you're thinking
about directing a project
always remember this is decision making
at the project board level.
This brings us down into
the next process, which is
how we manage a stage boundary.
As we get to the end of stage
one or the end of stage two
and we want to move into the
next stage as a project manager,
we have to go back to the project board
and ask permission to do that.
And that's where we initiate this managing
a stage boundary process.
It's going to enable the
project manager to provide
the project board with
sufficient information
for them to review the success
of the current management
stage; approve the stage plan
for the the next stage.
Review the updated project
plan, confirm the continued
business justification and
decide if they're going to
accept the risks and let
the project move forward.
Again, this is simply
where the project manager
comes to the project board
and says, "Here's the current
"status, here's my plan way ahead,
"can I move into the next stage?"
And then if the project
board says yes, they use that
directing a project process
to make that decision
and let us move into the next stage.
That brings us into controlling a stage.
And this again is a
project manager function.
This is going to be where the
project manager assigns the work
to be done, monitors that
work, deals with any issues
that come up, reports the progress back up
to the project board,
using highlight reports.
And they take corrective
action to ensure that the stage
remains within the tolerances
that they're given.
So this is the day-to-day
work of a project manager.
It's where they spend most of their time.
But this isn't where the product
is actually being created.
This is just the management
of that creation.
For that to be created,
we had to move into
the managing product delivery.
And this is done at the team level.
So this is where the link
between the project manager
and a team manager comes into play.
And where they're going to
agree on the requirements
for the acceptance, execution and delivery
of those products.
The role of the team manager
here is to coordinate
all of the work that needs to
be done inside their team plan
here at managing product delivery.
They're the closest ones
to the finished product.
So if I'm talking about
building a website, for example,
I might have the graphics
team working on one package,
and they have a team manager.
And then I might have a
coding team that's working
on another package and
they have a team manager.
The project manager is going to be working
with those individual team
managers to make sure they
understand what the requirements
are for the coding aspect
of the site and the
graphics aspect of the site.
And once they agree to
that, those team managers
will run the daily production.
To get that product delivered.
Next, we have closing a project.
And once we get to the
final stage, this is what we
call closing a project.
This is going to provide us
with a fixed point at which
the acceptance for the
project's product is confirmed
by the end users.
And this is going to
recognize that the objectives
set out by the original
project initiation document
have been achieved.
So when we started up
this project and we went
to the initiation phase, we
made a list of everything
that this project was going to deliver.
Now that we're in the closing
a project phase, we're
going to go back to that
list and make sure that we've
met all those requirements.
Now one of the interesting
things about closing a project
is you don't have to wait
until you've gone through
all the stages to get to this phase.
In fact if we're going
through and say we're in stage
two out of 10 and we
decide there is no longer
a continued business justification,
then the project board
can decide that we're going to
terminate work on the project
and jump right into closing a project.
This means that the project
has nothing more to contribute
and this a time we're going to
go through and just finalize
everything, release the resources
that we don't need anymore
and close up the project
prematurely, based on the fact
that there's no longer a
continued business justification.