- [Trainer] When we start talking about
tailoring the Plans theme
inside of PRINCE2 Agile,
we have to recognize
that a lot of big changes
aren't really required
because we're still going to do planning
like we did in PRINCE2.
The biggest difference is going
to be the low-level plans.
With Agile, if we're going to be doing it
in a PRINCE2 Agile method,
we'll still have an
overarching project plan.
This overarching project
plan may be demonstrated
as a Gantt chart or some
other method like that,
that provides us with formal milestones
that show us the duration of work
that we expect to get done.
The big difference, though,
is once we start looking
inside the Stage or the Team level plans.
At this point, we're going to
start looking at the low-level
details that are shown in backlogs.
So, it really becomes more
of a matter of the format
of the plans than having
the plans themselves.
When we look at this, we're
going to be using Agile
techniques and approaches.
Things like releases and
sprints and burn charts
to show how much value or how much product
can be delivered in a
fixed amount of time.
Whether that's a two week
sprint or a four week sprint
or a four week or an eight week release
or whatever we've decided
to do inside of our plan.
The big difference here
is that these plans
at the low level, will
be much more informal
than what we will see in the
normal PRINCE2 Team plan.
Instead we're going to be
looking at that pole method
where we're going to have all of the work
that is in the ready state,
be allowed to be chosen from
during the prioritization
of that s1print planning.
Again, that goes back to
our low-level details.
As we look at this from
an Agile perspective,
there's going to be a lot
of emphasis on planning
but we're going to be
doing this in this team
and collaboration based method.
We're going to rely on empiricism
instead of rationalism.
What I mean by that is we're
really focused on what the
output is going to be.
We're going to do our planning
based on what we've seen
based on our previous
experiences, as well.
The planning can be based on
features that are going to be put
into the end product.
It's going to be a very team
based collaborative exercise
and we're going to plan at
the last responsible moment.
And what that means is
that we are going to wait
until right before the
sprint to choose the things
we're going to work on in the next sprint.
That allows us to have better clarity
because there's a
shorter planning horizon.
When we do this, we're
going to pick this out
based on a prioritization system.
And, some people use a point
system that helps you to
estimate what is most important
and what is least important.
Maybe this feature is worth 10 points
and this other feature is worth two points
and we're only going to do
100 points worth of stuff
in this sprint.
And, as we start picking
things, we will then put it in
there based on the level of
effort and the amount of time
it will take.
When we look at PRINCE2
and we look at Agile,
we're always considering
our planning horizon.
How far out can we accurately plan?
It's really hard to figure out
what we're going to plan for
in six months or a year from now.
But, it's really easy to start
planning what we're going to do
tomorrow or what we're
going to do next week
because it's closer to us
and we have more fidelity
into that planning process.
When we look at the Plans
theme, there's some general
guidance that we have to consider.
The first is that PRINCE2 does
support any planning style.
It doesn't say it has to
be some long drawn out
planning process.
We can use a Gantt chart or a
burn down chart or a sprint.
It doesn't really matter.
As long as we're doing planning,
we're still in accordance
with the PRINCE2 framework.
We also are going to be focused on doing
product based planning.
And, this can be at any plan level.
When we do product based
planning, that happens at a lot
at the team level, especially in Agile,
when we start picking specific features
that we're going to roll into
this sprint and this release.
But, that also happens at the
team level, the stage level,
and at the project level.
Our high-level plans are
developed to continue to support
that continued business justification.
We want to make sure that
the product plan is still
proceeding as planned.
In that, we're going to
give them broad timings.
What's the end date that we
expect the final deliverable?
As well as broad costs.
How much of a significant expenditure
are we going to have to do
to get to the finish line?
When we look at the lower-level plans,
these are going to be used to support
the delivery of our product.
To be able to bring things
into that low-level plan,
we are going to do, providing
ready stories and pulling those
into our sprint planning
based on the ready backlog.
We're also going to
provide clearer priorities
to the planning team.
This is a very high priority function.
This is a low priority function.
So, when they're planning what
they're going to work on first,
they're going to be taking,
at least, some of those
high priority things
and maybe some of those
lower priority things,
and they will trade things
that bring out a well rounded
and well planned sprint for
them to work on over the next
two to four weeks.
As we look at the levels of plans,
there's really three levels.
The big higher level one
is called the Project level
or the Project Plan.
When we look at this big overarching plan,
it is likely to be a lot more formal
because it's being dealt with
at the project manager level
and the project board level.
This will show stage boundaries,
releases, major produccts,
major activities, different
groupings, and dependencies
across the entire project.
This is going to give you the
big broad cost and timing.
How much is this new website
that we're going to build
going to cost us and how
many weeks, months, or years
is it going to take to develop?
This is going to be
very big and very broad.
As we bring it down to the Stage Plan,
we're going to start bringing
it into a smaller timeframe
and a smaller cost window.
Then we bring it down to the lowest level
which is the Team level
or the Release Plan.
Both of these, whichever
term you're going to use,
are more likely to be
in the form of a backlog
instead of a written out plan.
This is going to contain
things like your stories,
your priorities, the amount
of work that needs to be done,
and the relative size of
each of those pieces of work.
That's going to allow us to do
a good job in sprint planning
to figure out what we'll be
able to do in this cycle.
As we look at these plans,
you can see it graphically,
we have this overarching Project plan
then underneath that,
we have a Stage plan,
then as we get lower,
we have the Release plan
which has also got our Team
plan for those two time boxes.
This allows us to focus
specifically on what we're going to
work at, at each and every level.
When we go into our sprint planning,
we have to have a way of figuring out
which things we're going to
take from the ready bucket
and work on in the sprint because
usually there's going to be
more stuff ready than you have
capacity to be able to do.
And, the way we do this is
we're going to use some sort of
Agile estimating technique.
This is going to give
us a relative estimate
based upon a system of points.
This will allow us to choose
which things we want to work
on first and which ones we're
going to defer to a later sprint.
There's lots of different types out there.
One of them is based
on Fibonacci sequences
and has a series of numbers
from 1, 1, 2, 3, 5, 8, 13, 21,
and so on.
The reason they use this
is because one will be your
highest priority and the larger numbers
will be your lower priority.
This gives you a nice wide distribution
as you try to figure out which priorities
are biggest and smallest.
Another way that I've
see commonly seen used
is what we use the T-shirt size method.
This will be small,
medium, large, extra-large,
that kind of an idea.
This will allow you to figure
out how much work is involved
in this particular feature.
And, the final way, is
what's known as story points.
This is where the user stories are graded
based on some rubric and each
one is assigned a number.
Based on those numbers,
we would then prioritize
which one's highest, take more work.
Which one's lowest, take
the least amount of work.
Once we've chosen everything
we want to work on
for this sprint and put
it into that Sprint plan,
that Team plan, or that Release plan,
we are going to move on
into the Progress theme.