- So in this lesson, we're going to talk
about management products.
In the PRINCE2 method,
there are 26 distinct
management products that are created
throughout the lifecycle
and throughout the project.
All of these can be found in appendix A
of your PRINCE2 manual or
your PRINCE2 Agile manual.
Now, you don't need to know
all 26 of them for the exam.
But there are several of them that
you have to be familiar with,
because they are heavily tailored
and used inside of an Agile environment.
This includes your business case,
your checkpoint report,
your highlight report,
your project brief, your project
initiation documentation,
your project product description,
and your work package.
And so we're going to
talk about each of those
inside of this lesson.
The first management product
we're going to talk about
is the business case.
And the business case is used to
document the justification for starting
and continuing this project.
The business case is
going to be referenced
over and over again during the project,
to ensure there is still a continued
business justification that exists.
As we look in the business case,
it's going to tell us things like
what we hope to achieve with this project.
If this project was to build a website
and what is the goal of
building that website?
Is it to sell more widgets?
Or is it to inform people?
Is it to get better brand awareness?
Whatever that purpose is,
it should be documented
inside the business case.
It should say, we're going to spend,
roughly, x amount of dollars
to get y amount of value.
That's what it's all about.
It's what are the benefits and
the outcomes of this project?
And that way we can keep going back
to that business case to see if we're
still on track to hit those.
And if we're not, then we might
be terminating this project early
using closing a project process.
The next management product we're going to
talk about is the checkpoint report.
And your checkpoint report is a report
that the team manager's going to create
and send up to the project manager
with a current status
of their work packages.
So whatever they're working on,
to be able to build their product,
they need to be able to report that
up to the project manager.
Because, again, we want
to manage by exception.
Both from the project board
down to the project manager
and from the project manager
down to the team manager.
So this team manager is going to be able
to use this time based control,
where every week or every month
they send a report up
to the project manager
to say, "Here's where we are.
"Here's the progress we made.
"Here's the issues we have
"and here's the status of my pieces."
Now, just like we have
this Checkpoint Report
going up to the project manager,
the project manager gets multiple
Checkpoint Reports from
all of the different teams.
They're going to consolidate all of those
and create a single report
called a Highlight Report.
And the Highlight Report is going to go
from the project manager all the way
up to the project board.
And this is going to give them the current
status of the stage plan.
So all the different moving
pieces, for this stage,
are going to be incorporated
into this single report,
based off of those Checkpoint Reports.
Again, this is a time based control.
And based on how your project is set up,
it may be weekly, every two weeks,
every month, every six months,
it really depends on how
risky your project is
and how much control the project board
wants to retain and how much they
want to delegate down
to that project manager.
The next one we're going to talk about
is your project brief.
Now the project brief is what's going to
be created in the starting
up a project phase
and it's going to be used to get approval
to move into your
initiating a project phase,
where we'll actually develop a really good
and thought out business case.
But the project brief is created
even before that initial business case.
It's kind of like the outline.
The next document we have is the project
initiation document or the PIT.
This is the cornerstone of any project.
It's going to describe
the plan of approach
for project management
throughout the project.
It's going to contain lots of different
pieces underneath it,
including the project plan,
the detailed business
case, the communications
management approach, the
risk management approach,
the quality management approach,
the change control approach,
the project controls,
and any tailoring that
you're going to perform.
This is the golden document
inside of a project.
And it is created all the way back
in your initiating a project phase.
When you're initiating a project,
you're creating that
project initiation document.
And once it's approved, that's when
you're able to move into your first stage.
Now the next one we're going to talk about
is your project product description.
As we're going to figure out
what we're going to build,
we're going to have to be able to exactly
describe what is going to be delivered.
So if I'm going to build a house,
I should know, right from the beginning,
how many bedrooms?
How many bathrooms?
Is it going to have a kitchen or not?
Is it going to have a garage?
Is it going to have storage?
All of these things would have to be told
inside this project description.
It's going to tell us
exactly what we want.
Is it going to be built out of cement,
or brick, or wood, right?
And inside of this project
product description,
we're going to contain
things like the purpose,
the composition, the specifications,
the quality controls,
the tolerance levels,
and the acceptance criteria.
All of these will define
what the end result
of this project is going to be, based on
that product description.
The next one we have is our work package.
And this is what our team
manager's going to use
to create that product and
do product delivery for us.
The team manager uses the work package
which has his tolerances set in it
and what the acceptance criteria is,
to build out that product.
So if I'm going to this house example,
maybe I have a work
package for the plumbing.
And I have a work package for the floors.
And a work package for the electrical.
And each of those three team managers
now knows, inside that work package,
how many electrical outlets I need,
how many toilets I need,
how many sinks I need,
how many types of flooring I need.
All of those details are
in those work packages.
Each of those work
packages would be approved
by the project manager, prior to any work
beginning on that work package.
And allows that project manager
to have levels of control established
and then allow the team
manager to be empowered,
to get that final product created.