- In this lesson we're going
to talk about the exam itself.
We're going to talk about how long it is,
how many questions it is,
and really what the point
of the whole exam is.
And let's talk about that first.
What is the point of the
PRINCE2 Agile Foundation exam?
Well, if you pass it, you're
going to gain the first level
of certification inside the
PRINCE2 Agile framework.
The second level is Practitioner,
and to be able to take the Practitioner,
you have to have already
passed a Foundation level exam,
whether that's the PRINCE2 Foundation
or the PRINCE2 Agile Foundation.
When you look at this,
it's really going to ask,
can you understand how to blend PRINCE2
with Agile techniques?
And they really want to know
one fundamental question.
Are you able to know enough about PRINCE2
and Agile to work effectively inside of
a project management team
underneath a PRINCE2 environment?
If you can, that's the level
that we're looking for for Foundation.
That means you have to
understand the terms,
the techniques, and the tactics
that are used by both PRINCE2 and Agile.
So, when we look at this and
we start looking at this exam,
there are going to be five exam objectives
that we're going to cover,
and the rest of this course
is all built around these five things.
Think of it as our table of contents.
The first one is, do you
understand key concepts
relating to projects and PRINCE2?
This is your traditional
PRINCE2 framework.
The second one is, do you
understand key concepts
relating to projects and
PRINCE2 in an Agile environment?
This starts bringing in
those Agile concepts.
Number three, do you understand
PRINCE2 principles, themes,
processes, and management
products and how to tailor them
and apply them inside of an Agile context?
Number four, do you understand
the Agile ways of working,
the key terms, and the techniques?
And number five, do you
understand the focus areas
that apply inside of an Agile context?
So when you sit down to
take the exam on test day,
you're going to find that
there are 50 questions
you have to answer in one hour.
And these questions come in the form
of multiple choice questions
with choices A, B, C, or D.
Now, those multiple choice questions,
they'll show up as three
different types of format.
The vast majority of these are going to be
what we call standard
multiple choice questions,
where they might give you
a definition and then ask,
based on A, B, C, or D, which
terms matches that definition.
When we have a list type question,
this is one where they'll
give you four statements,
labeled one, two, three, and four.
And then your multiple choice options,
you'll have to select which of
those two statements are true.
And you'll do that by
choosing A, one and two,
B, two and three, C, three
and four, or D, one and four.
And the last type is what
we call a negative question.
They'll say, which of these are not true?
And then they'll have four
answers, A, B, C, and D,
and you'll select the
one that is not true.
As I said, the vast
majority of the questions
will be standard multiple
choice type though.
Now, to earn your certification,
you have to get at least 28 questions
out of 50 correct on test day.
That equates to 56%, so if
you can score 56% or higher,
you're going to pass and get certified.
This is a very doable and
very achievable number.
On exam day, it is closed-book though.
Everything you have to answer is going to
come out of your head,
not out of a textbook,
and not out of any paper that you bring
with you into the exam center.
So how do you know when you're ready
to go take the Foundations exam?
Well, after you've
taken this entire course
and you've watched all the videos,
you're going to take a
practice exam at the end.
When you take that practice exam,
if you score a 70% or higher,
you're ready to go take
the real foundations exam.
Now, wait a minute, Jason,
you said 70% on the practice exam,
but it's only 56% to pass the real exam.
Well, yes, the reason why I say that is
because I want to make
sure that you are ready
and you pass it on the first try
because each time you take that exam,
it costs about $350 to
buy your exam voucher.
And I don't know about you,
but I only want to have to
take the Foundations exam once
if I'm paying $350 each
time I take that exam.
Now, if you need more practice,
go out and find additional practice exams
to hone your skills to
make sure you're ready
for that certification exam.
But again, if you're scoring 70% or higher
on my practice exam, you
should be fine come test day.