- Change is inevitable.
In every project you work on,
whether it's in a waterfall method
or an Agile method,
there is going to be change that occurs.
The difference is how we're
going to react to that change.
When we look at it in an Agile way,
we're going to try to be more responsive
to the change at the detailed level.
Now, into our PRINCE2 Agile project,
we do want to make sure that we control
significant changes at the project level.
So when we create the project plan
and we say we're going to build a car,
we want to make sure that any changes
to that design of that car
are controlled up at the project level.
Now, when we start talking
about the detail level,
that may be when we start talking about
the color of the seats,
the fabric that's chosen,
or any of those other details
down at the team level,
that is where change can improve
the quality and usability
of the product much quicker
and the people designing
it can make those changes
within good tolerances.
And that's one of the keys when you start
tailoring your theme of change,
is you want to make sure
that you have good tolerances
because those tolerances that are set
in your product description
and your work package
are going to control how
well and how effectively
you can control change
and adapt by changing.
For example, when you look
at your product descriptions,
this is where your quality criteria
and your tolerances are originally set
for the project.
This gives you clear baselines
that can be managed very formally.
Anytime there's a change
that's going to happen
to one of these baselines,
or go outside these tolerances,
it's going to have to escalate all the way
up to the project board
and that change authority
to make the decision.
Now, when you look at the work packages
at that lower level,
this is where detailed
level change can occur.
Again, your work packages is going to have
defined tolerances for the team
that's going to say what their
left and right bounds are.
For example, in my car example,
we may have given them the tolerance
that there has to be four seats,
but we didn't tell them what type
of fabric they have to choose.
They have the ability to choose that
based on their desires,
based on what they think will
work best for the customer,
and what will meet the requirement.
This is going to be able to be managed
by the team dynamically,
as long as they stay
within their tolerances.
Now, if we go to something
of a more technical example,
we look at something like a website,
and we say the
responsiveness time has to be
between zero and one hundred milliseconds,
I don't really care which
technology they use,
as long as they stay
within that tolerance.
And so the team can figure out
what the solution is going to be
that's going to meet my end state.
This all comes down to good
requirements definitions.
Now, requirements definitions can be
either binary or on a spectrum.
If they're binary, this means
it's a yes or no question.
Going back to my car example,
the car must have four seats.
Does it have four seats?
Yes, they've met the intent.
Now if I looked at it on a spectrum level,
does the car have brown seats
and is that brown a color
between five and ten
on our color index?
Now I can look at it.
If it's a four, it's not within that,
it's outside tolerance.
But if it's a five, six,
seven, eight, nine, or ten,
then it's within my tolerance
and it's acceptable.
The idea with change in the theme
is by using good risk management
and good configuration management,
we can lessen the impact
of changes to our product.
And the whole idea inside PRINCE2 Agile,
is that we believe that the
team is closest to the problem.
They understand best
what the customer needs,
what the customer wants,
and how to deliver that effectively.
If we give them a good tolerance band,
they can build this thing
within that tolerance
and meet our needs
and dynamically deal with
the changes that come up
as we go through prototyping
and testing and development.
PRINCE2 and PRINCE2 Agile
look at change differently.
If we look at it from
a PRINCE2 perspective,
change is this thing that is cautious.
It's something that we want to avoid.
We want to make sure that all changes
are controlled up at the
change authority level
and at the project board level.
It's something where we
just want to make sure
that what we've designed
with all of our detail
is followed through in execution.
PRINCE2 Agile, on the other hand,
takes the opposite approach.
We're going to build
requirements very loosely
at the beginning and add
more detail as we go along.
As we go through and create our baselines,
we're going to create them for the correct
level of detail for
blending the work properly.
And what I mean by that is,
back in the starting up a project
and initiating a project phase,
we're going to have big,
wide tolerances set up
for our baselines up at the project level.
And we're going to give
a large portion of that
big tolerance down to our team level.
So the team has a lot of room
to make changes autonomously.
As they're working their
collaborative method,
they can decide that this project
needs to look more like
this or more like that
because they're closest to the problem.
And this is going to allow
them to rapidly respond
to change at the detailed level,
in coordination with the product owner
and the customer representatives.
Now, if there's any major
significant changes,
that will still go back
up to the project board
or the change authority
under PRINCE2 Agile
to be able to get approval for that.
Our goal in PRINCE2
Agile is to get feedback
as quickly as possible.
So we want to get our product out there
and get it into the hands of our customer.
By getting it to the customer,
we're going to get
feedback that is going to
empower us to make changes
based on that feedback
and get us a better product in the end.
We really do desire true feedback
from our end customer to ensure that
we're giving them what they want
and that it's meeting their needs.
There's lots of feedback loops that exist.
You may hear ones like the OODA loop,
which is the observe,
orient, decide, and act loop.
You may have heard of the PDCA,
which is plan, do, check, and act.
You may have heard of PDSA,
which is plan, do, study, and act.
Or you may have seen the
one we talked about earlier
in Lean Startup, build,
measure, and learn.
And in Agile, any of these
loops will work just fine.
Again, you can observe or plan
and then do something and
then act based on that.
In the Lean Startup one, we're
going to build something,
prototype it quickly,
get it out to a customer,
measure what the response
is, learn based on that,
and then build the next loop.
And this is the idea,
is getting in that feedback loop
to get a better product
and allowing the team
to make the changes
needed at this low level
and still meeting the
time and cost restrictions
that we've placed upon
them in our project.