- In this lesson, we are going to talk
about the Kanban method and how it applies
inside of Prince2.
Now, the Kanban method
was originally developed
by Toyota as part of their
manufacturing plants.
Kanban is actually the Japanese word
for signboard or billboard.
The idea with Kanban was to create
a visual management system
that limited the number
of work items that were currently
being accessed and
worked on as you're going
through the circulation process.
The idea here is that if we can focus
on just a couple of products,
maybe one or two or three
of them, we can get more work done than
if we are working on five
or 10 or 15 things at once.
So Kanban was really starting to work
with the agility portion
to improve our day-to-day
decision making, and focus us down on
to those couple of products
that we needed to work on.
They work on deferring the commitment
to work on future products
and future projects.
And the whole idea is to
reduce your lead times,
and get something from start to finish
in the shortest amount of time possible.
And if you focus on just a
couple of projects at a time,
or a couple of products
inside of a project at a time,
you can really get a lot
more done than trying
to spread yourself out
across multiple products
and multiple projects.
The idea with Kanban and
how we're going to use it
inside of Prince2 Agile, is being able
to use it as a visualization method.
And we're going to do
this inside the context
of our time boxes.
Kanban focuses on six general practices.
These are visualization,
limiting our work in progress,
managing the flow,
making policies explicit,
implementing feedback loops,
and improving collaboratively
while evolving experimentally.
Let's look at each one of those as we go
through the rest of this lesson.
First, we have visualization.
Kanban is very big on ensuring
that everyone knows
what is being worked on
at any one time.
And so they created this type of board,
and you'll see here we have the things
that are ready to be worked on,
the things that are in the build stage,
the things that are in the test stage,
and the things that are
in the deploy stage.
This allows us to see how
the work is progressing,
what is left to do, and where are there
any problems that exist.
And anything that's inside the build stage
or the test stage is what
we call work in progress.
Which brings us to our second point,
limiting work in progress.
Now this may seem
counterintuitive at first,
but this is a fundamental
concept inside of Kanban.
The idea is for us to work on
as little things as possible
so that we can get things through
in the fastest amount of time.
Inside that build and test phase,
we're going to put into it
work in progress limits.
So we may say, for this project,
we're only going to allow three
things to be worked on at once.
And whatever that limit is,
we have to stay within it.
Kanban is working really hard here
to avoid scheduling
work at specific times,
instead, it relies on a pull system.
So the development team
will go to that ready bucket
on the left, and be able
to pull out what's ready
to be worked on, and then
start building on it.
But we don't want them to
pull too many things at once.
And so, instead, we're just going to pull
to where capacity exists within
those work in progress limits.
This is going to reduce the
impact of task switching
and multitasking, because
really, we are not computers.
We are not great at multitasking.
We are much better when we
focus on one or two things
at a time, as opposed to trying
to work on 10 things simultaneously.
And that's the whole idea here,
when we limit our work in progress limits.
Now, the next one we have
is managing our flow.
The team is going to be
constantly looking at ways
to maximize their flow, which is
how do we get things from ready to done
in the quickest amount of time possible?
To do that, we're focusing on areas
that we can reduce waste.
And anytime that we can get waste removed,
or we can make a process more
efficient, we want to do that.
That's part of that team collaboration
that's going to help us improve our flow.
And again, as we talked
about in the last principle,
the team is the one
who's going to pull jobs
when they're ready to work on it.
And so it's not going to be a
push method, it's going to be
a pull method to manage
that flow most effectively.
The next one we have is
making our policies explicit.
And this is where we're
going to really focus
on making sure there are
clearly defined boundaries set
for how the team is going to work.
The policies will evolve
over time and migrate,
and we're going to end
up changing them based
on what we see that can be more
efficient or less efficient,
and we always want to get
towards more efficient.
But the idea with these policies is
that if the team has
proper policies in place,
they can make better decisions.
And in Prince2, we
implement this a lot of time
using those tolerances, right?
And so we have the team
that knows what their left
and right boundaries are,
which allows them to work
within them much more efficiently,
and get more flow created.
The next one we have is
implementing feedback loops.
And this is really important,
especially to be able
to learn lessons and
implement those lessons.
The value being delivered
is ultimately going
to be judged by the final
customer of that product.
And so we want to make
sure we get a product out
as quickly as possible to the customer,
because that's going to
allow us to get that feedback
and be able to make the
next version even better.
This is something that we're going to do
a quantitative assessment of,
and that's going to directly affect
what subsequently we're going to deliver.
So if I built this
course, and I get a bunch
of feedback from students that
I missed some certain topic,
I want to get that feedback quickly,
so I can go back in the
studio, add that content,
and put it back out in
version two of the course.
And that way, we are
constantly making it better.
The same thing happens
in a Kanban environment.
We always want to make
sure that we're getting
that feedback and implementing it quickly.
The sixth and final principle here is
to improve collaboratively
while evolving experimentally.
The idea here is that we want to build
on collaboration within our teams,
so they can be creative
and try new things.
And they're going to
constantly be experimenting
with better processes and
better methods of doing things.
If we find some better
ways of doing things,
we're going to implement
those, codify those,
and put them into policy,
so that we can use
that in future iterations as well.
Again, the whole idea
with Agile is teamwork.
We're all trying to get the thing done
in the best and most
efficient way possible.
And that's the whole idea behind this
and Kanban fits in well with this.
Now, there are some other
considerations you have
to think about when you're using Kanban
in an Agile environment.
A lot of times, people will take Scrum,
which we talked about previously,
and Kanban and mix them together.
And this is often called Scrumban.
It's an application of
Kanban where the underlying
framework is that Scrum framework.
And you're going to see a lot
of this inside of Prince2 Agile
because we do use a lot of principles
from Kanban, like
limiting work in progress,
and the visualization,
the collaborativeness,
those policies, and
learning from experience,
as well as the Scrum
framework with our sprints,
and our time boxing and
other policies from there.
Our policies are going to
exist for similar work items
because the flow will start
becoming more predictable.
If this is the 17th course you've made,
you're going to be
really good at making it.
But if it's the first one,
it's not nearly as good
because you don't have those
policies and procedures down.
And so, as you keep working on a project,
and you do the same type
of work over and over,
you're going to get better, and
the flow is going to improve,
and you can do it quickly
and more efficiently.
Your team is constantly
going to be looking at ways
on how you can improve the system.
Because we're trying to get more flow,
better, cheaper, and faster.
The idea is if we conduct experiments
in a controlled and objective way,
we can then see, did this way work better?
And if it did, we're going to
implement it in the future,
and that's what Kanban is all about.
It's all about, how do we
produce something faster,
cheaper, better, using
defined boundaries on the left
and right side, that we
only have a minimal amount
of work in progress at any given time.