- Our next process is
managing a stage boundary.
This process is the one
that gets tailored the most
out of any other process
inside of PRINCE2 Agile.
The reason is because
you may not even have
well defined stages
inside of PRINCE2 Agile.
Instead, you may be relying
on sprints and releases.
Because of this,
we're always going to be doing
continued viability decisions,
we're not going to plan them
in advance at stage boundaries
like we would in normal print.
Instead, we're constantly looking at
is this project being successful
at achieving what we want,
and does it continue to be viable?
If not, we would stop
it and move into closing
a project process instead.
We're always going to
be asking the question
how are things progressing?
And how is the team and the
processes working together?
Is this working out well or is it not,
and what can we do to fix it?
And because of all this,
we don't have this big formal boundary
like we would in normal PRINCE2.
The biggest thing we're
going to do inside tailoring
this process is doing things
to look back, look forward,
and look at the big picture.
As we look back,
we want to think about
how did we do so far?
How much stuff has been delivered?
What quality has been achieved?
Was the benefit that we
thought would be delivered
delivered successfully?
Is the processes working well?
And did we do our reviews and
our retrospectives properly
to be able to gather
those lessons learned?
Then, we're going to look forward,
and we're going to start
planning our next stage.
What things are going to be
put into the next release
or the next sprint?
We're going to review our
product and our release backlogs.
Do we have enough work
that's in the ready bucket
for us to be able to start moving forward
into the next stage or the next
release or the next sprint?
And we're going to start planning,
what is that next release
going to look like?
We also then have to look
at the bigger picture.
We need to review the business case again
and the project plan and make
sure we're still on track
and we're still meeting
the goals that this project
was set out to achieve.
We also need to look at
the performance of Agile
and how it's working
inside our environment.
Is Agile going to be
continually a way to work
in this particular project?
Or do we need more
governance and more control
and less agility?
Or, do we have less
governance and less control
because the project is
becoming more certain
and less risky,
and we're going to allow more
agile development to happen.
This is the thing we have to decide
as whether we're going to continue forward
or we're going to stop the project,
and that's the way we
manage a stage boundary
inside the agile way of working.
It's a lot different than
what we see in a normal
PRINCE2 scenario,
because in a normal PRINCE2 scenario,
there's this formal deadline,
this formal place that we stop and look,
should we move forward or not?
Inside agile, we don't
do that nearly as much.
Instead, we're trying to make sure
our processes are improving,
our benefits are being realized,
and work has been getting done,
and if it is, and it's still viable,
we'll continue to move forward.
So how does controlling
a stage look inside
this agile process?
Well, it's going to be very visual.
We're going to use things
like the information radiator
and the burn charts to
evaluate our progress.
We're going to look at
the facts and figures
from the retrospectives
and make sure that the
processes are working
and that we're getting the product out
that we expect to get out.
If we are, we can then make
the decision to move forward.
This is a point of formality,
and it's carried out with as
little ceremony as possible.
Unlike PRINCE2 where we
might have a big meeting
and a big discussion and
figure out whether or not
we're going to move forward,
a lot of times,
this is just the product
where we're saying
yep, continue forward,
and they just keep movin' on.
There may not even be a
formal meeting about it,
it may just be something
that's done through email
or some other informal method.