- As we move from
controlling a stage process
down into the managing product delivery,
we're going to take the focus
away from the project manager
and put it down on the
team and the team manager.
This is one of the areas where
most of the Agile techniques
and practices are going
to be used directly
by the delivery team
to improve the quality
and engagement of the process.
We're going to use management
frameworks like Scrum
and delivery process
frameworks like Kanban.
Either way, as we put
these processes into use,
we're going to start
delivering a better project
in a better, more agile way.
Now, inside the Managing
Product Delivery process,
we are going to be focused very
heavily on those work packages.
Those work packages are going
to be created collaboratively
with the project manager
and the team manager,
and they're going to serve as a vital link
and a vital interface
between those two managers.
This is going to provide the team manager
and the team underneath
them with defined tolerances
for the work they're
going to be working on.
This is going to help them define
what the product descriptions
are at the correct level,
to ensure that they're not these epics,
but they're down at the user story
and detailed level that they need.
This also is going to make
sure that the project manager
and the team manager both
agree to and understand
the guidance that's being
provided for areas like quality,
releases and risk, so what
else is really important here
at the managing product delivery level?
Well, in addition to those work packages,
we also want to make sure we understand
what reporting arrangements
are being used.
Are we going to be responsible
for providing a checkpoint report up,
or are we going to have
the project manager
sitting in our daily standups?
Either is okay, it just
depends on the level
of formality and transparency
that you want to have
up with the project manager.
Wider project context
should really be understood
down at the team level as well.
This is important because in Agile,
we always want to be working
in a very collaborative
and transparent way.
If there's multiple different teams
that are working on this project,
we should also know what the
other teams are working on.
That gives us that wider context
of what's going on inside the project
and helps us to be more efficient.
Now, once the team understands
the wider project context,
this helps them in understanding
how to prioritize things for delivery.
Now, as we do that, all
of this prioritization
should have been done back
in project initiation,
so we know what the project board expects,
as the high priorities,
the medium priorities,
and the low priorities.
And based on that, we're going to be able
to select the appropriate order of work.
Any time we have changes, we have to think
about are these big
changes or little changes?
If they're changes at the detail level,
these are more dynamic and can be handled
down at the team level.
If they're going to be a
big change to the project,
like we're going to go from a
four-seat car to a two-seat car,
that's something we're going to have to go
and make a change to the baseline,
using a formal change management process.
Prioritization is needed for all of this,
because it's going to help us determine
what things can be changed,
what things must be worked first
and what things would be worked last.
Also, when we look a prioritization,
we're going to look at
what has a higher priority,
quality criteria or functional
or non-functional requirements.
As we start prioritizing
things in quality,
and the acceptance criteria to know,
this is a level of
quality that must be met,
and this is a number one priority,
we will work towards that
and descope out functional requirements.
Or, you may be told that
quality is not as important
and function is more important,
and so we're going to
put more functions in
and lower down our quality.
This again is that quality
versus scope balance
that we're going to have to
make based on the prioritization
that we get from the project
initiation documents.