- Our final process is closing a project.
We've done everything we think
we need to in the project,
and we're looking at finishing it.
Now, when we get to closing a project
inside the agile context,
we're going to look back and see
how did we do?
How much was delivered?
To what quality?
Was the benefit delivered as promised?
And was the processes working well?
This all looks very similar
to managing a stage boundary
that we talked about in the last lesson,
but one thing we'll add to this is
we're going to look at the
final project or release reviews
in retrospectives.
To make sure that we
understood the whole process.
Now as we look forward we're going to say
are there and other benefits
that we can expect from this project,
and if so when will we get them?
This ties back to the
original Prince Two-Way
of closing a project.
Is there anything
outstanding in the project
that still needs to be completed?
Because you can close a
project and still have
a couple of things that
haven't been realized yet.
And those might be realized
inside of the operations
as it's moved to business as usual.
The same thing occurs here
inside the agile way of working.
Now as we look at the big picture here,
we want to make sure we're
checking the original baselines
and documents to make sure
we've met the original
and final outputs and
outcomes that were expected.
We want to check our products
if they've been accepted
by the operations team.
Conduct those operational handover,
and give this product to the customer.
And we need to finalize any documentation,
because as we built things
a lot of times we're not
documenting it fully along the way.
Now that we're enclosing a project,
this is the time to tie all that up
and finish all the documentation
and play catch up so that
we have a nice final product
that's been built much faster
and much more efficiently
than if we had used a waterfall method.
Now as we start looking at
what you're going to find
inside this closing a project process,
you're going to find that
there are defined processes
that only exist in mature
agile environments.
Often times closing a project
is one of the messiest places
inside this whole agile
thing in some companies.
The reason is because
we built it really fast
and then we turn it over to operations,
but we have no support built for it.
For example, if I went and built a new app
and turned it over to the
customer service team,
who now has to support it,
but they have no idea how it works,
because we didn't properly document it.
That can be a problem.
And so you want to try
to level up your maturity
in your organization by defining
good processes for this.
You want to make sure that
regular handovers have occurred
and that you've been doing this
all the way along throughout the project,
so as a piece of softwares been developed
we're going to give it
to the operations team
and release it into the environment.
They should then be able
to understand how it works
and be able to support it moving forward.
If we've done this a lot
throughout the project
in our agile way of working,
this means that it can become
second nature.
If we haven't now we're going
to be up against the wall
as we hit this closing a project,
because they're going
to have to take it over
and you're going to have to
train them up on how to do that.
Now as you look through the
closing a project process,
there's a couple of things
that you have to do.
The first is
you want to check against
your original baseline.
Did we meet everything we set out to do?
If we didn't we need to figure out
is it viable to keep a project going
further to meet those things
or should we terminate at this point?
We also want to evaluate the use of agile
on this particular project,
because if we look back and we say,
hey this time we built a car
and we tried doing it agile
and it didn't work out so well,
maybe next time you're going
to do it in a less agile way.
Or you were building a piece of software
and it worked really well
and you're going to say
we're going to use agile again
next time we build software.
So you want to evaluate the use of agile
as doing a final retrospective.
Also you want to ensure
there's some formality
to the final acceptance,
and that that level of
formality is appropriate
for the project.
If we're releasing one small feature
we may not need a full turnover,
but if we're releasing a full product
and operations now has to support it
we want to make sure that
in this formal handover
and acceptance between
the development team
and the operations team.
We also again want to
finalize any documentation,
because as we create things
iteratively and incrementally
we need to make sure we have
the final things in place
so that this can live on
as a finalized product in the future.
Now as we move forward
we want to think about
what does this all look like?
How does it actually happen?
Well, one of the things that happens is
that we create a workshop at the end
as part of closing the project.
This workshop gets
everybody in the same room
and we start talking about what went well
and what didn't.
We capture those lessons.
We ensure that the
operations team is happy
and ready to accept.
We make sure the development
team doesn't have any
outstanding work that needs to be done.
And all of that can be
done collaboratively
inside this workshop.
Also we want to make sure
that all the benefits
have already been delivered.
If they haven't we might
need to continue on
in this project and not close it yet.
Or we my close this
project and open a new one
to get the rest of those
benefits if we decide
they're still needed.
And also we want to make
sure that all the information
about this project is
put together and archived
and documented.
What I mean by that is,
we built a lot of stuff,
we have a lot of projects,
and we have information
radiators and burn down charts,
and issues and tasks and
suggestions and all of this stuff.
All of it should be collected
and it should be archived
so that the organization
can go back and look at it
in the future if we're
doing similar projects.
For example, if I went
a built a car this time
and now three months later
I need to go build a truck
a lot of that is going to carry over,
and so we can go back to
this projects records,
pull that information, and decide
what is going to be
applicable as we move forward
in developing that truck.