- In this lesson, we're
going to talk about
how you start up a project,
and initiate a project in an Agile manner.
We're going to combine the two of these
because most of the things
we're going to talk about
are applicable to both of these processes.
First, we need to determine if the project
is viable and worthwhile.
In starting up a project,
we want to look at it
and start creating the outline
for this business case.
And we take all of the ideas we have
and narrow it down to one that
is going to be our project.
Now when we start doing this
inside initiating a project,
we're going to take that
outline business case
and develop it much more fully.
We'll talk about that a little bit more
as we go through this lesson.
We also want to ensure that we're creating
a solid foundation for
us to understand the work
that's needed to be done,
for us to take this project
from an idea to final
execution and delivery.
By doing that it's going to allow
us to create the user stories
and the requirements much more thoroughly,
and be able to understand
all of the work that needs to get done
for us to have the
final project delivered.
Next we want to make sure that
we're setting up our project
in an appropriate manner.
And that's going to make
sure that we're using
the right Agile terms,
the right Agile roles,
and the right organizational structures
to make it work in an Agile method.
The impact of frequent
releases of the products
is going to enable us to get
benefits early and often.
That continuous feedback
loop is going to help us
better define the project as
we move forward throughout it.
And that's one of the
key distinctions between
the way we do it in traditional Prince2,
where everything is defined early on,
and all the requirements are stated as
early as the initiating a project phase,
as opposed to an Agile where these are
continually being developed,
and we're continually massaging them
to get to the end state that
we want with our final product.
Now as we move forward
and we start looking
at some other things we tailor
inside of these processes,
we have to remember two key things.
We want to make sure we're
defining things at the right level
and that we're defining
things the right way.
Now what do I mean by that?
When I talk about defining
things at the right level,
we want to consider things like
our outputs and our outcomes.
What is the output and outcome
that we expect from this project?
When we start writing that down,
that will serve as our
project product description.
The baseline of our user
stories essentially.
We also want to consider the benefits.
What are the benefits we expect?
Traditionally, this would be done
in a fully written out business case.
But in Agile, it doesn't
have to be nearly as formal.
Instead we want to start thinking
about what's the minimum viable product.
What's the best and worst case scenario
for the amount of product
that we have to deliver?
And if we can define that early on here,
in the starting up a project or
initiating a project phrase,
then we're going to be able to
start building towards that.
And finally, we got to think about
those high-level requirements.
What are those epics?
What are those things that the
user wants to be able to do?
And then we bring those down lower
into the outputs, outcomes, and benefits.
And so by doing this at the right level,
we can really define the big rocks
getting down to smaller
rocks in level of detail.
As we talk about defining
things the right way,
we want to think about how we
can enable Agile to work easier.
And the way do this is often by
ensuring we are outcome focused.
If we focus on the outcomes and
we focus on the benefits,
that's going to enable
us to have a lot more
wiggle room in what we actually deliver.
If my outcome is to have a car
that drives 120 miles
an hour for three hours,
I can build that a lot of different ways.
I have a lot of flexibility there.
But if I have a very specific requirement
that says my tolerance has to
be within point one inches,
that doesn't give me a
lot of room to maneuver.
And so without that room to maneuver,
we're not going to be nearly as agile.
So remember that when you're defining
what your thing is you wanted to do.
What is the outcome?
What is the benefit?
And by defining those well
early on in this process,
we're going to be able to
build to that a lot easier.
As we continue to tailor
these two processes,
we have to think about the products
that are usually output
from these processes.
That's things like our project brief,
our project initiation document,
and our business case.
Let's look at the project brief first.
Our project brief tends to be
very formal inside of Prince2.
It's a written report or it's
a PowerPoint presentation.
But in Agile, this can
be a lot less formal.
Instead, we're looking for
just some key components of it.
What methods are we going to use?
Are we going to use a lean start-up
and minimum viable product for instance.
If so, we would document that down.
And this project brief may only be
one slide or one piece of paper.
It doesn't have to be
really long and in depth.
Instead, we're going to make definitions
that are based on outcomes
instead of tight specifications.
We're going to make sure we're talking
about the fact that we're
going to use frequent delivery.
And frequent iteration.
So we get products out
to our customers sooner,
get their feedback and incorporate that
to make the next version.
This whole idea of the way
we're going to do this project
in an Agile method has to be documented
inside this project brief.
But again, this can be a
very informal document.
It could be one piece of paper,
it could be one whiteboard
in a conference room.
It doesn't really matter as long as
everyone agrees that that's
the way we're going to work.
Now as we look at the next thing,
we're going to look at our business case.
In our business case tends to be
a fairly flushed out very in depth
piece of paper that's written out
in our normal Prince2.
But in Agile, it doesn't
have to be that way.
Again, we're going to identify some basic
things inside our business case in Agile.
If we're going to use a
minimum viable product,
we need to identify that
in the business case.
What are the outcomes we expect to get
from our minimum viable product.
We want to talk about how
we're going to increase
flexing the amount of delivery
that's going to be done.
And so we want to get 80 percent
of our requirements filled.
But we're willing to accept as low as 60,
or we'd be happy to get
as much as 100 percent.
And that's something we can
cover in the business case.
Again, it's what's your best case,
what's your worse case,
and what's your most likely case.
And by giving that in
terms of amount delivered,
it really does work in
a much more Agile way
since you're going to be pulling things
from the back log to work
at during the sprints.
The third one we have is our
project product description.
This is something that's going
to focus on your outcomes.
It's going to be created
as part of a workshop
in a collaborative method,
and we're going to capture
those as user stories and epics.
If it's a very large project,
it's going to be an epic.
That epic is going to be made
up of many smaller stories
that we'll get to later
on during the process.
This will also be used to
create our product backlog.
And that product backlog
is all of the features
that we want to deliver and
we'll start pulling those
into our sprint planning to be able
to be created during our sprints.
Now our project initiation document
is our last document.
Normally, this is a very
large and complex document
that covers things like our
risk management strategy,
our communications management
strategy and many others.
Now inside of Agile,
we are going to make it
much less formal.
Instead of being this big document,
it may just exist as an
information radiator.
Because it's got all the
things you need in it.
It's got your information plan,
it's got your team rules,
it's got what issues are being tracked,
what new things are being tracked,
what progress is being tracked.
All of that.
And when so you think about
your project initiation document
in an Agile context,
you want to think about
what is the minimum that I have to do
so everyone knows what's needed?
And not do any extra paperwork.
This is going to help us plan for
the release of frequent releases.
As well as planning for the definition
of what is done and what is ready.
And it will also help us to
map Prince2 and our Agile
roles together.
Again, all of this can be shown
on an information radiator,
in a very informal way.
And we're going to make sure we tailor it
to be appropriate for the Agile
environment we're working in.
If we're working in a
very simple environment,
it may just be a board.
If it's a complex environment,
it may be a board that gives you
a summary, and we have more details
behind it written down on paper.
It just depends on how
you want to tailor this
to work in your project.
Next we're going to talk about how
we view starting up a project,
and initiating a project,
and what we have that
are Agile considerations.
And some of those are things like
what upfront work do we have to do?
And how much of it before we can
start getting into actually
doing something in a sprint?
And this is done through
what's called a sprint zero,
or discovery phase.
During sprint zero, which may be called
the initiation stage,
back in a traditional Prince2 model,
we're going to go through
and do our visioning,
and our chartering and
getting people together
to say "What is the grand
scheme for this product?
What is it we hope to have as an outcome?"
And as we start building this vision,
we can then start creating our backlog.
We're going to use workshops
and information communication,
whether formal or informal
to figure all this out.
And we put all this together,
we're going to start figuring out
what is the minimum thing
we need to start delivering,
and what is enough.
What means we are done?
And those are things we're
going to define here,
inside of the starting up a project,
and initiating a project phase.
Because we have to know what done is,
otherwise how will we ever
know if we ever got there?
The next thing we need to talk about
is the Agile behaviors,
and how do you asses those five behaviors
of transparency, collaboration,
rich communication,
self-organization, and exploration.
One of the common ways to do it
in starting up a project phase,
is to use a stop light chart.
And this is red, yellow, and green.
Red means there's some kind of significant
problem or exception.
Yellow means things are tracking poorly
and we should be concerned.
And green means
everything's good right now,
but we should monitor it because
it may be a problem later on.
And so this is just a very simple
way for you to look
across your organization
and see how they're
implementing Agile behaviors
inside of your project.
Another method of assessing
your organization,
beyond just the five behaviors,
is to look at it with the Agilometer.
Looking at those six key areas.
Again, we're going to look at this,
and we're going to put them on a
sliding scale from one to five.
How low or how high they
are in regards to Agile.
We're going to use each
of these in isolation,
and we're not going to average them up.
But this will give us an idea
of where our organization is,
and where our risks lie.
The last area that we want to measure
inside our project early on
is the level of uncertainty.
How certain or uncertain is this project?
And how complex or not
complex is this project?
To do that, we use a tool
called the Cynefin framework.
The Cynefin framework is a
decision making framework
that helps us determine the
exact level of complexity
in relation to our project
and the project environment.
This is going to tell us how much
we need to tailor Prince2 or Prince2 Agile
to work properly for
this particular project
in this particular environment.
When I look at the Cynefin framework,
it has five key areas.
These are obvious, complicated,
complex, chaotic, and disorder.
You can see it here on the screen,
as it's in this graphic.
And when you look at these different
areas, some of these are
going to be more used
in projects, and some
are going to be more used
in business as usual.
For example, if I look at obvious,
this is where we have best practices.
This is going to be our typical
business as usual operations.
It's very proceduralized it's very easy,
and it is not complex and
it's not uncertain at all.
Now as we start moving into
complicated or complex,
this is where the environment
or the project itself,
becomes more difficult or more uncertain.
This is where most of your
projects are going to be.
We still have good practices,
or emergent practices inside these areas,
that we can work a project with our
existing processes.
Now as we go down into chaotic,
this is some novel new
practices just being tried out.
This is something that may be a
first time ever for our company.
So it's very uncertain
and so we're going to have
additional governance
controls placed on that.
If we get into the disorder category,
this is where we have
no known relationships.
Things are just kind
of messy and thrown up,
and your project is likely to fail.
And so as you figure out
where does your project
and your environment fit
in these five categories,
you can figure how best
to put processes around it
to ensure you have a positive outcome.