- In this section,
we're going to do a quick review
of the seven processes from PRINCE2
and how they're applied inside
of an Agile environment.
As we go through the
next couple of lessons,
we'll dig into each of these processes
a little bit more in depth.
First let's look at the
seven processes that we use
and how they're laid out
across the different stages.
The first one is starting up a project.
This is where we take all
of the ideas that we have
and come up with the one idea
that we think is going to be our project.
This gets presented up to
program management and corporate,
and when they approve it,
it's going to initiate the project
and move us into the
project initiation stage.
Here we're going to be using the
initiating a project process.
Inside that process,
we're going to further
develop the business case,
and we're then going to also develop
our project initiation document,
which provides our risk management,
communication management,
and other structures
that we're going to need
throughout the life cycle of this project.
During this initiating a project process,
we're also going to develop the stage plan
for the subsequent that we're moving to,
as well as the overarching project plan.
This will then go back
up to directing a project
in that process where the program board
can make decisions if
they want to move forward
and if we have a continued
justifiable business case
to keep moving the
project towards the right
and towards the finish line.
At this point, if we get
to the end of a stage,
we're going to go into our
managing a stage boundary process,
and in this process,
we're going to look
over the next stage plan
to make sure it can be
approved and worked on,
as well as look over
the current stage plan
and ensure that everything
that was supposed to be done
has been completed before
we move to the next stage.
Assuming that stage
boundary has been approved,
we'll move into the subsequent stages,
and in each of these stages,
you're going to see
that the project manager
is focused on controlling a stage.
This is where they do the day to day work
that needs to be done for
the project management.
Underneath them, at the same time,
you're going to see
managing product delivery.
This is focused on the team managers
working with their teams
to create those products
that need to be delivered
to finish the stage.
As that information flows back
up to the project manager,
they will then enter
into the managing a stage
boundary process again,
going back to the directing a project,
and seeing if we can get approval
to move to the next stage.
We'll continue doing this in
all of our subsequent stages
until we get to the last stage.
In the last stage,
we'll have this closing a project process
where we ensure that the project has met
all of its deliverables
and that there's nothing more to do.
If that's true,
the directing a project process
will then feed into the
closing a project process
and give them approval to
close out the project fully,
releasing the resources and people
back to their own organizations
and getting ready for the next project.
So all of that that we just covered
is how it works in a
traditional PRINCE2 methodology.
But how does it work
when we start bringing in
Agile concepts, techniques, and behaviors?
Well, Agile is going to
need to be incorporated
into each of those seven processes,
but the amount of variation
that's going to happen
to that process is going to
depend on the process itself
and the agile techniques
we're going to implement.
For example, if we look
at the controlling a stage
or the managing product
delivery processes,
both of those will be heavily changed
based on our Agile framework.
For example, if I have a stage,
this is going to be a certain
amount of time or deliverables
that are going to be existing in there.
Underneath that one stage, though,
we may have several releases,
and each of those releases
may have several sprints.
So as you can see here on the screen,
we have three sprints,
and let's assume each of
those sprints is time fixed
to two weeks each.
Those three sprints make up one release.
That release now is a
month and a half long,
and we have four of those.
So if we put those four releases
at a month and a half each,
together we get a
six-month management stage.
And so you can start
seeing how these things
are going to tie together from sprints
into releases into management stages.
Now, that's great to
understand what it looks like
inside just one controlling stage,
but what does it look like
across the entire project?
Well, here's where you're going
to start seeing it be done
in two different ways.
There's the typical Agile way of doing it,
which is to start up and
initiate the project,
and in that we're going to get our vision
and our product backlog,
and then from that we're going to develop
what's going to be put into each stage
by pulling in things to a sprint backlog.
That sprint backlog
then goes into a sprint,
which gets worked on,
and eventually we get a shippable product
that gets moved out.
Now if we look at this where
we use a larger process
and we start doing it
with releases and sprints
and not just sprints,
we're going to have our
vision and product backlog
done in the starting up a project.
In our initiating a project,
we'll create our release backlog.
Then we'll pull in what
we're going to work on
for that particular
sprint, that next stage,
and that'll be done in a
controlling a stage process,
and that will then move into the sprint,
where the work is done,
and then that goes out into our product
that is going to be shipped and fulfilled.
And you can see how
this all works together
and ties together.
Notice much of the Agile way of working
is going to be handled
down at the delivery layer.
It's going to be working on the team
at the project manager and below.
It's not going to really affect
the project board as much
because they're still going to
have that overarching control
and governance for each
of the seven processes.
And we'll talk about that more
as we go through this section.