- When PRINCE2 was being developed,
they went back and looked at
a lot of different projects
and they started asking
two main questions.
First, why did this other project succeed?
And second, why did this project fail?
As they went back and looked
at all of these projects
they started finding
commonality about them.
And when they looked at
all those commonalities
they started developing
these best practices.
And they started seeing
that if you had these certain things,
projects were more
likely to be successful.
And if you were missing
some of those things
you were more likely to fail.
Those things are known
as the seven principles.
These are the seven key
principles to having a project
that is more likely to succeed.
In PRINCE2 everything else is built on top
of these seven principles.
What are these seven
principles, you might wonder.
Well, they are the Continued
business justification,
learn from experience,
defined roles and responsibilities,
manage by stages, manage by exception,
focus on products,
and tailor to suit the
project environment.
Now, we're going to
talk about each of these
in this lecture so you can understand
what their purpose is
and why they're important
to our project.
The first is continued
business justification.
Continued business justification
is all about insuring
that your project remains
desirable, viable and achievable.
We do this continually
checking that project,
and if there is ever a time that there is
not a continued business justification,
we should stop working on this project.
We shouldn't invest
more resources into it.
As we look at the continued
business justification,
we're trying to balance
between our advantages
that are going to be gained
and the impact of implementation.
When we look at advantages,
that's things like reduced
cost and time and risk.
It might be to give us more benefits.
It may be to improve our
quality or our scope.
On the other side, we have
the impact of implementation.
This is things like the cost
and duration of the option
that we're choosing to
use, the risk of the option
that we're choosing to use,
and all of those negative
things that might happen.
As we balance this, if
there's more of a positive
than a negative, then we have
a continued business
justification and we should
keep moving forward with our project.
This second principle is
learn from experience.
Learn from experience
recognizes the fact that
we're always going to have
mistakes and accidents
that happen during a project.
But the key concept here
is that we want to learn
from those so we don't repeat them.
How do we do that?
Well, during a project
we should be collecting lessons learned.
For example, if we ordered something
from an overseas supplier
and there was a delay at customs
and that caused our
project schedule to slip,
that's something we have to
be aware of next time we order
from an overseas supplier.
And so these are things
we would write down
and pass amongst the other project teams.
As we collect all these
reports, these lessons learned
from the previous projects,
that helps us figure
out what we need to put
mitigations in place for
those negative things
so that we can solve them this time
and avoid those problems.
Also, you can learn positive things.
For example, if I wanted
to build a new website,
I might want to go back to somebody
who has successfully
run that type of project
in the past and ask them questions
about what they did and what worked well.
Was outsourcing effective for them?
Or did they need to in-source?
Was doing the design first
or the coding first better?
Whatever those things are,
we can gather that information and learn
from other people's experience
and we can put that into place inside
our own project to do things better,
faster, cheaper and more efficiently.
The next one we have is defined
roles and responsibilities.
Everyone in the project
should know exactly what
role they're going to be
fulfilling inside the project
and their associated responsibilities.
If you are the team
manager, that has a certain
set of responsibilities.
If you're the executive
or the supplier, those have
certain responsibilities.
And you should understand what they are.
By doing this we're going to provide
terms of reference and role descriptions
for each and every team
member so they know
what their job is.
And this is going to make sure that each
team member has a correct
level of authority
to perform their role, too.
Because if I make you the executive
but you're not empowered to
make budgeting decisions,
then you're not going to
be effective in that role.
Every single person who
works on this project,
we need to make sure they have ample time
to dedicate to the project
because one of the problems that I've had
in previous places I've worked
is that they're going to
assign somebody all of the work
and that person can't do all of the work
because there's only
so many hours in a day.
And so if you're working
on three other projects
and I come up to you and say,
Hey can you help me with this one?
Your answer may be, no, I can't
because I don't have the time.
And that's okay.
As the project manager, I
want to make sure the people
I'm assigning have the time and capability
to put into my project so
that we can be successful.
Because if they don't
and they just say yes,
then I'm being set up for failure.
The next one we have
is managing by stages.
To manage by stages means
that we're going to break down
this really large concept
into smaller parts.
So for example, if I
wanted to build a car,
that's a fairly complex operation.
We've got a lot of things, from the idea,
the designing, the
engineering, the manufacturing,
putting all the pieces together, painting
the car and delivering
it, that have to be done.
We would then break that up into numerous
other stages that are smaller
pieces of that project.
And we can work through those and agree
to the details at each stage of what
we're expecting to get out of it.
By doing this, it will
help us estimate better
what the costs are for that stage
and what the time is for that stage.
Because if I asked you to
develop me a brand new car,
how long would it take you?
How much would it cost?
You probably don't know those answers
because it's such a
long and complex thing.
But if I said, how much
would it cost for you
to paint the car and how
long would that take?
You could probably figure
that out pretty quickly.
And so by breaking this
down into smaller chunks,
it allows us to get more
accurate detail with the things
that are closest to us
as opposed to the things
that are further out in our timeline.
The next one we have
is manage by exception
and this is one of my favorite principles.
Because it makes sure
that only significant
deviations from a budget or approved plan
are brought up to the
attention of management.
If I'm the project manager,
I don't need to know
every single detail that's going on
inside the project.
I need to know what
things are going outside
the boundaries that I've set up.
And so my team managers should be working
on their team packages
with the detail they need.
They're closer to the problem
and they understand it better.
By managing by exception,
we can get a lot more
work done because I'm
empowering the people
below me in this management organization
to make those decisions.
So, a good example of this is looking
at it from the opposite lens.
What does it look like when you
don't manage by exception?
Well, we sometimes refer
to this as micromanagement.
I don't know about you, but I've worked
for some micromanagers before.
I've had people where I
couldn't order pencils
for the office without going up to some
very high level manager
and getting their approval
for a $3 purchase.
That's just silly.
You want to make sure you give your people
good left and right limits
and let them operate between them.
And that's the whole concept
of management by exception.
Next, we have focus on products.
PRINCE2 is very focused on
delivering the end product.
And there's other products along the way
that will be delivered.
The idea of focus on
products is to successfully
deliver products leading
to the project's benefits being realized.
If I have to build the car, and I don't
get the whole car built,
then my end customer
can't have a way to
drive to and from work,
because that's the benefit
they want to realize.
It's the same thing in technology.
If I'm going to build a website,
and I don't build the entire website
from end to end
there's nothing there
for the customer to use.
And so we have this focus on delivering
the output at the end.
Now, when we start talking about Agile,
we're going to break
that down even smaller
to deliver smaller pieces that give us
usable ability, but when we look at
focus on products as a macro scale,
we are looking at getting some successful
delivered products into the hands of
those who are using it to
realize those benefits.
Our last principle is
probably one of the most
important ones inside of PRINCE2.
And it's tailoring to suit
the project environment.
PRINCE2 is a highly
adaptable framework that can
be specifically tailored to meet the needs
of each and every product.
And those tailorings are going to happen
based on different factors.
For example, not all projects operate
in the same cultural environment.
If I have a team who's making a website
here in the United States and a team
who's making one in India,
those are two different
cultural things and we're
going to have to change
some of the ways that we run this project
based on those cultural differences.
We also have geography.
We may look at something
that is built in America
versus something that is built in China
and you're going to have different costs
associated with that,
different manufacturing,
and different labor considerations.
Complexity is another one.
If you start looking at complexity,
these projects can be
very complex or very easy.
And depending on that,
we're going to put more
governance and controls in place.
If I'm building a car,
that is a very expensive
proposition and a very complex one,
so I'm going to have to make
lots of different stages
and lots of governance and control.
If instead I'm looking
at building something
like a piece of software that's
just going to do one function,
that might be a very simple aspect
and so it might not need all of the rigor
and governance controls that PRINCE2
would normally afford to it
and so we'll scale that back down.
The other thing we look
at is the scale itself.
How big or how small is the project?
If it's something that's
a million dollar project,
we're going to have a
lot more controls on it
than something that's a $10 project.
And finally, risk.
How risky is the thing you're doing?
A good example of this
is when I built my house.
I built it with a builder
who happens to build
a lot of this same style house
and so it was a very low risk evolution
because they've already built
20 or 30 of those before.
Now if I went and got a custom house made
and we had to choose every single piece
and we were using a builder who had never
built a house before, that's highly risky
and so we would have
more stages and we would
scope the project appropriately
with more governance and more control
to be able to address those risks
as we go through the project.