- The next thing we're
going to discuss is risk,
and risk is actually reduced
by working in an Agile method.
The reason for this is
because our Agile techniques
work in an iterative method,
and we're allowed to quickly adapt
when we find an issue
or risk and overcome it.
For example, when we start up a project,
we go and create our
outlying business case,
and as we start outlining
that business case,
we're going to avoid
putting too much detail in,
and that's going to prevent
us from being locked
into a certain set of requirements.
This allows us to be more
agile during development,
and be able to overcome
risks as they're identified.
Another thing that we do is we
do our daily standup meetings
where we get the delivery team
all around the information radiator,
and we all talk about
what we did yesterday
and what we're going to do today.
During that meeting, we're
also going to identify
any risks or issues that
need to be addressed,
and we can do that very quickly
at the detail level
inside our delivery team.
This happens a lot because
we have this self-managed
and self-directed team as well,
and that allows us to
overcome risks and obstacles
throughout the project.
Additionally, in Agile,
we're going to focus
on doing frequent demos
and frequent delivery
or releases of products.
By doing that, we're getting
things into the hands
of our customers sooner,
and that gives us additional
customer interaction
that will help us identify any
risks or challenges we have
in the project so that
we can move forward.
While working in an agile way can help us
to reduce our risk, there
are some unique risks
that will come up because
we're working in an agile way.
For example, when we work in an agile way,
we're continuously going to
be engaging with our customer.
That engagement gives
us continual feedback
which is great, but
that continual feedback
may also derail our project,
because we're constantly adjusting
and constantly doing new
requirements and new changes
to the thing we're working on.
This is a risk that we're
going to have to manage.
Another area that we're going
to tailor inside the risk theme
is that we're going to
reduce the formality
and bureaucracy that usually is seen
inside the risk management procedures.
In PRINCE2, we used something formal,
like an electronic risk register
to capture every single risk
and what mitigations
we're putting against it
and what residual risk is left over,
but in PRINCE2 Agile, we
may just have a few columns
on our team board or
our information radiator
that's going to capture those risks
and what we're doing about them.
Overall, Agile is going to
place a lot less emphasis
on risk than PRINCE2 does,
and the reason for this
is because risk can be
overcome much quicker
and much easier based
on that self-managing,
self-organizing delivery team.
By using the Agile
concepts and techniques,
we're already mitigating a lot of the risk
that we normally see in a
traditional waterfall development
because we can react to changes faster,
but Agile does have its own risks
associated with it on its own,
and we assess that by
looking at the Agilometer,
and assessing those six key
areas of our organization
to see, are we going to be able to operate
as an agile organization,
or are we going to be more
of a formal organization?
Either way, you're going to
be able to identify that early
and put mitigations in place
so that you can have a successful project.